<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns:yt="http://www.youtube.com/xml/schemas/2015" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 <link rel="self" href="http://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=PLrggWHcy3azrunmSfTCSlS5JRuB4zTgCY"/>
 <id>yt:playlist:PLrggWHcy3azrunmSfTCSlS5JRuB4zTgCY</id>
 <yt:playlistId>PLrggWHcy3azrunmSfTCSlS5JRuB4zTgCY</yt:playlistId>
 <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
 <title>Worship services - Trinity and Cores End URCs</title>
 <author>
  <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
  <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
 </author>
 <published>2020-04-04T11:11:34+00:00</published>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:wbW7EYqc7cU</id>
  <yt:videoId>wbW7EYqc7cU</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship  - Sunday 15th January 2023</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wbW7EYqc7cU"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2023-01-15T11:31:48+00:00</published>
  <updated>2023-01-15T12:58:47+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship  - Sunday 15th January 2023</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/wbW7EYqc7cU?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/wbW7EYqc7cU/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00:00 - Opening music, photos, and notices

Welcome and lighting of peace candle (an elder)

Call to Worship – Poem by Dominic Windram

HYMN 187: Worship the Lord

Opening Prayer – Faithfulness of God
Almighty and loving God, we thank you for the assurance we have
that you are always with us, that in you we will find help and
strength in times of trouble, that whatever we face you will
always be there to reach out and save us.
Almighty and loving God. Take our faith, weak though it is. Kindle
the sparks of life within us and fan a new flame of love within our
hearts, so, may we set out into another week with renewed
purpose, resolved to live and work for you, in the assurance that
you are with us, now and always,
Great is your faithfulness, from one generation to another. Thanks
be to God. Amen.

Lord’s Prayer

HYMN 188: Born in the night

Bible reading: Isaiah 60 Verses 1-6 read by Abigail Lokko

HYMN 183: Brightest and best

Bible Reading: Matthew 2: 1-12 read by Harri Bello

Epiphany Prayer of Confession
Loving God, you guided the wise men to Bethlehem, offering a
light for their path, and in faith they responded. Forgive us that all
too often we fall short of their example.
Gracious Lord, have mercy.
You offer us guidance in innumerable ways – through the light of
your word, the illumination of your Holy Spirit, the fellowship of
your church, and the encounter of prayer, yet so often we either
fail to hear or refuse to see.
Gracious Lord, have mercy.
We are too preoccupied with our own small affairs, eyes only for
the immediate moment, our vision impeded by trivial concerns, so
we fail to recognise where you are leading us,
Gracious Lord, have mercy.
We believe we know just where we are going, just what we want
from life, and exactly how we can get it, and we resist any
suggestion that we need to think again.
Gracious Lord, have mercy.
Loving God, forgive us our foolishness, our stubbornness, our
weakness.
Gracious Lord, have mercy.
Forgive our pride, our lack of faith, our closed minds.
Gracious Lord, have mercy.
Forgive us for ignoring your guidance, for resting your will, and as
a result so often walking in darkness.
Gracious Lord, have mercy.
Meet with us again we ask, and may the light of your love shine in
our hearts, so that we cannot but see it or fail to respond in
grateful praise and joyful service.
Gracious Lord, have mercy, in the name of Christ .Amen

HYMN 185: Wise men seeking Jesus

Talk: ‘What gifts shall we bring?’ - Pastor Vince Gerhardy

Time of quiet reflection and silent prayers for the world ending
with this prayer:
Loving God, accept our gifts for your work today.
Inspire our lives to reflect more truly the love of Jesus.
Hear our silent prayers for people on our hearts and places in
desperate need. Bring your healing and your peace, in Jesus name.
Amen.

HYMN 184: As with gladness men of old

Blessing

Organ voluntary

#Church #Worship #Sing #Organ #Faithful #Jesus #URC #UnitedReformedChurch  #Blessings #GoodNews #NIV #NIVUK #Bible #Lessons #King #GoodNews #Choir   #AllAreWelcome #JoinIn #Epiphany #Christian #WarmSpace #WednesdayCafe</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="6"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:vdLg62x5pKc</id>
  <yt:videoId>vdLg62x5pKc</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship  - Sunday 8th January 2023</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vdLg62x5pKc"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2023-01-08T12:12:21+00:00</published>
  <updated>2023-01-08T13:40:29+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship  - Sunday 8th January 2023</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/vdLg62x5pKc?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/vdLg62x5pKc/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00:00 - Opening music, photos, and notices

CALL TO WORSHIP – Isaiah 42: 6-7

HYMN R&amp;amp;S 134 On Jordan’s bank the Baptist’s cry.
(Tune 209)

PRAYERS - Approach, Confession, Thanksgiving &amp;amp; Praise

LORD'S PRAYER

WE LISTEN FOR GOD’S WORD

READING 1 – Isaiah 42:1-9 NIVUK read by Ian Bogart
‘Here is my servant, whom I uphold,
    my chosen one in whom I delight;
I will put my Spirit on him,
    and he will bring justice to the nations.
2  He will not shout or cry out,
    or raise his voice in the streets.
3  A bruised reed he will not break,
    and a smouldering wick he will not snuff out.

In faithfulness he will bring forth justice;
4      he will not falter or be discouraged
till he establishes justice on earth.
    In his teaching the islands will put their hope.’
5  This is what God the LORD says –
the Creator of the heavens, who stretches them out,
    who spreads out the earth with all that springs from it,
    who gives breath to its people,
    and life to those who walk on it:
6  ‘I, the LORD, have called you in righteousness;
    I will take hold of your hand.
I will keep you and will make you
    to be a covenant for the people
    and a light for the Gentiles,
7  to open eyes that are blind,
    to free captives from prison
    and to release from the dungeon those who sit in darkness.
8  ‘I am the LORD; that is my name!
    I will not yield my glory to another
    or my praise to idols.
9  See, the former things have taken place,
    and new things I declare;
before they spring into being
    I announce them to you.’

HYMN R&amp;amp;S 195 I am the Lord of the dance

ALL AGE TALK – Who is the servant?

READING 2 – Matthew 3:13-17 NIVUK read by Lesley Bogart
13  Then Jesus came from Galilee to the Jordan to be baptised by
John.  14  But John tried to deter him, saying, ‘I need to be baptised by you,
and do you come to me?’
15  Jesus replied, ‘Let it be so now; it is proper for us to do this to fulfil all
righteousness.’ Then John consented.
16  As soon as Jesus was baptised, he went up out of the water. At that
moment heaven was opened, and he saw the Spirit of God descending
like a dove and alighting on him.  17  And a voice from heaven said, ‘This is
my Son, whom I love; with him I am well pleased.’

HYMN TP 79 River wash over me.

SERMON – Baptism

WE MAKE OUR RESPONSE

HYMN TP 13 Be still, for the presence of the Lord.

DEDICATION of our OFFERINGS
PRAYERS of intercession

WE GO OUT TO SERVE

HYMN R&amp;amp;S 187 Worship the Lord in the beauty of holiness.

Blessing

Organ voluntary

#Church #Worship #Sing #Organ #Faithful #Jesus #URC #UnitedReformedChurch  #Blessings #GoodNews #NIV #NIVUK #Bible #Lessons #King #GoodNews #Choir   #AllAreWelcome #JoinIn #Epiphany #Christian #WarmSpace #WednesdayCafe</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="6"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:acIo9TsC5qA</id>
  <yt:videoId>acIo9TsC5qA</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>New Year Worship (Audio Only) - Sunday 1st January 2023</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=acIo9TsC5qA"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2023-01-01T11:48:39+00:00</published>
  <updated>2023-01-01T18:13:28+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>New Year Worship (Audio Only) - Sunday 1st January 2023</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/acIo9TsC5qA?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/acIo9TsC5qA/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00:00 - Opening music, photos, and notices

Call to worship
Jesus said, A new commandment I give to you that you love one
another as I have loved you.
We bring our worship, seeking that love to share.
Paul wrote, if anyone is in Christ, the new creation has come: the
old has gone, the new is here!
We bring our worship at the beginning of this new year.
Not looking back, but always moving forwards:
We bring our worship to you, the God of new life.

HYMN 159 Hark the herald angels sing

Prayer of adoration and confession

Introduction: What’s the time?

Lighting the Christmas Candle

Reading: Ecclesiastes 3.1-13 NIVUK read by Kitty Bird
3 There is a time for everything,
    and a season for every activity under the heavens:
2          a time to be born and a time to die,
    a time to plant and a time to uproot,
3      a time to kill and a time to heal,
    a time to tear down and a time to build,
4      a time to weep and a time to laugh,
    a time to mourn and a time to dance,
5      a time to scatter stones and a time to gather them,

    a time to embrace and a time to refrain from embracing,
6      a time to search and a time to give up,
    a time to keep and a time to throw away,
7      a time to tear and a time to mend,
    a time to be silent and a time to speak,
8      a time to love and a time to hate,
    a time for war and a time for peace.
9  What do workers gain from their toil?  10  I have seen the burden
God has laid on the human race.  11  He has made everything
beautiful in its time. He has also set eternity in the human heart;
yet [a]  no one can fathom what God has done from beginning to
end.  12  I know that there is nothing better for people than to be
happy and to do good while they live.  13  That each of them may eat
and drink, and find satisfaction in all their toil – this is the gift of
God.

HYMN 188 Born in the night, Mary’s child

Reading: Revelation 21.1-6a NIVUK read by Rosemary Taylor
21 Then I saw ‘a new heaven and a new earth,’ for the first heaven
and the first earth had passed away, and there was no longer any
sea.  2  I saw the Holy City, the new Jerusalem, coming down out of
heaven from God, prepared as a bride beautifully dressed for her
husband.  3  And I heard a loud voice from the throne saying, ‘Look!
God’s dwelling-place is now among the people, and he will dwell
with them. They will be his people, and God himself will be with
them and be their God.  4  “He will wipe every tear from their eyes.
There will be no more death” or mourning or crying or pain, for
the old order of things has passed away.’
5  He who was seated on the throne said, ‘I am making everything
new!’
6  He said to me: ‘It is done. I am the Alpha and the Omega, the
Beginning and the End.

Short Address: ‘God makes new’

HYMN 685 vs 1 – 3 sung seated to begin our prayers

Prayer for the world

Prayer of Dedication at the beginning of this new year
Eternal God, Beginning and End of all things,
we come to you now to offer the praise of our lips
and the service of our lives.
We recommit ourselves
to walk the way of Jesus,
to seek your will for our lives and for our world,
to pray and work for your kingdom of justice and joy.
Unite us as one body in Christ, renew us by your Spirit,
that we may be channels of your love and peace,
through Jesus Christ our Saviour and Lord. Amen.

Communion: we invite you to share in the bread and wine at
church (or at home) united in the name of Christ.

HYMN 63 Great God, we sing that mighty hand

A Prayer of thanksgiving with the response
We thank you Lord of life And praise your holy name

Lord’s Prayer

Closing Prayer

HYMN 603 Lord for the years

Blessing

Organ voluntary

#Church #CarolConcert #Worship #Advent #Sing #Organ #HarkTheHerald #SilentNight #Faithful #Jesus #URC #UnitedReformedChurch #Christmas #Blessings #BleakMidwinter #CalypsoCarol #InfantHoly #GoodNews #NIV #NIVUK #Bible #Lessons #Carols #King #NewKing #GoodNews #Tidings #CarolSinging #Choir   #AllAreWelcome #JoinIn 
#JoyToTheWorld</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="21"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:oRtSD2cPnDo</id>
  <yt:videoId>oRtSD2cPnDo</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Christmas Morning Worship - Sunday 25th December 2022</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oRtSD2cPnDo"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-12-25T10:59:48+00:00</published>
  <updated>2023-01-12T09:02:07+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Christmas Morning Worship - Sunday 25th December 2022</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/oRtSD2cPnDo?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/oRtSD2cPnDo/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00:00 - Opening music, photos, and notices

17:15 - Welcome to our Christmas service

18:30 - 21:22 - Carol to prepare for worship: 155 While shepherds watched their flocks

21:25 - Welcome and introduction (including lighting of peace candle)

22:45 - Call to worship (words from Isaiah 9)
A child is born to us! A son is given to us! And he will be our ruler;
and will be called, Wonderful Counsellor,
The Almighty, the Everlasting, Prince of peace.
All: We come to worship Jesus Christ,
born in Bethlehem, Light of the world,
King of love and Lord of life.

23:30 - 27:19 - Hymn 160 - O come all ye faithful (omit verses 3 and 4)

27:20 - 29:54 - Part 1 Celebrating the Light

Lighting the Advent Candles
We light each candle to remember those who played their part
preparing the way for Jesus, Emmanuel, God with us; and we light
the central candle to celebrate his birth and life and touch on our
lives:
All: Lord Jesus, light of the world,
be with us in all our celebrations this day.
Bring your love, hope and peace to our broken world,
that all creation may learn the song of the angels:
Glory to God in the highest and peace on earth. Amen.

30:24 - 31:05 - Song (tune Frere Jacques - unaccompanied)
Christ our light, Christ our light,
Light our lives, light our lives.
We’ll be lights to others; we’ll be lights to others
Light our lives, light our lives.

31:13 - Part 2: ‘opening the gift’

36:04 - 37:53 - Hymn 167 Once in Royal David’s city vs 1 and 2

37:56 - Part 3: Telling the story

42:06 - 43:58 - Hymn 167 Once in Royal David’s city vs 3 and 4

44:36 - 45:45 - Reading: John 1.1 – 5, 9 – 14 NIVUK read by Julia Sparks

45:54 - 48:39 - Part 4: Knowing the meaning

48:54 - 49:25 - Reading: ‘God came in person!’ read by Linda Curley

50:20 - 54:36 - Hymn 162 - In the bleak mid winter

54:43 - 58:27 - Part 5 - Praying for the world and ourselves
Today we thank you, God of new life, for the child born in Bethlehem long
ago, whose life continues to inspire and challenge and comfort us today.
Help us to know his presence and share his peace…
Lord of all life, hear our prayer.
We pray for children born today and for their families, for midwives in their
care; and we lift to you families where there is sadness or hurt...
Lord of all life, hear our prayer.
Today we pray for peace, peace in places where there is violence and war,
anger and fear...
Lord of all life, hear our prayer.
We pray for travellers... those who have travelled home for Christmas, those
travelling today, those seeking a new place to call home…
Lord of all life, hear our prayer.
We pray for all who are sick, and those who care for them – at home or in
hospital. We remember those who have died, those we miss at the table
and thank you, God of eternal life, for each of them in their uniqueness…
Lord of all life, hear our prayer.
And we pray for ourselves, for our needs, our hopes and fears, our joys and
dreams for the future. Lead us Lord, in your way of generous love…
Lord of all life, hear our prayer.
God of new life, hear our prayers, spoken and silent, and unite us with all
celebrating the birth of Jesus, as we pray the prayer he gave us:
Lord’s Prayer

59:17 - 01:01:51 - Hymn 164 - Go tell it on the mountain

01:01:54 - 01:02:20 - Blessing
Let us go in the peace and joy of Jesus Christ
To share his love with all this Christmas Day
And the grace of our Lord Jesus Christ, the love of God and the fellowship
of the Holy Spirit be with us and all creation, now and always. Amen.

01:02:31 - 01:05:46 - Organ voluntary

#Church #CarolConcert #Worship #Advent #Sing #Organ #HarkTheHerald #SilentNight #Faithful #Jesus #URC #UnitedReformedChurch #Christmas #Blessings #BleakMidwinter #CalypsoCarol #InfantHoly #GoodNews #NIV #NIVUK #Bible #Lessons #Carols #King #NewKing #GoodNews #Tidings #CarolSinging #Choir #BassGuitar #Drums #AllAreWelcome #JoinIn 
#JoyToTheWorld</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="18"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:XtTl9IJttvU</id>
  <yt:videoId>XtTl9IJttvU</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Carol Service - Sunday 18th December 2022</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XtTl9IJttvU"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-12-18T17:15:20+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-12-20T11:54:23+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Carol Service - Sunday 18th December 2022</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/XtTl9IJttvU?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/XtTl9IJttvU/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00:00 - Opening music, photos, and notices

10:18 - Welcome

13:18 - 18:14 - Carol: O come all ye faithful [on screen or R&amp;S 160 vs 1 – 5]

18:19 - Lighting of the Advent Candles and Opening Prayer

22:21 - 24:07 - Song: Longing for light (MP 1201 vs 1 and 2)

24:17 - 1 st Bible Reading: Isaiah 9 verses 2, 6 and 7 Arthur Winning

25:10 - 29:05 - Carol: It came upon a midnight clear [on screen or R&amp;S 144]

29:09 - 2 nd Bible Reading: Luke 1: 26 – 38 Lesley Bogart

31:01 - 34:52 - Carol: O little town of Bethlehem [on screen or R&amp;S 144]

35:04 - 3 rd Bible Reading: Luke 2: 1–7 (Good News) Samuel Evans

36:31 - 38:43 - Carol: See him lying on a bed of straw [on screen or R&amp;S 151]

39:04 - 4 th Bible Reading: Luke 2: 8 – 20 Richard Harding

40:30 - 43:05 - Carol: Silent night [on screen or R&amp;S 147]

43:17 - Reading: For him all stars have shone Rebekah / Matthew Sparks

42:41 - 46:20 - Carol: Come and join the celebration [on screen or R&amp;S 166]

46:30 5 th Bible Reading: Matthew 2: 1 – 12 Alan Yates (black screen for first part)

48:40 - 50:31 - Carol: Infant holy [on screen or R&amp;S 149]

50:43 - Reading: Gifts of the wise Rebekah / Matthew Sparks

51:37 - Introducing our Christmas charities: donations will be shared between
One Can, Wycombe Homeless Connection, Wycombe Refugee
Partnership – working in our community and Commitment for Life –
supporting projects in Israel and occupied Palestinian territories.

58:56 - Worship Song ‘Christmas blessing’ by Sam Hargreaves https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-RrCdTdr91M

01:01:40 - Prayers of intercession

01:04:47 - Lord’s Prayer

01:06:00 - 01:09:26 - Carol: Hark! the herald angels sing [on screen or R&amp;S 159]

01:09:27 - 01:09:51 - Blessing

01:10:11 - 01:17:10 - Organ voluntary

#Church #CarolConcert #Worship #Advent #Sing #Organ #HarkTheHerald #SilentNight #Faithful #Jesus #URC #UnitedReformedChurch #Christmas #Blessings #BleakMidwinter #CalypsoCarol #InfantHoly #GoodNews #NIV #NIVUK #Bible #Lessons #Carols #King #NewKing #GoodNews #Tidings #CarolSinging #Choir #BassGuitar #Drums #AllAreWelcome #JoinIn 
@onecantrust4907 @wycombehomelessconnection7371</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="27"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:eFtyfvc8ap4</id>
  <yt:videoId>eFtyfvc8ap4</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship - Sunday 18th December 2022</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eFtyfvc8ap4"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-12-18T11:54:59+00:00</published>
  <updated>2023-01-03T22:54:59+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship - Sunday 18th December 2022</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/eFtyfvc8ap4?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/eFtyfvc8ap4/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00:00 - Opening music, photos, and notices

10:14 - Welcome and lighting of peace candle 
12:20 - Call to worship
God of creation, God of history:
God is here with us.
God of mystery, God of blessing:
God is here with us.
God in Jesus, God named Emmanuel:
God is here with us.

13:08 - 15:44 - Hymn - Joy to the world, the Lord is come (R&amp;S 135)

15:52 - Opening Prayers and Lord’s Prayer

18:29 - 27:27 - Introduction: Nativity now – what part would you play?
The recent Brownie sleepover on the nice warm floor
Nativity - what part would you want?
Shepherd, Mary, Joseph, and animal, an angel?  An alien, a lobster?
A snowman?
What part would you play?
A rat?  The least significant but still with a part?
Do we ever feel unloved?  We are still welcomed by Jesus
What part do we play in the Christmas story?

27:39 - 30:30 - Carol - The angel Gabriel (R&amp;amp;S 139)

30:43 - Lighting the Advent candles
As we light the last candle before Christmas Day,
we give thanks for the role Mary and Joseph played in God’s
unfolding plan and pray:
God of all our lives, you call each of us to play a part in your story
and purposes for the world. As we give thanks for the courage
and the humility of Mary and Joseph, may shine your light into
the lives of others.
Draw us all to the Christmas stable, where hope is born and all
are loved, in Jesus’ name. Amen.

33:48 - 34:53 - Reading: Isaiah 7.10 – 16 GNB 

36:13 - 39:21 - Song -  Emmanuel, Emmanuel (MP 121) sung three times
Emmanuel, Emmanuel, His name is called Emmanuel
God with us, revealed in us – His name is called Emmanuel

40:01 - Find Mary…find Joseph (carols R&amp;amp;S 144 – 181)

44:55 - 46:24 - Matthew 1. 18 – 25 NIVUK

47:03 - 51:24 - Carol Joseph, son of David (Tune R&amp;amp;S 243 Noel nouvelet)
1. Joseph, son of David, son of Abraham;
regally descended, son of tent and psalm;
waited the day when, filled with joy and pride,
he would marry Mary, she would be his bride.

2. Joseph, though a poor man, with no wealth or fame,
yet possessed a treasure in his fam’ly name.
He must pass on this honour to his son,
in the line of David – then his job was done!

3. Yet, before the wedding, Mary was with child
and there was no father; ev’ryone went wild!
What could he do, to keep his name intact?
Mary must be banished! Surely he must act!

4. Calmly, at God’s prompting, Joseph held his ground,
risking, trusting, waiting; Mary still around.
Somehow he knew, though how he could not tell,
God would act through Jesus, all would then be well.

5. Showing such devotion, Joseph stood in line
with ancestral women working God’s design:
Rahab, and Tamar, Bathsheba and Ruth –
each, when others faltered, stood for hope and truth.

6. Now the gift of Joseph – ancestry and name –
graciously surrendered, nevermore the same;
offered to Jesus, ’til God’s work is done,
welcomes all the nations, seeks to make us one.
© John Campbell (based on Matthew 1)

52:14 - Short prayer

52:32 - 01:03:42 - Short Talk
Gathering this afternoon for the carol service
Keeping quiet about the score for the #WorldCupFinal
Focus on Emmanuel, Christ the light of the world
Other people playing their part around Jesus
Looking at Mary and Joseph
Mary does play a part in our carols but just Silent Night with Mary and Joseph looking on protectively
Joseph was older, not unusual at that time
Their son was unusual
Revealing God's immense, eternal love
Mary carried Jesus, Joseph protects them and takes them to Bethlehem to be registered
Telling the story of the birth
One word to take home - Emmanuel - God with us


01:03:54 - 01:06:09 - Song - Born in the night, Mary’s child (R&amp;S 188) sung seated

01:06:15 - Prayers for each other and the world

01:12:22 - 01:17:16 - Carol - See! In yonder manger low (R&amp;S 157)

01:17: 16 - 01:17:46 - Blessing

01:18:15 - 01:20:05 - Music, notices and photos

#Church #Worship #Advent  #AllAreWelcome #URC #UnitedReformedChurch #Hope #Isaiah #FourCandles #ForkHandles #Matthew #AllAreWelcome #URC #unitedreformedchurch</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="35"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:MBQLNs_bIYk</id>
  <yt:videoId>MBQLNs_bIYk</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship - Sunday 11th December 2022</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MBQLNs_bIYk"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-12-11T11:47:22+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-12-14T08:57:29+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship - Sunday 11th December 2022</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/MBQLNs_bIYk?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/MBQLNs_bIYk/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00:00 - Opening music, photos, and notices

07:35 - Welcome and lighting of peace candle (Linda as duty elder)

08:32 - Introduction – Linda

09:50 - 13:40 - Carol: In the Bleak Mid-Winter (R&amp;S 162)

13:46 - Story Telling – Julia
What are you looking forward to most about Christmas
Dinner
Cousins
Grandchildren
Now think back to when you were a child?
Presents
Stocking
Which do you like best - giving or receiving
Why do we give presents?
Enjoyment, showing our love for one another, reminding us of the first Christmas present wrapped in strips of cloth
Jesus was the first and best
Remembering our friends, family and God at Christmas
We need to receive, unwrap, thank, enjoy, and share our presents and God's present of Jesus

17:47 - 19:00 - Reading: Luke 2. 4-12 (NIVUK) – Samuel
4  So Joseph also went up from the town of Nazareth in Galilee to
Judea, to Bethlehem the town of David, because he belonged to
the house and line of David.  5  He went there to register with Mary,
who was pledged to be married to him and was expecting a
child.  6  While they were there, the time came for the baby to be
born,  7  and she gave birth to her firstborn, a son. She wrapped him
in cloths and placed him in a manger, because there was no guest
room available for them.
8  And there were shepherds living out in the fields near by, keeping
watch over their flocks at night.  9  An angel of the Lord appeared to
them, and the glory of the Lord shone around them, and they
were terrified.  10  But the angel said to them, ‘Do not be afraid. I
bring you good news that will cause great joy for all the
people.  11  Today in the town of David a Saviour has been born to
you; he is the Messiah, the Lord.  12  This will be a sign to you: you
will find a baby wrapped in cloths and lying in a manger.’

19:14 - 23:17 - Carol - We Three Kings of Orient Are

23:33 - 24:37 - Reading: Matthew 2. 1-2, 9-12 (NIVUK)
After Jesus was born in Bethlehem in Judea, during the time of
King Herod, Magi from the east came to Jerusalem  2  and asked,
‘Where is the one who has been born king of the Jews? We saw
his star when it rose and have come to worship him.’
9  After they had heard the king, they went on their way, and the
star they had seen when it rose went ahead of them until it
stopped over the place where the child was.  10  When they saw the
star, they were overjoyed.  11  On coming to the house, they saw the
child with his mother Mary, and they bowed down and
worshipped him. Then they opened their treasures and presented
him with gifts of gold, frankincense and myrrh.  12  And having been
warned in a dream not to go back to Herod, they returned to their
country by another route.

24:46 - Lighting of the Advent Candle – Samuel

26:18 - 29:30 - Carol - Good King Wenceslas (verses 1-3, 5)

29:37 - Introduction to Activities
- Print wrapping paper) – Sarah
- Christmas Stocking – Sarah
- Story Teller – Linda
- Edible Baby – Julia
- Themed crossword for those sitting – Ellen
- At home – Ellen

58:58 - 01:01:34 - Carol -  Come and Join the Celebration (R&amp;amp;S 166)

01:01:40 - Prayers and Lord’s Prayer – Sarah

01:06:32 - 01:19:56 - Carol - Hark the Herald Angels Sing (R&amp;amp;S 159)

01:10:03 - 01:10:40 - Messy Grace – Linda

01:10:56 - Music, notices and photos

#Church #Worship #Advent  #AllAreWelcome #URC #UnitedReformedChurch #Hope #Isaiah #Paul #Romans</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="24"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:C8h3HLFKpTk</id>
  <yt:videoId>C8h3HLFKpTk</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship - Sunday 4th December 2022</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=C8h3HLFKpTk"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-12-04T12:01:41+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-12-06T08:41:22+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship - Sunday 4th December 2022</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/C8h3HLFKpTk?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/C8h3HLFKpTk/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00:00 - Opening music, photos, and notices

08:30 - Welcome and lighting of peace candle (an elder)
#Ukraine 

10:20 - Call to worship (based on Psalm 72. 18,19)
Praise be to the Lord God, 
the God of Israel, the God of all people
the God who alone does marvellous deeds.
Praise be to God’s glorious name for ever;
may the whole earth be filled with God’s glory.
Seen in the Face of Jesus, Emmanuel, 
God with us for ever and ever.  Amen.

11:18 - 15:51 - Hymn - O come o come Emmanuel (R&amp;S 126 vs. 1 – 5)
Four candles and the great Os

16:11 - Prayer of adoration and confession

18:09 - Introduction for all ages: ‘Speaking up, speaking out’
Have any of  you joined a protest march?
Would you ever join one?
Cancel the debt?
Having a phobia of crowds, feeling uncomfortable in them but admiring those who do protest
What would you protest about?
CND, Mahsa Amini, China, Extinction Rebellion, Insulate Britain
Local protests
What would go on your banner?
Prayer as a kind of protest
&quot;It is better to light a candle than curse the darkness&quot;

27:30 - Lighting of 2nd Advent candle 
Reader: As we light the second Advent candle, 
  we remember the prophets of the past and the 
present, witnessing to the justice and peace God 
wants for this world.  And we pray that we too may 
be ready to speak out against evil and wrong and 
show God’s love today
All:  Lord Jesus, light of the world,
born to bring peace and love to a hurting world.
Help us to follow your way and to know your 
peace this Christmastide.  Amen. 

32:35 - 35:398 - Hymn -  Make way, make way (R&amp;S 141)

36:10 - Introducing the first reading: ‘a world transformed’

37:01 - 38:40 - Reading: Isaiah 11.1-10 (NIVUK) read by Eljse Hatton

39:10 - 42:10 - Hymn - Hills of the north rejoice vs 5 (CP 337)

42:18 - 43:52 - Reading: Romans 15.4-13 (NIVUK) read by Tony Hatton 

44:20 - Short Address
What does hope mean in your lives?
This is the season of hope and light
Sharing 3 pictures of hope
The great reading from Romans of hope overflowing
Take that hope home with you
Firstly from hundreds of years ago, a tiny middle eastern nation being surrounded and the invasion becoming a certainty
Isaiah delivered a message of hope to Judah
Secondly from a man who had endures much suffering in his life yet held on to the love of God and the hope of Christ
Paul writing to the Christians in Rome against the evil empire
Finally from Cambridge when studying economics
A small christian group called the ecumenical fellowship group
Meeting, discussing and planning social action, going to the local psychiatric hospital to sit with and talk to some of the patients



53:20 - 58:20 - Prayers for the church and the world 


58:40 - 01:01:10 - Hymn - Hark the glad sound (R&amp;S 137)  

01:01:18 - Thanksgiving Prayer and Lord’s Prayer
01:04:17 - Distribution of bread and wine and Closing Prayer 

01:11:02 - 01:13:54 - Hymn - Joy to the world (R&amp;S 135ii)

01:13:55 - 01:14:26 -  Blessing

01:14:51 - 01:18:44 - Music, notices and photos

#Church #Worship #Advent  #AllAreWelcome #URC #UnitedReformedChurch #Hope #Isaiah #Paul #Romans</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="1" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="37"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:Glr8tbgbwC0</id>
  <yt:videoId>Glr8tbgbwC0</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship - Sunday 27th November 2022</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Glr8tbgbwC0"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-11-27T11:56:13+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-11-28T08:59:22+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship - Sunday 27th November 2022</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/Glr8tbgbwC0?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/Glr8tbgbwC0/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00:00 - Opening music, photos, and notices

11:15 - Welcome and lighting of peace candle (an elder)

13:46 - Call to worship - Psalm 122

15:04 - 21:54 - Hymn:  O Come o come Emanuel R&amp;S126

21:58 - Prayer of adoration and confession

25:05 - Lord’s Prayer

26:05 - Reading: Matthew 24 vv 36-44 Read by Kate Yates

27:10 - 30:37 -  All age talk and intro
Boys' Brigade camp &amp; worrying about people being sick on the coach
Phobias
Working in care for so many years and being unable to deal with sick
&quot;Are we there yet?&quot;
Donkey, Shrek and Fiona in Shrek 2
The answer never comes until all of a sudden it does
We are told in our readings to prepare as we don't know the time and the hour
Penitential seasons before the two great festivals of Easter and Christmas
Thinking more about getting ready for Christ
Extending our prayer life
The start of the lectionary aligns with Advent
We have to prepare and be ready

30:51 - 34:02 - Hymn: Light of the World  MP1086

34:10 - Lighting of the Advent Candle

37:05 - 38:18 - Reading: Isaiah 2  vv 1-5  read by Kate Yates

38:36 - 40:37 - Hymn: Come thou long expected Jesus R&amp;S 138

40:42 - 52:33 - Address
Matthew 23 vv34 - Truly I tell you this generation will not pass away until all these things have happened
Reading v34, Matthew could not have thought of this generation only lasting 30-40 years after the crucifixion, but maybe before all of Jesus' had passed away
Compare to v36 - &quot;But about that day or hour no one knows, not even the angels in heaven, nor the Son, but only the Father&quot;
We know so little, constantly confounded by events
Jesus says &quot;about that day and hour no-one knows&quot;
Remembering days or hours about which I did not know - friends telling they have terminal cancer, meeting a future spouse, going to court to get justice, being asked to pray for a COVID sufferer
The day or hour about which we do not know comes to us all in thousands of different ways
We have no way of knowing whether it will be welcome or unwelcome
Jesus says &quot;Keep awake and be ready&quot; but for what?
We don't know but that is how life unfolds, it deepens the meaning of life. 
Everything matters and we should not want to miss a moment

52:50 - 55:19 - Hymn: Hark the glad sound the Saviour comes R&amp;S 137

55:23 - Offering Prayer
Prayers for the church and the world 

59:42 - 01:04:46 - Hymn: Lo He comes with clouds descending R&amp;S 656

01:04:47 - 01:05:08 - Blessing

01:05:34 - 01:09:00 - Organ voluntary, notices and photos

#Advent #Church #Jesus #Sing #Hymn  #AdventCandle #Candle</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="60"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:ae71A8eaGLI</id>
  <yt:videoId>ae71A8eaGLI</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship - Sunday 20th November 2022</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ae71A8eaGLI"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-11-20T12:25:47+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-11-29T16:26:22+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship - Sunday 20th November 2022</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/ae71A8eaGLI?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/ae71A8eaGLI/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00:00 - Opening music, photos, and notices

13:17 - Welcome and lighting of peace candle (an elder)

15:13 - Call to worship

Strength through vulnerability, peace through pain:
Jesus is the image of the unseen God.
Courage through truth, light through darkness:
Jesus is the image of the unseen God.

15:49 - Hymn - MP 465 Meekness and majesty

19:56 - Prayer of adoration and confession
Lord’s Prayer

22:48- 26:59 - Introducing of today’s theme: ‘Christ the King’

27:31 - 28:51 - Reading: Jeremiah 23.1-6 (NIVUK) read by David Bishop
23 ‘Woe to the shepherds who are destroying and scattering the sheep
of my pasture!’ declares the LORD.  2  Therefore this is what the LORD, the
God of Israel, says to the shepherds who tend my people: ‘Because you
have scattered my flock and driven them away and have not bestowed
care on them, I will bestow punishment on you for the evil you have
done,’ declares the LORD.  3  ‘I myself will gather the remnant of my flock
out of all the countries where I have driven them and will bring them
back to their pasture, where they will be fruitful and increase in
number.  4  I will place shepherds over them who will tend them, and they
will no longer be afraid or terrified, nor will any be missing,’ declares
the LORD.
5  ‘The days are coming,’ declares the LORD, ‘when I will raise up for
David a righteous Branch,
a King who will reign wisely and do what is just and right in the land.
6  In his days Judah will be saved and Israel will live in safety.
This is the name by which he will be called: The LORD Our Righteous
Saviour.

29:40 - 33:12 - Hymn MP 1008 The Lord’s my shepherd (Stuart Townend)

33:18 - Activity: ‘A king chart’
Thinking about Kings
What do you associate with the word King?
Castles
Privilege
Wealth
Heredity
Fine Clothes
Powerful
Authority
War
History
Which of these connect with Christ the King?
Powerful, crown, heritage, authority, history
That's not enough, let's add some words specific to Jesus
Faithful, loving, shepherd, servant, compassionate, humble

48:10 - Pilate's sign above the cross - Jesus King of the Jews

49:28 - Reading Luke 23.33-43 (NIVUK) read by Val Bishop
33  When they came to the place called the Skull, they crucified him there,
along with the criminals – one on his right, the other on his left.  34  Jesus
said, ‘Father, forgive them, for they do not know what they are
doing.’ [a]  And they divided up his clothes by casting lots. 35  The people
stood watching, and the rulers even sneered at him. They said, ‘He saved
others; let him save himself if he is God’s Messiah, the Chosen One.’
36  The soldiers also came up and mocked him. They offered him wine
vinegar  37  and said, ‘If you are the king of the Jews, save yourself.’
38  There was a written notice above him, which read: THIS IS THE KING OF THE
JEWS. 39  One of the criminals who hung there hurled insults at him: ‘Aren’t
you the Messiah? Save yourself and us!’ 40  But the other criminal
rebuked him. ‘Don’t you fear God,’ he said, ‘since you are under the
same sentence?  41  We are punished justly, for we are getting what our
deeds deserve. But this man has done nothing wrong.’
42  Then he said, ‘Jesus, remember me when you come into your
kingdom.’ 43  Jesus answered him, ‘Truly I tell you, today you will be with
me in paradise.’

51:04 - 53:05 - Short talk: Preparing for the King, praying for the kingdom
One of the great prayers of the New Testament - &quot;Jesus, remember me when you come into your
kingdom&quot;
This is an incredible King we are thinking of
In our system, the monarchy recognises its dependence on God, a King of love
He is the King of Kings
Next Sunday at the beginning of Advent we begin to prepare for the arrival of our King

53:06 - Craft Activity: Crown of love

01:03:50 - 01:08:00 - Hymn R&amp;S 522 From heaven you came

01:08:34 - Offering Prayer
Lord, show us where and how we can serve you,
the king who serves and gives yourself for us.
In our words and in our lives, we will worship you,
The King of love, the Prince of Peace.

01:09:30 - Taize Song - Jesus remember me (sung three times)
Jesus remember me, when you come into your kingdom…

01:11:11 - Prayers for the world with the response
Jesus, King of love,
remember them today.

01:15:39 - 01:19:01 - Hymn R&amp;S 262 Crown him the Lord of life

01:19:02 - 01:19:37 - Blessing
Let us hold fast to that which is good
In the strength of Jesus we are powerful
Let us never give in to evil.
In the peace of Jesus we are forgiven
Let follow his way of compassion
In the love of Jesus we are encircled
Blessed today and always
Amen.

01:19:54 - 01:22:45 - Music and notices after the service

#StirUpSunday #Church #Worship #Jeremiah #Luke #Bible #Crowns #JuniorChurch #TheLordsMyShepherd #Shepherd #Lord #God #Jesus</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="1" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="30"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:8HUynkMXiWc</id>
  <yt:videoId>8HUynkMXiWc</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship - Sunday 13th November 2022 - Remembrance Sunday</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8HUynkMXiWc"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-11-13T13:28:50+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-11-14T08:54:40+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship - Sunday 13th November 2022 - Remembrance Sunday</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/8HUynkMXiWc?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/8HUynkMXiWc/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00:00 - Opening music, photos, and notices

10:43 - Welcome and notices (an elder)

Call to worship
Lighting of Peace candle
Minister: On this Remembrance Sunday, we affirm that God is with us now, source of true peace.
All:  Be present with us, Lord, bring life and hope.
Minister: We remember the victory of Jesus Christ over death 
and hatred and his greeting ‘Peace be with you’:
All:  Be present with us, Lord, bring grace and peace.
Minister: Christ’s light shines in our world and in our hearts 
and the world’s darkness will never overcome it:
All:  Be present with us, Lord: 
lead us by the light of your love and truth.

13:16 - 15:57 - Hymn MP 1201  Longing for light (vs 1,2 and 5)

15:58 - 18:11 - Prayer of adoration and confession

18:17 - 25:04 - Introduction for all ages: ‘peace begins here and now’
Today is the day we remember
The different colours of poppies now available
White for peace, red for suffering and sacrifice
What other colours will be made available in the future as we recognise the impact of war
Imagine a pebble, holding it in your hand
Ripples in the water
Turning hearts of stone to love

Lord, lead me from death to life, from falsehood to truth;
lead me from despair to hope, from fear to trust;
lead me from hate to love, from war to peace.
Let peace fill our heart, our world, our universe.  Amen.

25:22 - 26:50 - Reading: Micah 4: 1 – 5 read by Larry Ogbewe
4 In the last days the mountain of the LORD’s temple will be established as the highest of the mountains; it will be exalted above the hills, and peoples will stream to it.  2 Many nations will come and say,
‘Come, let us go up to the mountain of the LORD, to the temple of the God of Jacob.  He will teach us his ways, so that we may walk in his paths.’
  The law will go out from Zion, the word of the LORD from Jerusalem.  3 He will judge between many peoples and will settle disputes for strong nations far and wide.  They will beat their swords into ploughshares and their spears into pruning hooks.  Nation will not take up sword against nation, nor will they train for war any more.  4 Everyone will sit under their own vine and under their own fig-tree, and no one will make them afraid, for the LORD Almighty has spoken.
5 All the nations may walk in the name of their gods,
but we will walk in the name of the LORD our God for ever and ever.

27:57 - 29:12 - Reading: Revelation 22. 1 – 5 read by Norma Garden
Then the angel showed me the river of the water of life, as clear as crystal, flowing from the throne of God and of the Lamb 2 down the middle of the great street of the city. On each side of the river stood the tree of life, bearing twelve crops of fruit, yielding its fruit every month. And the leaves of the tree are for the healing of the nations. 3 No longer will there be any curse. The throne of God and of the Lamb will be in the city, and his servants will serve him. 4 They will see his face, and his name will be on their foreheads. 5 There will be no more night. They will not need the light of a lamp or the light of the sun, for the Lord God will give them light. And they will reign for ever and ever.

30:01 - Hymn R&amp;S 477 - Let there be love shared among us

32:07 - Prayer before the Act of Remembrance

36:56 - Act of remembrance at 11 am
They shall grow not old, as we that are left grow old; 
age shall not weary them, nor the years condemn. 
At the going down of the sun and in the morning, 
we will remember them. 
We will remember them.

The  two minutes of silence
Prayers

43:19 - 46:36 - Hymn -  R&amp;S 705  Our God, our help in ages past

46:42 - 01:00:36 - Short Address: ‘healing a broken world’

Minister: On this day when our nation remembers the sacrifices of the past and the conflicts and crises of the present, we offer our lives once more for God’s work of healing a broken world and bringing peace and justice to all:  
All:  God of hope, we commit ourselves 
to your way of truth and compassion.
As we work for peace – give us wisdom, 
as we strive for justice – give us courage, 
as we care for those in need – give us compassion. 
As we strive to protect the planet – give us hope
Through Jesus Christ our Lord. Amen.

01:00:52 - 01:04:20 - Hymn R&amp;S 629  Make me a channel of your peace

01:04:24 - Thanksgiving Prayer and Lord’s Prayer

01:07:19 - Distribution of bread and wine 

01:13:40 - Closing Prayer 

01:14:37 - 01:17:50 - Hymn R&amp;S 620   For the healing of the nations

01:17:52 - 01:18:30 - Blessing

01:18:58 - 01:22:14 - Music and notices after the service

#Remembrance #WeWillRemenberThem #NeverForget #Poppy #Poppies #Flanders #Church #Worship #Cenotaph</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="28"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:LeUKLHZrtxg</id>
  <yt:videoId>LeUKLHZrtxg</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Trinity URC Sunday 6th November 2022 led by Rebecca Hawes</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LeUKLHZrtxg"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-11-06T11:52:59+00:00</published>
  <updated>2023-01-11T08:07:24+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Trinity URC Sunday 6th November 2022 led by Rebecca Hawes</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/LeUKLHZrtxg?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/LeUKLHZrtxg/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00:00 - Opening music, photos, and notices

13:51 - Welcome and lighting of peace candle (an elder)

15:47 - Call to worship

16:38 - 19:44 - Hymn:  Alleluia, Sing to Jesus  ( to tune MP315 ). 

19:51 - Opening Prayers and the Lord’s Prayer

22:34 - 27:50 - Talk for all ages
A wonderful catchphrase for the Christian faith
A quiz - who said this?
To infinity and beyond
Nice to see you , to see you nice
Here's one I made earlier
Simples
Ahana means family, family means no-one gets left behind
I have a cunning plan
Think happy thoughts
We know those catchphrases because they are used by people and we learn about those people by their use
If you had a catchphrase, would it tell us about you?
The phrase that Job uses - I know that my redeemer lives
He clings on to this through his trials and tribulations
Peter says we should always have hope
A challenge - how can we live our lives so that we point to the hope we have in Jesus  

28:10 - 30:44 - Hymn Come on and Celebrate  ( TP23 )
 
30:55 - Blessing as Junior Church go to their activities:

31:55 - Reading: Job 19:23-27a read by Samuel Evans

32:40 - Update on the work of Wycombe YFC
Sharing the &quot;Encounter&quot; project in secondary schools
A place young people can come to and put their gifts and talents to use
Launched just under 12 months ago
Real growth in young people offering to help
A new worship band
A safe space to encounter God
Helping at Lighthouse Cressex supporting the lamplighters
Mentoring and pastoral support in primary schools

44:16 - 46:15 - Reading: 2 Thessalonians 2:1-5 &amp; 13-end read by Kitty Bird

46:33 - 50:01 - Hymn: Lord for the Years (R&amp;S 603)

50:12 - 01:08:07 - Sermon followed by time of quiet reflection 

01:09:06 - 01:11:37 - Hymn: How sweet the name of Jesus sounds (R&amp;S 277)

01:11:48 - Prayers for others and ourselves

01:20:05 - 01:22:51 - Hymn: O Jesus I have Promised (R&amp;S 509) new tune                       

01:22:59 - 01:23:32 - 
01:23:33 - 01:24:06 - Closing blessing 

01:24:38 - 01:27:58 - Organ voluntary and photos/notices

#WycombeYouthForChrist #WYFC #YFC #Job19 #thessalonians #church #god #worship #jesus #urc #unitedreformedchurch #AllAreWelcome</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="27"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:Wf6luERPLNM</id>
  <yt:videoId>Wf6luERPLNM</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Trinity URC Sunday 30th October 2022</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Wf6luERPLNM"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-10-30T13:15:48+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-12-04T09:26:53+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Trinity URC Sunday 30th October 2022</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/Wf6luERPLNM?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/Wf6luERPLNM/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00:00 - Opening Music on the Organ. 

07:39 - Welcome and lighting of peace candle (an elder)

09:38 - Call to worship
What does the Lord our God require of us? Is it not to act justly,
love mercy and walk humbly with our God.

10:34 - 15:30 - Hymn - Let us build a house
© Marty Haugen 1994 GIA Publications

15:32 - Opening Prayers with the response
May the love of Christ unite us
in wonder, love and praise.

Lord’s Prayer

19:02 - Introduction for all ages – out of the box!
If you filled a box, what might be in it?
Soap, flannels, a toy, toothbrush &amp; paste, a hat and scarf
Shoebox Collection: Daphne Stopforth updates us on the work of

22:07 - Link to Hope in Eastern Europe (including Ukraine) and collects
any Christmas shoeboxes you have brought to church today

28:32 - 31:09 - Song from Ukraine (recording)
Lord, oh the Great and Almighty, protect our beloved Ukraine,
Bless her with freedom and light of your holy rays.
With learning and knowledge enlighten us, your children small,
In love pure and everlasting, let us, oh Lord, grow.
We pray, oh Lord Almighty, protect our beloved Ukraine,
Grant our people and country all your kindness and grace.
Bless us with freedom, bless us with wisdom,
Guide into a kind world, Bless us, oh Lord, with good fortune
for ever and evermore.

31:39 - 33:15 - Reading: Isaiah 1.10 – 18 (NIVUK) read by Linda Curley

34:23 - 44:26 - Update on Commitment for Life given by Angus Massie. Our
focus is on Israel and the occupied Palestinian territories.

45:40 - 47:56 - Hymn MP 376 - Jesus taught how to be a family

48:23 - 49:41 - Reading: Luke 19.1 – 10 (NIVUK) read by Julia Sparks

50:23 - 52:02 - Hymn R&amp;S 92 - Amazing grace
(vs 1 and 2 only, sung seated as a prayer)

52:08 - 01:01:52 - Short Talk
Jesus is on his way to Jerusalem
A city so important to people before and after through the centuries.
He went to confront hypocrisy
He knows this is part of God's plan to save the world
He has important business to do - global salvation
The little town of Jericho has to be passed through 
A little man up a tree catches his eye and despite the huge task ahead, Jesus pauses and gives him his attention
No-one is beyond Jesus' attention

01:01:57 - Prayers for the church and the world with sung response
Hymn R&amp;S 401 - Through our lives

01:09:28 - 01:12:34 - Hymn - R&amp;S 567 Thy hand, O God, has guided

01:12:36 - 01:13:05 - Blessing

01:13:28 - 01:17:33 - Organ voluntary and photos/notices</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="19"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:AqI779nVQs8</id>
  <yt:videoId>AqI779nVQs8</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Trinity URC Compassion Sunday Guest speaker 23rd Oct</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AqI779nVQs8"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-10-23T10:53:14+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-11-14T08:38:40+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Trinity URC Compassion Sunday Guest speaker 23rd Oct</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/AqI779nVQs8?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/AqI779nVQs8/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00:00 - Music before the service

07:34 - Welcome and lighting of peace candle (elder)

09:35 - Call to worship: words from Psalm 24

10:34 - 13:11 Hymn: Jesus shall reign where’er the sun R&amp;amp;S 269

13:20 - Opening Prayers and the Lord’s Prayer

15:49 - 20:48 - Trinity's sponsored children

20:55 - 39:18 - My story – Miss Dilini Paul
Our impact:
More than 3,000 hours for children at the projects we support
More than 1,000 nutritious meals
More than 15 medical checkups
20 Letters sent, 9 letters received

39:54 - 42:58 - Worship song: Blessed assurance

Blessing as Junior Church go to their activities:
Adults: May the Lord be with you
Junior Church: And also with you
All: Amen

Introduction to Bible readings

43:52 - 45:23 - Reading: Exodus 2 vv 5-10 read by Jeany Bien

45:37 - 49:18 - Hymn: King of Kings MP100

49:40 - 01:04:21 - Talk - Mr Vinoraj Thavarasa followed by time of quiet reflection
Sponsored children, how we help
Guatemala
Pharoah's daughter stopping by the water's edge
God putting compassion into her heart
She was willing to put forward her love and resources to care for the child

01:06:07 - 01:10:07 - Hymn: Christ be our light MP1201

01:10:23 - Prayers for others and ourselves led by Rosemary

01:13:50 - 01:17:34 - Hymn: We’ve a story to tell to the nations MP744

01:17:35 - 01:17:53 - Closing blessing
The Grace

01:18:11 - 01:22:30 - Organ voluntary, photos, and notices

#God #exodus #Compassion #Jesus #sponsorachild  #mushroom #berries #berry #autumn #leaves</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="12"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
</feed>
