<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns:yt="http://www.youtube.com/xml/schemas/2015" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 <link rel="self" href="http://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=PLrggWHcy3azrunmSfTCSlS5JRuB4zTgCY"/>
 <id>yt:playlist:PLrggWHcy3azrunmSfTCSlS5JRuB4zTgCY</id>
 <yt:playlistId>PLrggWHcy3azrunmSfTCSlS5JRuB4zTgCY</yt:playlistId>
 <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
 <title>Worship services - Trinity and Cores End URCs</title>
 <author>
  <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
  <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
 </author>
 <published>2020-04-04T11:11:34+00:00</published>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:XYjNXhbXSCA</id>
  <yt:videoId>XYjNXhbXSCA</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship  - Sunday 19th March 2023 - 4th Sunday In Lent</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XYjNXhbXSCA"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2023-03-19T11:51:20+00:00</published>
  <updated>2023-03-19T12:01:09+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship  - Sunday 19th March 2023 - 4th Sunday In Lent</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/XYjNXhbXSCA?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/XYjNXhbXSCA/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00:00 - Opening music, photos, and notices

Entry of Bible (please stand if you are able)

Welcome and lighting of peace candle (an elder)

Call to worship
Leader: Let us worship the Living God,
Women: who is mother
Men: and father,
Women: loving saviour
Men: and faithful friend,
Leader: alpha and omega,
All: the beginning and the end,
Leader: life and being beyond all we can imagine.
All: We come to worship our God.

HYMN R&amp;amp;S 74 Praise to the Lord

Introduction: How do you pray? How do you see, imagine or
name the immortal, invisible God?

1 st Reading: Psalm 131 (The Message) read by Jeany Bien
GOD, I’m not trying to rule the roost,
    I don’t want to be king of the mountain.
I haven’t meddled where I have no business
    or fantasized grandiose plans.
2  I’ve kept my feet on the ground,
    I’ve cultivated a quiet heart.

Like a baby content in its mother’s arms,
    my soul is a baby content.
3  Wait, Israel, for GOD. Wait with hope.
    Hope now; hope always!

Prayer

SONG MP 1076 Jesus be the centre

2nd Reading Luke 13.34 read by Kitty Bird
Jesus said, ‘Jerusalem…How often have I desired to gather your
children together as a hen gathers her brood under her wings, and
you were not willing!’

Short talk: ‘Mothering – instinct to protect’

SONG MP 583 Safe in the shadow of the Lord

3 rd reading Matthew 12.46-50 NIVUK read by Kitty Bird
46  While Jesus was still talking to the crowd, his mother and
brothers stood outside, wanting to speak to him.  47  Someone told
him, ‘Your mother and brothers are standing outside, wanting to
speak to you.’
48  He replied, ‘Who is my mother, and who are my
brothers?’  49  Pointing to his disciples, he said, ‘Here are my mother
and my brothers.  50  For whoever does the will of my Father in
heaven is my brother and sister and mother.’
4 th Reading: John 19.26-27 read by Jeany Bien
26  When Jesus saw his mother there, and the disciple whom he
loved standing near by, he said to her, ‘Woman, here is your
son,’  27  and to the disciple, ‘Here is your mother.’ From that time
on, this disciple took her into his home.

Short Talk: ‘God’s new family’

HYMN R&amp;amp;S 41 For the beauty of the earth (Tune: 575)

All age Activity: ‘connected as one family’

HYMN R&amp;amp;S 518 Father I place into your hands

Leader: God who is father and mother to us all,
All: We place them in your hands.

Lord’s Prayer (modern version)

HYMN R&amp;amp;S 531 Lord of all hopefulness

Blessing

Music, photos , and notices after the service

#Church #Worship #Sing #Organ #Faithful #Jesus #URC #UnitedReformedChurch  #Blessings #GoodNews #NIV #NIVUK #Bible #Lessons #King #GoodNews #Hymns  #AllAreWelcome #JoinIn #Christian #WarmSpace #WednesdayCafe #RejoiceandSing #Compassion #Lent 

#PrayForTurkey #PrayForUkraine 

#SafeUnderTheWing #Swans #Elephant #Lioness #Cow #KeepWarm #Mothering #MotheringSunday #PartOfTheFamily #Family #Connected 

#SummarisedWithChatGPT #ChatGPT</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="4"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:qjGtwJrmnTE</id>
  <yt:videoId>qjGtwJrmnTE</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship  - Sunday 12th March 2023 - 3rd Sunday In Lent</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qjGtwJrmnTE"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2023-03-12T11:36:39+00:00</published>
  <updated>2023-03-17T08:43:45+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship  - Sunday 12th March 2023 - 3rd Sunday In Lent</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/qjGtwJrmnTE?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/qjGtwJrmnTE/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00:00 - Opening music, photos, and notices

05:05 - Entry of Bible (please stand if you are able)

05:23 - Welcome and lighting of peace candle led by Linda Curley

06:33 - Call to worship led by Linda Curley
We come to God rejoicing:
We bring our thanks and praise.
We come to God with our needs and concerns:
We bring our hopes and prayers.

06:51 - 11:07 - Hymn R&amp;S 39 All creatures of our God and King (vs 1-4 only)

11:39 - 12:59 - Reading: Psalm 95. 1 – 7 (adapted) read by Abigail Lokko

13:18 - 14:48 - Introduction to the theme: ‘water of life’
Reading: John 4. 5 – 8 NIVUK read by Rosemary Taylor

14:50 - 16:39 - Prayer
Lord's Prayer

16:48 - 19:25 - Song MP God forgave my sin in Jesus’ name

19:53 - 26:26 - Talk for all ages: ‘Wells, water and well-being’
The story of Jesus meeting a Samaritan at a well and the importance of water in our lives.
Water has been treated with great respect throughout history and is often seen as a holy place linked to particular local saints with healing miracles.
A church in Bierton, North of Aylesbury, linked to a Christian woman from medieval times called Asif.
Rivers, especially chalk streams, are important for wildlife and need to be looked after for the benefit of both wildlife and ourselves.
Sewage is sometimes dumped into our rivers, which is surely a disgrace to our nation.
The psalm used in the service reminds us that the planet belongs to God and the oceans belong to God, their maker.
A new high seas treaty by the United Nations to create large protected areas of the oceans to safeguard marine biodiversity.
Water is a key theme in Lent this year with support for Water Aid, which provides clean water and sanitation to many poor communities around the world.
The effects of climate change on water supplies in many poorer nations and the need to create water and sanitation services that last and can come back quickly online after a climate hazard.
Women's voices and experiences are essential in adapting to climate change, and they must be heard and acted upon.

26:35 - 29:01 - Hymn R&amp;S 572 Colours of day

29:17 - 31:03 - Reading: John 4.6 - 15 read by Norma Garden

31:18 - 34:20 - Hymn R&amp;S 349 I heard the voice

34:50 - 37:50 - Reading: John 4.16 – 30 NIVUK read by Abigail Lokko

38:19 - 44:11- Short Address
Wells are significant places in the Bible, and many important meetings took place at wells.
Jacob's Well, located in modern-day Palestine, is the most famous well in the Bible.
Maria, who lives in a small island in El Salvador, has to travel to the mainland every day to fetch water because there is no mains water on her island.
Many women in low-income countries have to do this kind of work every day.
In the encounter between Jesus and the Samaritan woman, both were thirsty and had to act to quench their thirst.
The physical and spiritual aspects of our lives are intertwined and essential to our well-being.
The American theologian Sally McFague believed that the interconnection of our souls and bodies brings us life in all its fullness.
We should value both physical and spiritual water as essential to our life and well-being.
We should recognize and accept everyone as brother and sister, as well as being accepted as a child of God.
We should be thirsty for the Water of Life.

followed by 2 or 3 minutes of quiet reflection on these questions:
- Do we welcome and value both the physical water and the
spiritual water as essential to our life and well-being?
- What do they teach us about recognising and accepting
everyone as brother and sister?
- What do we learn for ourselves about being accepted as
brother or sister, and a child of God?
- Are we thirsty for the water of life?

44:29 - 46:35 - Hymn R&amp;S 543 Lead us heavenly Father lead us

46:45 - 48:42 - Reading: John 4.31 – 42 NIVUK read by Norma Garden

49:11 - 54:02 - Prayers for the world led by Sue Thorne

54:12 - 57:46 - Hymn R&amp;S 579 Lord thy Church on earth

57:48 - 58:18 - Blessing

58:52 - 01:01:40 - Music, photos , and notices after the service

#Church #Worship #Sing #Organ #Faithful #Jesus #URC #UnitedReformedChurch  #Blessings #GoodNews #NIV #NIVUK #Bible #Lessons #King #GoodNews #Hymns    #AllAreWelcome #JoinIn #Christian #WarmSpace #WednesdayCafe #RejoiceandSing #Compassion #Lent #PrayersForTurkey #Temptation #Armor #Nicodemus #TheRepairShop #RepairShop #GBSnowSport #ParaSnowsport
#SummarisedWithChatGPT #Aylesbury #Bierton #Water #ClimateChange #Sewage #WaterAid #SomeHose #TwoRonnies 

Summarised with #ChatGPT</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="184"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:UXZjTykiJcg</id>
  <yt:videoId>UXZjTykiJcg</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship  - Sunday 5th March 2023 - 2nd Sunday In Lent</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UXZjTykiJcg"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2023-03-05T11:53:54+00:00</published>
  <updated>2023-03-15T06:59:59+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship  - Sunday 5th March 2023 - 2nd Sunday In Lent</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/UXZjTykiJcg?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/UXZjTykiJcg/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Worship and Communion led by Terry Hinks
Organist: Andrew Winton

00:00:00 - Opening music, photos, and notices

Entry of Bible (please stand if you are able)

07:55 - Welcome and lighting of peace candle (an elder)

10:13 - Call to worship 
We come to worship you, Lord, the maker of our lives.
We come to meet you, Lord, the keeper of our lives.
We come to hear you, Lord, the wisdom in our lives.
We come to follow you, Lord, the guider of our lives.

11:06 - 13:36 - Hymn - R&amp;S 67  Immortal, invisible, God only wise

13:42 - Prayers of adoration and confession

15:30 - 28:51 - All age talk: ‘Help! I need somebody!’
The Beatles and their song &quot;Help&quot; as an example of asking for help.
What helps you get through the day - things like daily devotions, friends, family, and nature.
The importance of turning to God for help, as well as offering help to others.
The Jars of Change appeal, which involves setting aside money over Lent to donate to the charity.
The charity's focus this year is on providing clean water and sanitation to communities in need.
Stories of two young women who have benefited from the charity's work.
The idea of giving and helping others, even in small ways.
A reminder that help can come from God and from our willingness to offer help to others.

29:18 - 30:16 - Reading: Psalm 121 NIVUK read by Ian Bogart
I lift up my eyes to the mountains –
    where does my help come from?
2 My help comes from the Lord,
    the Maker of heaven and earth.
3 He will not let your foot slip –
    he who watches over you will not slumber;
4 indeed, he who watches over Israel
    will neither slumber nor sleep.
5 The Lord watches over you –
    the Lord is your shade at your right hand;
6 the sun will not harm you by day, nor the moon by night.
7 The Lord will keep you from all harm –
    he will watch over your life;
8 the Lord will watch over your coming and going
    both now and for evermore.

31:00 - 33:37 - Hymn - R&amp;S 64  I lift my eyes to the quiet hills

33:44 - Introduction to the reading

34:47 - 37:13 - Reading: John 3.1-17 NIVUK 

37:34 - 39:39 - Hymn - MP 619  Such love
 
39:43 - 53:26 - Short Address:
The Repair Shop and the team of experts who restore old and broken items.
In August 2021, the team met with Prince Charles and learned about his foundation's work in training young craftspeople.
Charles gave the team a piece of pottery made for Queen Victoria's Diamond Jubilee and an 18th-century clock to repair.
Jay Blades, one of the show's hosts, grew up in Hackney, and he and Charles bonded over their shared interests in apprenticeships and heritage crafts.
The encounter between Nicodemus and Jesus in the Bible is similar to the meeting of Blades and Charles in that it brings together people from different backgrounds who share common interests.
Nicodemus is a Pharisee and a member of the ruling council in Jerusalem who comes to meet Jesus at night.
Nicodemus recognizes that God is at work in Jesus's ministry and life.
Jesus tells Nicodemus that he must be born again to see the kingdom of God.
This spiritual rebirth is about a fundamental change that enables us to see the kingdom of love, justice, and peace where God is at the center.
Jesus teaches that his followers must become like little children to enter the kingdom of heaven.
The kingdom of heaven is a place where God is at the center and all are of equal worth in the eyes of God.

53:30 - 58:22 - Prayers for the world with the response
So, God of compassion: 
open our hearts, to welcome all.

58:23 - Prayer of Dedication of all our gifts

01:01:41 - Communion: we invite you to share in the bread and wine at church (or at home) united in the name of Christ.
A Prayer of thanksgiving and Lord’s Prayer

Distribution of bread and wine (non-alcoholic grape juice)

Closing Prayer

01:08:27 - 01:11:02 -  Hymn R&amp;S 345  Guide me O thou Great Jehovah

01:11:03 - 01:11:32 - Blessing

01:11:58 - 01:15:16 - Music, photos , and notices after the service

#Church #Worship #Sing #Organ #Faithful #Jesus #URC #UnitedReformedChurch  #Blessings #GoodNews #NIV #NIVUK #Bible #Lessons #King #GoodNews #Hymns    #AllAreWelcome #JoinIn #Christian #WarmSpace #WednesdayCafe #RejoiceandSing #Compassion #Lent #PrayersForTurkey #Temptation #Armor #Nicodemus #TheRepairShop #RepairShop

Summarised with #ChatGPT</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="26"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:TxsijSqmzKQ</id>
  <yt:videoId>TxsijSqmzKQ</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship  - Sunday 26th February 2023 - 1st Sunday In Lent</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TxsijSqmzKQ"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2023-02-26T11:33:05+00:00</published>
  <updated>2023-02-28T08:43:03+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship  - Sunday 26th February 2023 - 1st Sunday In Lent</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/TxsijSqmzKQ?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/TxsijSqmzKQ/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Worship led by Richard Goldstraw
Organist: Charles Brewster

00:00:00 - Opening music, photos, and notices

02:26 - Welcome and lighting of the peace candle

04:29 - Call to worship

05:27 - 09:30 - Hymn – Praise to the holiest – Tune Gerontius

09:38 - Opening Prayers and the Lord’s Prayer

12:30 - 15:35 - Talk for all ages
The meaning and history of Lent, a season of penitence and self-denial observed to prepare for the Easter celebration. 
The importance of prayer, self-examination, and repentance during this period, as well as reading and meditating on God's word. 
A creative Lent daily program, which includes different activities for each day of the week
Sunday: Social media fast
Monday: Keep silence for at least 10 minutes
Tuesday: Do a prayer walk around your neighborhood
Wednesday: Fast your way (in a manner that is appropriate for your personal circumstances and needs)
Thursday: Connect with a friend by calling, texting, or sending an email
Friday: Read and reflect on God's holy word
Saturday: Rest and refresh.
Lent is our opportunity to grow in faith and devotion to Christ.
  
16:26 - 20:58 - Hymn – Dear Lord and Father
 
22:02 - Introduction to Bible readings

22:35 - 24:18 - Readings:  Psalm 32 NIVUK 
 
24:40 - 26:11 - Matthew 4:1-11 

27:29 - 29:42 - Hymn R&amp;S 543– Lead us heavenly Father Lead Us

29:48 - 41:05 - Sermon followed by time of quiet reflection 
Drawing inspiration from the hymn &quot;Father Lead Me Day by Day&quot; and Jesus' identity affirmation from God during his baptism.
The assurance of being saved by grace is necessary in our lives.
The promises of God should be hidden in our hearts to remain steadfast during temptations.
The full armor of God should be worn to stand firm against the devil's schemes.
Jesus defeated Satan on the cross, and we must use his name to resist temptations.
Jesus' response to temptations was quoting the word of God.
The spirit drives us into unusual and unexplored places.
The spirit is at work whenever people speak the language of love, dream of a new community, and reach out to one another.
God is gracious and picks us up when we stumble and fall into ditches along the way.
Nothing in all creation can separate us from the love of God in Christ Jesus, and goodness is stronger than evil, love is stronger than hate.
As children of God, we need to have the promises of God hidden in our hearts and be sure of our identity in Him. 
Temptations will come, but we can stand firm by putting on the full armor of God and using the Word of God to resist the devil's schemes. 
The Spirit may also drive us into unusual and unexplored places, and we need to be open to following His leading. Ultimately, we can take comfort in the fact that nothing can separate us from the love of God in Christ Jesus, and victory is ours through Him who loves us.

42:45 - 44:28 - Hymn – In my life Lord, Be Glorified

44:33 - 50:09 - Prayers for others and ourselves

51:59 - 55:40 - Hymn– O Jesus I have promised – Tune Hatherop                     

56:19 - 56:40 - Closing blessing 

57:01 - 01:02:24 - Music, photos , and notices after the service

#Church #Worship #Sing #Organ #Faithful #Jesus #URC #UnitedReformedChurch  #Blessings #GoodNews #NIV #NIVUK #Bible #Lessons #King #GoodNews #Hymns    #AllAreWelcome #JoinIn #Christian #WarmSpace #WednesdayCafe #RejoiceandSing #Compassion #Lent #PrayersForTurkey #Temptation #Armor 

Summarised with #ChatGPT</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="39"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:295Y8bfMr7w</id>
  <yt:videoId>295Y8bfMr7w</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship  - Sunday 19th February 2023</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=295Y8bfMr7w"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2023-02-19T11:57:28+00:00</published>
  <updated>2023-02-22T23:17:00+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship  - Sunday 19th February 2023</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/295Y8bfMr7w?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/295Y8bfMr7w/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00:00 - Opening music, photos, and notices

08:00 - Entry of Bible (please stand if you are able)

08:20 - Welcome and lighting of the peace candle 

10:28 - Call to worship
Exalt the Lord our God and worship at his holy mountain, for
the Lord our God is holy. Grace and peace from God our Father
and the Lord Jesus Christ

10:56 - 14:37 - Hymn - MP 77 Christ triumphant

14:40 - Opening Prayer of praise with the response
God of glory (truth), to you
We offer our worship and praise.

17:35 - Lord’s Prayer (modern version)

18:18 - Introduction: ‘what just happened?’
The importance of paying attention and being good witnesses in our daily lives. 
A scene from Sherlock Holmes to illustrate how we often do things without noticing.


25:43 - 27:09 - Readings: Exodus 24.12-18 NIVUK 

27:23 - 36:34 - Short Talk: ‘A mountain top experience’
The story of Moses and the giving of the Ten Commandments is a significant moment in the faith story.
The invitation from God for Moses to come up the mountain was initially frightening but is seen as gracious.
Mountains have been sacred places in many different cultures and faiths, and they speak of powers beyond our own.
The Holy God is described as a mystery, appearing as cloud, blazing light, and fire.
The law that Moses was given on the mountain would make the Israelites a holy people as they live by the Commandments of honoring God and loving their neighbor.
Moses stayed on the mountain for 40 days and 40 nights, which is significant in both the Old and New Testaments.
Lent is a period of 40 days, leading up to the eve of Easter, and represents a journey towards the Mountaintop of Easter day.
The signs of spring, such as snowdrops, are a symbol of God's renewing love and a reminder of the presence of Jesus.
The prayer at the end of the passage is a reminder to seek hope and peace during the darker days and to be enlightened on our journey through Lent and beyond.

36:44 - 40:03 - Hymn - 454 Majesty, worship his majesty

40:32 - 41:57 - Reading: Matthew 17. 1 – 9 (The Message) 

42:36 - 44:22 - Hymn - MP 545 Open our eyes Lord (sung twice seated)

45:20 - 47:13 - Reflection: ‘After the event’ Peter, James and John remember
&quot;Brothers of thunder&quot;

48:18 - 51:19 - Hymn - MP 1227 The splendour of the King

51:22 - 01:00:35 - Short talk: ‘wonderers, worshippers and witnesses’
The topic of reflection is the story of the three disciples who went up the mountain with Jesus and witnessed the splendor of God.
A reflection on four words related to the story of Jesus and his disciples on the mountain: wonder, worship, witness, and work.
Wonder: Take a step back and wonder at the mysteries of God's presence, creation, and scripture during the season of Lent.
Worship: The disciples' worship involved listening to Jesus, listen deeply to Jesus in scripture as the heart of worship.
Witness: Witness to the reality of Jesus with humility and through both words and actions.
Work: The disciples were invited to be part of the work of Jesus, we should pray for and participate in God's work in the world today.

The disciples' experience on the mountain was a revelation of divine light that they could not put into words.
The disciples' response was to worship, but they had a lot to learn about true worship, which involves following and listening to Jesus.
Listening to Jesus is at the heart of worship and is an essential aspect of our tradition.
After wandering, worshiping, and listening, we are called to be witnesses of Jesus, but our witness can be mistaken if we fail to witness to the reality of Jesus.
Witnessing requires humility and a deep understanding of the love of God.
We are encouraged to pray for God's work in the world and for our part in it.


Prayer Activity ending with shared prayer

All our prayers, silent and spoken we bring to you, God of life
and light. Help us to know the love of Jesus, to see his hidden
glory, shining all around. Amen.

01:00:47 - 01:04:24 - Hymn - MP 728 We have a gospel to proclaim

01:04:26 - 01:04:48 - Blessing

01:05:13 - 01:10:30 - Music, notices and photos 

Summarised with #ChatGPT 

#Church #Worship #Sing #Organ #Faithful #Jesus #URC #UnitedReformedChurch  #Blessings #GoodNews #NIV #NIVUK #Bible #Lessons #King #GoodNews #Hymns    #AllAreWelcome #JoinIn #Christian #WarmSpace #WednesdayCafe #RejoiceandSing #Compassion #Lent #PrayersForTurkey</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="21"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:FnDtb89_PuU</id>
  <yt:videoId>FnDtb89_PuU</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship  - Sunday 12th February 2023</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FnDtb89_PuU"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2023-02-12T11:57:28+00:00</published>
  <updated>2023-02-14T15:55:56+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship  - Sunday 12th February 2023</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/FnDtb89_PuU?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/FnDtb89_PuU/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00:00 - Opening music, photos, and notices

Entry of Bible (please stand if you are able)

10:07 - Welcome and lighting of peace candle (an elder)

12:08 - Call to worship

13:07 - 15:38  - Hymn R&amp;S 97: King of glory, King of peace

15:41 - Opening Prayers
18:11 - Lord’s Prayer

19:06 - Reading: Matthew 6. 25 – 34 NIVUK read by Sue Thorne
25  ‘Therefore I tell you, do not worry about your life, what you will
eat or drink; or about your body, what you will wear. Is not life
more than food, and the body more than clothes?  26  Look at the
birds of the air; they do not sow or reap or store away in barns,
and yet your heavenly Father feeds them. Are you not much more
valuable than they?  27  Can any one of you by worrying add a single
hour to your life [ ?
28  ‘And why do you worry about clothes? See how the flowers of
the field grow. They do not labour or spin.  29  Yet I tell you that not
even Solomon in all his splendour was dressed like one of
these.  30  If that is how God clothes the grass of the field, which is
here today and tomorrow is thrown into the fire, will he not much
more clothe you – you of little faith?  31  So do not worry, saying,
“What shall we eat?” or “What shall we drink?” or “What shall we
wear?”  32  For the pagans run after all these things, and your
heavenly Father knows that you need them.  33  But seek first his
kingdom and his righteousness, and all these things will be given
to you as well.  34  Therefore do not worry about tomorrow, for
tomorrow will worry about itself. Each day has enough trouble of
its own.

20:56 - 25:03 - Introduction to the service (all age talk)
Worrying is a common experience that is not always easy to overcome.
We often worry about trivial things that waste our time and energy.
Jesus wanted people to be free of constant worrying.
Worrying about a job change and how it turned out to be unnecessary.
Jesus advises us to put our worries down and not let them make our lives hard.
Life will have its ups and downs, and worrying only makes it worse.
Trusting in God and his love can help us cope with life's challenges.
We should focus on living one day at a time instead of worrying about the future.
God will bring us safely through life's difficulties and to heaven.
Trust in God's love and rely on Him to help us cope with life's challenges instead of worrying about things that are outside of our control.

25:19 - 28:44 - Hymn R&amp;S 86: God who stretched the spangled heavens

29:10 - 31:10 - Reading: Romans 8. 18 – 25 NIVUK read by John Hillson (seated)
18  I consider that our present sufferings are not worth comparing
with the glory that will be revealed in us.  19  For the creation waits
in eager expectation for the children of God to be revealed.  20  For
the creation was subjected to frustration, not by its own choice,
but by the will of the one who subjected it, in hope  21  that [a]  the
creation itself will be liberated from its bondage to decay and
brought into the freedom and glory of the children of God.
22  We know that the whole creation has been groaning as in the
pains of childbirth right up to the present time.  23  Not only so, but
we ourselves, who have the firstfruits of the Spirit, groan inwardly
as we wait eagerly for our adoption to sonship, the redemption of
our bodies.  24  For in this hope we were saved. But hope that is seen
is no hope at all. Who hopes for what they already have?  25  But if
we hope for what we do not yet have, we wait for it patiently.

31:25 - 34:50 - Hymn R&amp;S 364: Just as I am

34:57 - 49:43 - Address
Our age is characterized by anxiety and worry.
Hyper-connectivity in a globalized world increases our exposure to anxiety and worry.
Some people are more prone to anxiety than others.
God will take care of what comes our way in life.
Life is more important than material possessions.
Focusing on the present moment and giving attention to what God is doing can alleviate worry and anxiety.
Worry is illogical and misses the point of life. Trusting God and living one day at a time is the way to true peace.
As Christians, we're called to have faith in God's care and provision. Worry and anxiety are incompatible with this faith.
Trust that God knows your every need, not just your wants. Live each day with gratitude and reliance on Him.
Today is the only performance we'll give. Let's make the most of it by trusting God, living with purpose, and rejoicing in His goodness. #faith #trustGod #dontworry #liveonedayatatime #rejoice


50:12 - 53:52 - Hymn R&amp;S 267: Immortal love for ever full

53:56 - Prayers of intercession

58:55 - 01:02:16 - Hymn R&amp;S 285: O for a thousand tongues to sing

01:02:18 - 01:02:39 - Blessing

01:03:07 - 01:07:00 - Music, notices and photos 


#Church #Worship #Sing #Organ #Faithful #Jesus #URC #UnitedReformedChurch  #Blessings #GoodNews #NIV #NIVUK #Bible #Lessons #King #GoodNews #Hymns    #AllAreWelcome #JoinIn #Christian #WarmSpace #WednesdayCafe #RejoiceandSing #Compassion #Lent #PrayersForTurkey</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="51"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:DNAiyXB-Fn8</id>
  <yt:videoId>DNAiyXB-Fn8</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship  - Sunday 29th January 2023</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DNAiyXB-Fn8"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2023-01-29T11:47:49+00:00</published>
  <updated>2023-02-27T04:16:07+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship  - Sunday 29th January 2023</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/DNAiyXB-Fn8?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/DNAiyXB-Fn8/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00:00 - Opening music, photos, and notices

Entry of Bible (please stand if you are able)

07:50 - Welcome and lighting of peace candle (an elder)

09:22 - Call to worship
Let us come into the presence of God…
…so together we come to worship
We come to worship the Living God
Together we come to be still and know
We come to know that we are loved by God,
the source of all life and truth and love. Amen

10:19 - 14:32 - Hymn -  MP 1259 Bless the Lord my soul (Matt Redman)

14:38 - Prayers of adoration and confession

Lord's Prayer

16:46 - 27:50 - All age talk: Well I’m blessed!’ and ‘Bless you!’
Use of the word &quot;bless&quot; and its variations in the context of Christianity and worship.
Counting one's blessings and giving thanks to God, even on difficult days.
Photographs sent in by members of the congregation during worship.
Sharing our own blessings
Linking to the Beatitudes
The importance of blessings in the Christian life and the act of giving thanks to God.
The joy of having a good pudding as a blessing and enjoying a good apple crumble.

27:53 - 28:58 - Reading: Psalm 15 (The Message)

29:27 - 33:00 - Hymn - TP 15 Bind us together

33:36 - Introduction to the readings

34:35 - 36:40 - Reading: Micah 6.1 – 8 NIVUK read by Alan Yates
He has shown you, O mortal, what is good.
    And what does the LORD require of you?
To act justly and to love mercy and to walk humbly with your God.

37:52 - Prayer:
What does it mean to act justly today? (pause)
Lord guide us in your Way of justice
What does it mean to love mercy? (pause)
Lord guide us in your Way of mercy.
What does it mean to walk humbly with our God? (pause)
Lord guide us in our journey with you.
Deepen within us, faith, hope and love,
in Jesus’ name. Amen.

39:15 - 40:33 - Reading: Matthew 5.1 – 12 NIVUK read by Kate Yates
5 Now when Jesus saw the crowds, he went up on a mountainside and
sat down. His disciples came to him,  2  and he began to teach them.
He said: 3  ‘Blessed are the poor in spirit,   for theirs is the kingdom of
heaven.
4  Blessed are those who mourn,  for they will be comforted.
5  Blessed are the meek,  for they will inherit the earth.
6  Blessed are those who hunger and thirst for righteousness,
    for they will be filled.
7  Blessed are the merciful,  for they will be shown mercy.
8  Blessed are the pure in heart,   for they will see God.
9  Blessed are the peacemakers,   for they will be called children of God.
10  Blessed are those who are persecuted because of righteousness,
    for theirs is the kingdom of heaven.
11  ‘Blessed are you when people insult you, persecute you and falsely say
all kinds of evil against you because of me.  12  Rejoice and be glad,
because great is your reward in heaven, for in the same way they
persecuted the prophets who were before you.

40:50 - 43:32 - Hymn - R&amp;S 636 The Church of Christ

43:37 - 55:38 - Address
Reflecting on the meaning and use of the word &quot;bless&quot; and &quot;blessings.&quot; 
The different ways in which the word can be used and the importance of matching words of blessings with actions of blessings. 
The experience of blessing a teddy bear at a hospice
Many prophets remind us that blessings cannot be taken for granted and must be matched by actions of blessing. 
The importance of being blessings to others and not taking the blessings we enjoy for granted. 
Sharing food with leaders from other churches to mark the end of a week of prayer for Christian Unity.
I pray that we will be a church that blesses our wider community that risks blessing unsuitable people and unsuitable things
May we all know that glorious blessing of Jesus and be that blessing to our hurting world

55:59 - 01:00:54 - Hymn -  MP 857 I, the Lord of sea and sky

01:01:00 - Prayers for the church and the world with the response
So for them we pray
Grant courage, peace and strength.

01:08:15 - 01:10:52 - Hymn - R&amp;S 344 God of grace and God of glory

01:10:54 - 01:11:25 - Blessing
 
01:11:39 - 01:14:06 - Music, notices and photos 


#Church #Worship #Sing #Organ #Faithful #Jesus #URC #UnitedReformedChurch  #Blessings #GoodNews #NIV #NIVUK #Bible #Lessons #King #GoodNews #Hymns    #AllAreWelcome #JoinIn #Christian #WarmSpace #WednesdayCafe #RejoiceandSing</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="34"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:qCUNEJqjFGc</id>
  <yt:videoId>qCUNEJqjFGc</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship  - Sunday 22nd January 2023</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qCUNEJqjFGc"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2023-01-22T12:43:09+00:00</published>
  <updated>2023-01-31T09:10:45+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship  - Sunday 22nd January 2023</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/qCUNEJqjFGc?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/qCUNEJqjFGc/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00:00 - Opening music, photos, and notices

Entry of Bible (please stand if you are able)

08:26 - Welcome and lighting of peace candle (an elder)

10:22 - CALL TO WORSHIP Psalm 27:1
The lord is my light and my salvation;
  I will fear no one.  
The Lord will protect me from all danger;
  I will never be afraid.

11:23 - 13:18 - Hymn - R&amp;S 608 – Awake, awake to love and work

13:26 - PRAYERS - Approach, Confession, Thanksgiving and Praise
 
18:31 - LORD'S PRAYER Modern version

19:09 - WE LISTEN FOR GOD’S WORD

19:59 - 21:48 - 1st READING Matthew 4:12-23 NIVUK read by David Bishop
12 When Jesus heard that John had been put in prison, he withdrew to Galilee. 13 Leaving Nazareth, he went and lived in Capernaum, which was by the lake in the area of Zebulun and Naphtali – 14 to fulfil what was said through the prophet Isaiah:
15 ‘Land of Zebulun and land of Naphtali,
    the Way of the Sea, beyond the Jordan,
    Galilee of the Gentiles –
16 the people living in darkness
    have seen a great light;
on those living in the land of the shadow of death
    a light has dawned.’[a]
17 From that time on Jesus began to preach, ‘Repent, for the kingdom of heaven has come near.’
18 As Jesus was walking beside the Sea of Galilee, he saw two brothers, Simon called Peter and his brother Andrew. They were casting a net into the lake, for they were fishermen. 19 ‘Come, follow me,’ Jesus said, ‘and I will send you out to fish for people.’ 20 At once they left their nets and followed him.
21 Going on from there, he saw two other brothers, James son of Zebedee and his brother John. They were in a boat with their father Zebedee, preparing their nets. Jesus called them, 22 and immediately they left the boat and their father and followed him.
23 Jesus went throughout Galilee, teaching in their synagogues, proclaiming the good news of the kingdom, and healing every disease and illness among the people.
 
22:00 - 27:32 - ALL AGE TALK ‘Are you called to follow?’
&quot;Following&quot; people on social media websites, and how the younger generation may interpret this differently than older generations.
Can you identify these icons?
Different social media websites use different terms for following people (e.g. followers on Twitter, subscribers on YouTube).
Does following on social media cost you anything?
The real cost of following someone on social media may be a mental one, contrast with Jesus asking someone to &quot;follow me&quot; in the Bible.
If Jesus were on Twitter, it would be interesting to see how many tweets he would produce, and how many people would follow him.
Social media today doesn't cost us anything in terms of money, but the cost may be more mental or emotional.
   
27:51 - 31:43 - HYMN R&amp;S R&amp;S 367 – I want to walk with Jesus Christ

32:14 - Introduction to the second reading

33:07 - 34:02 - 2nd READING Isaiah 9:1-4 NIVUK read by Valerie Bishop
2 The people walking in darkness
    have seen a great light;
on those living in the land of deep darkness
    a light has dawned.

34:31 - 37:49 - HYMN  R&amp;S 679 – The Lord is my shepherd.

37:58 - 51:59 - SERMON ‘Leaders and followers’
The good, the bad, and the ugly of leadership styles.
Tony Blair - &quot;the art of leadership is being able to say no&quot;
Peter Drucker - &quot;management is doing things right and leadership is doing the right things.&quot;
An adapted definition of leadership given by Colin Powell, which is that the day the &quot;congregation&quot; stops bringing their problems to the leader is the day the leader has stopped leading, and either the congregation has lost confidence in the leader or they believe the leader doesn't care.
Connect to the reading from Isaiah, which mentions Zebulun and Nephthali, two of the leaders of the twelve tribes
The early part of the passage in Isaiah has a broader appeal and can be applied to anyone living in darkness and in the shadow of death.
Linking the phrase &quot;valley of the shadow of death&quot; from the reading from Isaiah to the broader concept of living in darkness and difficulties.
Applying this to anyone facing challenges and difficulties in life.
Leadership in difficult times and the hope of light and guidance in those times.

WE MAKE OUR RESPONSE

52:19 - 54:30 - HYMN R&amp;S 543 – Lead us, heavenly Father, lead us

54:35 - DEDICATION of our OFFERINGS

55:11 - PRAYERS of intercession 

01:00:45 - 01:04:12 - HYMN R&amp;S 509 – O Jesus, I have promised
 
01:04:41 - 01:04:58 - BLESSING 

01:05:16 - 01:09:17 - Music, notices, and photos after the service


#Church #Worship #Sing #Organ #Faithful #Jesus #URC #UnitedReformedChurch  #Blessings #GoodNews #NIV #NIVUK #Bible #Lessons #King #GoodNews #Hymns    #AllAreWelcome #JoinIn #Christian #WarmSpace #WednesdayCafe #RejoiceandSing

Key points provided using #ChatGPT</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="36"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:wbW7EYqc7cU</id>
  <yt:videoId>wbW7EYqc7cU</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship  - Sunday 15th January 2023</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wbW7EYqc7cU"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2023-01-15T11:31:48+00:00</published>
  <updated>2023-01-25T08:52:37+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship  - Sunday 15th January 2023</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/wbW7EYqc7cU?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/wbW7EYqc7cU/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00:00 - Opening music, photos, and notices

03:29 - Welcome and lighting of peace candle (an elder)

06:11 - Call to Worship – Poem by Dominic Windram

07:12 - 10:18 - Hymn - 187: Worship the Lord

10:28 - Opening Prayer – Faithfulness of God
Almighty and loving God, we thank you for the assurance we have
that you are always with us, that in you we will find help and
strength in times of trouble, that whatever we face you will
always be there to reach out and save us.
Almighty and loving God. Take our faith, weak though it is. Kindle
the sparks of life within us and fan a new flame of love within our
hearts, so, may we set out into another week with renewed
purpose, resolved to live and work for you, in the assurance that
you are with us, now and always,
Great is your faithfulness, from one generation to another. Thanks
be to God. Amen.

Lord’s Prayer

12:12 - 14:38 - Hymn - 188: Born in the night

14:58 - 16:29 - Bible reading: Isaiah 60 Verses 1-6 read by Abigail Lokko

16:49 - 20:26 - Hymn - 183: Brightest and best

20:44 - 22:51 - Bible Reading: Matthew 2: 1-12 read by Harri Bello

23:27 - 25:50 - Epiphany Prayer of Confession
Loving God, you guided the wise men to Bethlehem, offering a
light for their path, and in faith they responded. Forgive us that all
too often we fall short of their example.
Gracious Lord, have mercy.
You offer us guidance in innumerable ways – through the light of
your word, the illumination of your Holy Spirit, the fellowship of
your church, and the encounter of prayer, yet so often we either
fail to hear or refuse to see.
Gracious Lord, have mercy.
We are too preoccupied with our own small affairs, eyes only for
the immediate moment, our vision impeded by trivial concerns, so
we fail to recognise where you are leading us,
Gracious Lord, have mercy.
We believe we know just where we are going, just what we want
from life, and exactly how we can get it, and we resist any
suggestion that we need to think again.
Gracious Lord, have mercy.
Loving God, forgive us our foolishness, our stubbornness, our
weakness.
Gracious Lord, have mercy.
Forgive our pride, our lack of faith, our closed minds.
Gracious Lord, have mercy.
Forgive us for ignoring your guidance, for resting your will, and as
a result so often walking in darkness.
Gracious Lord, have mercy.
Meet with us again we ask, and may the light of your love shine in
our hearts, so that we cannot but see it or fail to respond in
grateful praise and joyful service.
Gracious Lord, have mercy, in the name of Christ .Amen

26:11 - 29:39 - Hymn - 185: Wise men seeking Jesus

29:46 - 45:14 - Talk: ‘What gifts shall we bring?’ - Pastor Vince Gerhardy
The Wise Men are often depicted in Christmas imagery as arriving at the manger with the shepherds, but they may have arrived later, when Jesus was a child.
The Wise Men are not named in the reading and little is known about their origins or how far they traveled.
Gold, frankincense, and myrrh, unusual gifts for a baby.
The story of the Wise Men is traditionally part of the celebration of Epiphany, which is usually celebrated on January 6th, 12 days after Christmas.
Focusing on the Wise Men's story separately from the celebration of Jesus' birth allows us to appreciate their significance.
The gifts of gold, frankincense, and myrrh are said to symbolize Jesus as a king, God and a sacrifice for humanity respectively.
What gifts shall we bring to Jesus.


45:22 - 46:14 - Time of quiet reflection and silent prayers for the world ending
with this prayer:
Loving God, accept our gifts for your work today.
Inspire our lives to reflect more truly the love of Jesus.
Hear our silent prayers for people on our hearts and places in
desperate need. Bring your healing and your peace, in Jesus name.
Amen.

46:30 - 49:43 - Hymn 184: As with gladness men of old

49:45 - 50:03 - Blessing

51:10 - 52:43 - Organ voluntary

#Church #Worship #Sing #Organ #Faithful #Jesus #URC #UnitedReformedChurch  #Blessings #GoodNews #NIV #NIVUK #Bible #Lessons #King #GoodNews #Choir   #AllAreWelcome #JoinIn #Epiphany #Christian #WarmSpace #WednesdayCafe

Speaking summaries provided using #ChatGPT</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="21"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:vdLg62x5pKc</id>
  <yt:videoId>vdLg62x5pKc</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship  - Sunday 8th January 2023</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vdLg62x5pKc"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2023-01-08T12:12:21+00:00</published>
  <updated>2023-01-18T08:42:37+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship  - Sunday 8th January 2023</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/vdLg62x5pKc?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/vdLg62x5pKc/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00:00 - Opening music, photos, and notices

04:08 - Welcome and lighting of the peace candle

05:50 - CALL TO WORSHIP – Isaiah 42: 6-7

07:24 - Hymn - R&amp;S 134 On Jordan’s bank the Baptist’s cry.
(Tune 209)

10:07 - PRAYERS - Approach, Confession, Thanksgiving &amp;amp; Praise

14:30 - LORD'S PRAYER

15:10 - WE LISTEN FOR GOD’S WORD

15:51 - 17:36 - READING 1 – Isaiah 42:1-9 NIVUK read by Ian Bogart
‘Here is my servant, whom I uphold,
    my chosen one in whom I delight;
I will put my Spirit on him,
    and he will bring justice to the nations.
2  He will not shout or cry out,
    or raise his voice in the streets.
3  A bruised reed he will not break,
    and a smouldering wick he will not snuff out.

In faithfulness he will bring forth justice;
4      he will not falter or be discouraged
till he establishes justice on earth.
    In his teaching the islands will put their hope.’
5  This is what God the LORD says –
the Creator of the heavens, who stretches them out,
    who spreads out the earth with all that springs from it,
    who gives breath to its people,
    and life to those who walk on it:
6  ‘I, the LORD, have called you in righteousness;
    I will take hold of your hand.
I will keep you and will make you
    to be a covenant for the people
    and a light for the Gentiles,
7  to open eyes that are blind,
    to free captives from prison
    and to release from the dungeon those who sit in darkness.
8  ‘I am the LORD; that is my name!
    I will not yield my glory to another
    or my praise to idols.
9  See, the former things have taken place,
    and new things I declare;
before they spring into being
    I announce them to you.’

17:43 - 23:01 - ALL AGE TALK – Who is the servant?
The identity of the &quot;servant&quot; in Isaiah 42.
Initial understanding is that the servant is Jesus.
Uncertainty about the true identity of the servant.
The servant could be the nation of Israel.
The servant could be Jacob, whose nickname was Israel.
Isaiah wrote this passage before Jesus' birth.


24:29 -  25:28 - READING 2 – Matthew 3:13-17 NIVUK read by Lesley Bogart
13  Then Jesus came from Galilee to the Jordan to be baptised by
John.  14  But John tried to deter him, saying, ‘I need to be baptised by you,
and do you come to me?’
15  Jesus replied, ‘Let it be so now; it is proper for us to do this to fulfil all
righteousness.’ Then John consented.
16  As soon as Jesus was baptised, he went up out of the water. At that
moment heaven was opened, and he saw the Spirit of God descending
like a dove and alighting on him.  17  And a voice from heaven said, ‘This is
my Son, whom I love; with him I am well pleased.’

26:42 - 30:36 - Hymn - R&amp;S 195 I am the Lord of the dance

30:51 - 42:49 - SERMON – Baptism
Similarities between statements in Isaiah and Matthew.
Both passages begin with God declaring that the servant is his chosen one and in whom he delights or is well pleased.
In Isaiah, the servant may be referring to the audience and others in a plural sense.
The servant in Isaiah is described as humble and not war-like.
Reflect on how they can embody this servant-like humility in their own lives.
Both passages in Isaiah and Matthew launch mission for people.
Isaiah 42:2 tells us that the servant will not shout or lift up their head.
We should reflect on our own humility and how it relates to the servant in Isaiah.

43:03 -  WE MAKE OUR RESPONSE

43:23 - 46:08 - Hymn - TP 13 Be still, for the presence of the Lord.

46:18 - DEDICATION of our OFFERINGS
47:18 - PRAYERS of intercession

WE GO OUT TO SERVE

52:04 - 55:13 - Hymn - R&amp;S 187 Worship the Lord in the beauty of holiness.

55:16 - 55:35 - Blessing

56:24 - 57:58 - Organ voluntary

#Church #Worship #Sing #Organ #Faithful #Jesus #URC #UnitedReformedChurch  #Blessings #GoodNews #NIV #NIVUK #Bible #Lessons #King #GoodNews #Choir   #AllAreWelcome #JoinIn #Epiphany #Christian #WarmSpace #WednesdayCafe</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="8"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:acIo9TsC5qA</id>
  <yt:videoId>acIo9TsC5qA</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>New Year Worship (Audio Only) - Sunday 1st January 2023</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=acIo9TsC5qA"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2023-01-01T11:48:39+00:00</published>
  <updated>2023-01-21T23:47:35+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>New Year Worship (Audio Only) - Sunday 1st January 2023</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/acIo9TsC5qA?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/acIo9TsC5qA/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00:00 - Opening music, photos, and notices

06:45 - Call to worship
Jesus said, A new commandment I give to you that you love one
another as I have loved you.
We bring our worship, seeking that love to share.
Paul wrote, if anyone is in Christ, the new creation has come: the
old has gone, the new is here!
We bring our worship at the beginning of this new year.
Not looking back, but always moving forwards:
We bring our worship to you, the God of new life.

08:39 - Hymn - 159 Hark the herald angels sing

11:37 - Prayer of adoration and confession

13:42 - Introduction: What’s the time?
Second Sunday of Christmas, 8th day of Christmas
American Samoa and Western Samoa timezones
Saint Jerome and his view on the relationship between Sunday and the &quot;son of God&quot;
The symbolism of eight maids of milking being given as a gift.


20:00 - Lighting the Christmas Candle

22:10 - 24:02 - Reading: Ecclesiastes 3.1-13 NIVUK read by Kitty Bird
3 There is a time for everything,
    and a season for every activity under the heavens:
2          a time to be born and a time to die,
    a time to plant and a time to uproot,
3      a time to kill and a time to heal,
    a time to tear down and a time to build,
4      a time to weep and a time to laugh,
    a time to mourn and a time to dance,
5      a time to scatter stones and a time to gather them,

    a time to embrace and a time to refrain from embracing,
6      a time to search and a time to give up,
    a time to keep and a time to throw away,
7      a time to tear and a time to mend,
    a time to be silent and a time to speak,
8      a time to love and a time to hate,
    a time for war and a time for peace.

27:28 - Hymn - 188 Born in the night, Mary’s child

26:35 - 28:43 - Reading: Revelation 21.1-6a NIVUK read by Rosemary Taylor
21 Then I saw ‘a new heaven and a new earth,’ for the first heaven
and the first earth had passed away, and there was no longer any
sea.  2  I saw the Holy City, the new Jerusalem, coming down out of
heaven from God, prepared as a bride beautifully dressed for her
husband.  3  And I heard a loud voice from the throne saying, ‘Look!
God’s dwelling-place is now among the people, and he will dwell
with them. They will be his people, and God himself will be with
them and be their God.  4  “He will wipe every tear from their eyes.
There will be no more death” or mourning or crying or pain, for
the old order of things has passed away.’
5  He who was seated on the throne said, ‘I am making everything
new!’
6  He said to me: ‘It is done. I am the Alpha and the Omega, the
Beginning and the End.

29:19 - 40:21 - Short Address: ‘God makes new’
How people have celebrated the start of the new year.
A message from a daughter who chose to go to bed instead of celebrating the new year.
The chaotic nature of recent years and the hope for a better 2023.
People's attitudes towards time can vary based on their mood, age and circumstances.
An inscription on an old clock at a Cathedral in Chester that speaks about how time slips away as a person ages.
Ancient Greek language has two words for time, Chronos, which is chronological time and Kairos which is the special moments that stand out.
Ecclesiastes, a philosopher, who talks about the flow and ebb of time and the choices one must make during different times.
The choices one must make during different times

40:55 - Hymn - 685 vs 1 – 3 sung seated to begin our prayers

42:46 - 46:35 - Prayer for the world

47:08 - Prayer of Dedication at the beginning of this new year

47:50 - Communion: we invite you to share in the bread and wine at
church (or at home) united in the name of Christ.

48:18 - Hymn - 63 Great God, we sing that mighty hand

51:10 - A Prayer of thanksgiving with the response
We thank you Lord of life And praise your holy name

Lord’s Prayer

Closing Prayer

01:02:20 - Hymn 603 Lord for the years

01:06:01 - 01:06:34 - Blessing

01:07:04 - 01:09:14 - Organ voluntary

#Church #CarolConcert #Worship #Advent #Sing #Organ #HarkTheHerald #SilentNight #Faithful #Jesus #URC #UnitedReformedChurch #Christmas #Blessings #BleakMidwinter #CalypsoCarol #InfantHoly #GoodNews #NIV #NIVUK #Bible #Lessons #Carols #King #NewKing #GoodNews #Tidings #CarolSinging #Choir   #AllAreWelcome #JoinIn 
#JoyToTheWorld</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="22"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:oRtSD2cPnDo</id>
  <yt:videoId>oRtSD2cPnDo</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Christmas Morning Worship - Sunday 25th December 2022</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oRtSD2cPnDo"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-12-25T10:59:48+00:00</published>
  <updated>2023-03-09T03:42:26+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Christmas Morning Worship - Sunday 25th December 2022</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/oRtSD2cPnDo?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/oRtSD2cPnDo/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00:00 - Opening music, photos, and notices

17:15 - Welcome to our Christmas service

18:30 - 21:22 - Carol to prepare for worship: 155 While shepherds watched their flocks

21:25 - Welcome and introduction (including lighting of peace candle)

22:45 - Call to worship (words from Isaiah 9)
A child is born to us! A son is given to us! And he will be our ruler;
and will be called, Wonderful Counsellor,
The Almighty, the Everlasting, Prince of peace.
All: We come to worship Jesus Christ,
born in Bethlehem, Light of the world,
King of love and Lord of life.

23:30 - 27:19 - Hymn 160 - O come all ye faithful (omit verses 3 and 4)

27:20 - 29:54 - Part 1 Celebrating the Light

Lighting the Advent Candles
We light each candle to remember those who played their part
preparing the way for Jesus, Emmanuel, God with us; and we light
the central candle to celebrate his birth and life and touch on our
lives:
All: Lord Jesus, light of the world,
be with us in all our celebrations this day.
Bring your love, hope and peace to our broken world,
that all creation may learn the song of the angels:
Glory to God in the highest and peace on earth. Amen.

30:24 - 31:05 - Song (tune Frere Jacques - unaccompanied)
Christ our light, Christ our light,
Light our lives, light our lives.
We’ll be lights to others; we’ll be lights to others
Light our lives, light our lives.

31:13 - Part 2: ‘opening the gift’

36:04 - 37:53 - Hymn 167 Once in Royal David’s city vs 1 and 2

37:56 - Part 3: Telling the story

42:06 - 43:58 - Hymn 167 Once in Royal David’s city vs 3 and 4

44:36 - 45:45 - Reading: John 1.1 – 5, 9 – 14 NIVUK read by Julia Sparks

45:54 - 48:39 - Part 4: Knowing the meaning

48:54 - 49:25 - Reading: ‘God came in person!’ read by Linda Curley

50:20 - 54:36 - Hymn 162 - In the bleak mid winter

54:43 - 58:27 - Part 5 - Praying for the world and ourselves
Today we thank you, God of new life, for the child born in Bethlehem long
ago, whose life continues to inspire and challenge and comfort us today.
Help us to know his presence and share his peace…
Lord of all life, hear our prayer.
We pray for children born today and for their families, for midwives in their
care; and we lift to you families where there is sadness or hurt...
Lord of all life, hear our prayer.
Today we pray for peace, peace in places where there is violence and war,
anger and fear...
Lord of all life, hear our prayer.
We pray for travellers... those who have travelled home for Christmas, those
travelling today, those seeking a new place to call home…
Lord of all life, hear our prayer.
We pray for all who are sick, and those who care for them – at home or in
hospital. We remember those who have died, those we miss at the table
and thank you, God of eternal life, for each of them in their uniqueness…
Lord of all life, hear our prayer.
And we pray for ourselves, for our needs, our hopes and fears, our joys and
dreams for the future. Lead us Lord, in your way of generous love…
Lord of all life, hear our prayer.
God of new life, hear our prayers, spoken and silent, and unite us with all
celebrating the birth of Jesus, as we pray the prayer he gave us:
Lord’s Prayer

59:17 - 01:01:51 - Hymn 164 - Go tell it on the mountain

01:01:54 - 01:02:20 - Blessing
Let us go in the peace and joy of Jesus Christ
To share his love with all this Christmas Day
And the grace of our Lord Jesus Christ, the love of God and the fellowship
of the Holy Spirit be with us and all creation, now and always. Amen.

01:02:31 - 01:05:46 - Organ voluntary

#Church #CarolConcert #Worship #Advent #Sing #Organ #HarkTheHerald #SilentNight #Faithful #Jesus #URC #UnitedReformedChurch #Christmas #Blessings #BleakMidwinter #CalypsoCarol #InfantHoly #GoodNews #NIV #NIVUK #Bible #Lessons #Carols #King #NewKing #GoodNews #Tidings #CarolSinging #Choir #BassGuitar #Drums #AllAreWelcome #JoinIn 
#JoyToTheWorld</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="19"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:XtTl9IJttvU</id>
  <yt:videoId>XtTl9IJttvU</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Carol Service - Sunday 18th December 2022</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XtTl9IJttvU"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-12-18T17:15:20+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-12-20T11:54:23+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Carol Service - Sunday 18th December 2022</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/XtTl9IJttvU?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/XtTl9IJttvU/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00:00 - Opening music, photos, and notices

10:18 - Welcome

13:18 - 18:14 - Carol: O come all ye faithful [on screen or R&amp;S 160 vs 1 – 5]

18:19 - Lighting of the Advent Candles and Opening Prayer

22:21 - 24:07 - Song: Longing for light (MP 1201 vs 1 and 2)

24:17 - 1 st Bible Reading: Isaiah 9 verses 2, 6 and 7 Arthur Winning

25:10 - 29:05 - Carol: It came upon a midnight clear [on screen or R&amp;S 144]

29:09 - 2 nd Bible Reading: Luke 1: 26 – 38 Lesley Bogart

31:01 - 34:52 - Carol: O little town of Bethlehem [on screen or R&amp;S 144]

35:04 - 3 rd Bible Reading: Luke 2: 1–7 (Good News) Samuel Evans

36:31 - 38:43 - Carol: See him lying on a bed of straw [on screen or R&amp;S 151]

39:04 - 4 th Bible Reading: Luke 2: 8 – 20 Richard Harding

40:30 - 43:05 - Carol: Silent night [on screen or R&amp;S 147]

43:17 - Reading: For him all stars have shone Rebekah / Matthew Sparks

42:41 - 46:20 - Carol: Come and join the celebration [on screen or R&amp;S 166]

46:30 5 th Bible Reading: Matthew 2: 1 – 12 Alan Yates (black screen for first part)

48:40 - 50:31 - Carol: Infant holy [on screen or R&amp;S 149]

50:43 - Reading: Gifts of the wise Rebekah / Matthew Sparks

51:37 - Introducing our Christmas charities: donations will be shared between
One Can, Wycombe Homeless Connection, Wycombe Refugee
Partnership – working in our community and Commitment for Life –
supporting projects in Israel and occupied Palestinian territories.

58:56 - Worship Song ‘Christmas blessing’ by Sam Hargreaves https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-RrCdTdr91M

01:01:40 - Prayers of intercession

01:04:47 - Lord’s Prayer

01:06:00 - 01:09:26 - Carol: Hark! the herald angels sing [on screen or R&amp;S 159]

01:09:27 - 01:09:51 - Blessing

01:10:11 - 01:17:10 - Organ voluntary

#Church #CarolConcert #Worship #Advent #Sing #Organ #HarkTheHerald #SilentNight #Faithful #Jesus #URC #UnitedReformedChurch #Christmas #Blessings #BleakMidwinter #CalypsoCarol #InfantHoly #GoodNews #NIV #NIVUK #Bible #Lessons #Carols #King #NewKing #GoodNews #Tidings #CarolSinging #Choir #BassGuitar #Drums #AllAreWelcome #JoinIn 
@onecantrust4907 @wycombehomelessconnection7371</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="32"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:eFtyfvc8ap4</id>
  <yt:videoId>eFtyfvc8ap4</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship - Sunday 18th December 2022</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eFtyfvc8ap4"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-12-18T11:54:59+00:00</published>
  <updated>2023-01-03T22:54:59+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship - Sunday 18th December 2022</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/eFtyfvc8ap4?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/eFtyfvc8ap4/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00:00 - Opening music, photos, and notices

10:14 - Welcome and lighting of peace candle 
12:20 - Call to worship
God of creation, God of history:
God is here with us.
God of mystery, God of blessing:
God is here with us.
God in Jesus, God named Emmanuel:
God is here with us.

13:08 - 15:44 - Hymn - Joy to the world, the Lord is come (R&amp;S 135)

15:52 - Opening Prayers and Lord’s Prayer

18:29 - 27:27 - Introduction: Nativity now – what part would you play?
The recent Brownie sleepover on the nice warm floor
Nativity - what part would you want?
Shepherd, Mary, Joseph, and animal, an angel?  An alien, a lobster?
A snowman?
What part would you play?
A rat?  The least significant but still with a part?
Do we ever feel unloved?  We are still welcomed by Jesus
What part do we play in the Christmas story?

27:39 - 30:30 - Carol - The angel Gabriel (R&amp;amp;S 139)

30:43 - Lighting the Advent candles
As we light the last candle before Christmas Day,
we give thanks for the role Mary and Joseph played in God’s
unfolding plan and pray:
God of all our lives, you call each of us to play a part in your story
and purposes for the world. As we give thanks for the courage
and the humility of Mary and Joseph, may shine your light into
the lives of others.
Draw us all to the Christmas stable, where hope is born and all
are loved, in Jesus’ name. Amen.

33:48 - 34:53 - Reading: Isaiah 7.10 – 16 GNB 

36:13 - 39:21 - Song -  Emmanuel, Emmanuel (MP 121) sung three times
Emmanuel, Emmanuel, His name is called Emmanuel
God with us, revealed in us – His name is called Emmanuel

40:01 - Find Mary…find Joseph (carols R&amp;amp;S 144 – 181)

44:55 - 46:24 - Matthew 1. 18 – 25 NIVUK

47:03 - 51:24 - Carol Joseph, son of David (Tune R&amp;amp;S 243 Noel nouvelet)
1. Joseph, son of David, son of Abraham;
regally descended, son of tent and psalm;
waited the day when, filled with joy and pride,
he would marry Mary, she would be his bride.

2. Joseph, though a poor man, with no wealth or fame,
yet possessed a treasure in his fam’ly name.
He must pass on this honour to his son,
in the line of David – then his job was done!

3. Yet, before the wedding, Mary was with child
and there was no father; ev’ryone went wild!
What could he do, to keep his name intact?
Mary must be banished! Surely he must act!

4. Calmly, at God’s prompting, Joseph held his ground,
risking, trusting, waiting; Mary still around.
Somehow he knew, though how he could not tell,
God would act through Jesus, all would then be well.

5. Showing such devotion, Joseph stood in line
with ancestral women working God’s design:
Rahab, and Tamar, Bathsheba and Ruth –
each, when others faltered, stood for hope and truth.

6. Now the gift of Joseph – ancestry and name –
graciously surrendered, nevermore the same;
offered to Jesus, ’til God’s work is done,
welcomes all the nations, seeks to make us one.
© John Campbell (based on Matthew 1)

52:14 - Short prayer

52:32 - 01:03:42 - Short Talk
Gathering this afternoon for the carol service
Keeping quiet about the score for the #WorldCupFinal
Focus on Emmanuel, Christ the light of the world
Other people playing their part around Jesus
Looking at Mary and Joseph
Mary does play a part in our carols but just Silent Night with Mary and Joseph looking on protectively
Joseph was older, not unusual at that time
Their son was unusual
Revealing God's immense, eternal love
Mary carried Jesus, Joseph protects them and takes them to Bethlehem to be registered
Telling the story of the birth
One word to take home - Emmanuel - God with us


01:03:54 - 01:06:09 - Song - Born in the night, Mary’s child (R&amp;S 188) sung seated

01:06:15 - Prayers for each other and the world

01:12:22 - 01:17:16 - Carol - See! In yonder manger low (R&amp;S 157)

01:17: 16 - 01:17:46 - Blessing

01:18:15 - 01:20:05 - Music, notices and photos

#Church #Worship #Advent  #AllAreWelcome #URC #UnitedReformedChurch #Hope #Isaiah #FourCandles #ForkHandles #Matthew #AllAreWelcome #URC #unitedreformedchurch</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="35"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:MBQLNs_bIYk</id>
  <yt:videoId>MBQLNs_bIYk</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship - Sunday 11th December 2022</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MBQLNs_bIYk"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-12-11T11:47:22+00:00</published>
  <updated>2023-03-14T09:17:02+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship - Sunday 11th December 2022</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/MBQLNs_bIYk?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/MBQLNs_bIYk/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00:00 - Opening music, photos, and notices

07:35 - Welcome and lighting of peace candle (Linda as duty elder)

08:32 - Introduction – Linda

09:50 - 13:40 - Carol: In the Bleak Mid-Winter (R&amp;S 162)

13:46 - Story Telling – Julia
What are you looking forward to most about Christmas
Dinner
Cousins
Grandchildren
Now think back to when you were a child?
Presents
Stocking
Which do you like best - giving or receiving
Why do we give presents?
Enjoyment, showing our love for one another, reminding us of the first Christmas present wrapped in strips of cloth
Jesus was the first and best
Remembering our friends, family and God at Christmas
We need to receive, unwrap, thank, enjoy, and share our presents and God's present of Jesus

17:47 - 19:00 - Reading: Luke 2. 4-12 (NIVUK) – Samuel
4  So Joseph also went up from the town of Nazareth in Galilee to
Judea, to Bethlehem the town of David, because he belonged to
the house and line of David.  5  He went there to register with Mary,
who was pledged to be married to him and was expecting a
child.  6  While they were there, the time came for the baby to be
born,  7  and she gave birth to her firstborn, a son. She wrapped him
in cloths and placed him in a manger, because there was no guest
room available for them.
8  And there were shepherds living out in the fields near by, keeping
watch over their flocks at night.  9  An angel of the Lord appeared to
them, and the glory of the Lord shone around them, and they
were terrified.  10  But the angel said to them, ‘Do not be afraid. I
bring you good news that will cause great joy for all the
people.  11  Today in the town of David a Saviour has been born to
you; he is the Messiah, the Lord.  12  This will be a sign to you: you
will find a baby wrapped in cloths and lying in a manger.’

19:14 - 23:17 - Carol - We Three Kings of Orient Are

23:33 - 24:37 - Reading: Matthew 2. 1-2, 9-12 (NIVUK)
After Jesus was born in Bethlehem in Judea, during the time of
King Herod, Magi from the east came to Jerusalem  2  and asked,
‘Where is the one who has been born king of the Jews? We saw
his star when it rose and have come to worship him.’
9  After they had heard the king, they went on their way, and the
star they had seen when it rose went ahead of them until it
stopped over the place where the child was.  10  When they saw the
star, they were overjoyed.  11  On coming to the house, they saw the
child with his mother Mary, and they bowed down and
worshipped him. Then they opened their treasures and presented
him with gifts of gold, frankincense and myrrh.  12  And having been
warned in a dream not to go back to Herod, they returned to their
country by another route.

24:46 - Lighting of the Advent Candle – Samuel

26:18 - 29:30 - Carol - Good King Wenceslas (verses 1-3, 5)

29:37 - Introduction to Activities
- Print wrapping paper) – Sarah
- Christmas Stocking – Sarah
- Story Teller – Linda
- Edible Baby – Julia
- Themed crossword for those sitting – Ellen
- At home – Ellen

58:58 - 01:01:34 - Carol -  Come and Join the Celebration (R&amp;amp;S 166)

01:01:40 - Prayers and Lord’s Prayer – Sarah

01:06:32 - 01:19:56 - Carol - Hark the Herald Angels Sing (R&amp;amp;S 159)

01:10:03 - 01:10:40 - Messy Grace – Linda

01:10:56 - Music, notices and photos

#Church #Worship #Advent  #AllAreWelcome #URC #UnitedReformedChurch #Hope #Isaiah #Paul #Romans</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="25"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
</feed>
