<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns:yt="http://www.youtube.com/xml/schemas/2015" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 <link rel="self" href="http://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=PLrggWHcy3azrunmSfTCSlS5JRuB4zTgCY"/>
 <id>yt:playlist:PLrggWHcy3azrunmSfTCSlS5JRuB4zTgCY</id>
 <yt:playlistId>PLrggWHcy3azrunmSfTCSlS5JRuB4zTgCY</yt:playlistId>
 <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
 <title>Worship services - Trinity and Cores End URCs</title>
 <author>
  <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
  <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
 </author>
 <published>2020-04-04T11:11:34+00:00</published>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:ya4ZYEHXa2k</id>
  <yt:videoId>ya4ZYEHXa2k</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 16th January 2022</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ya4ZYEHXa2k"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-01-16T11:48:53+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-01-16T12:05:35+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 16th January 2022</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/ya4ZYEHXa2k?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/ya4ZYEHXa2k/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00.00  Photos and music before service
Welcome and lighting of peace candle (an elder)

Call to worship (based on Isaiah 60)
We are met in the presence of God;
and we do not meet alone.
With the Church throughout the world,
we gather to worship the Lord.
In Cathedrals, tin tabernacles and fields,
God’ holy name is praised. 
And here with our hearts and our voices,
God’ holy name is praised. 
We are met in the presence of God;
and we do not meet alone.

HYMN R&amp;S 293  Ye servants of God

Prayers of adoration and confession 
Lord’s Prayer 

Introduction: ‘Jesus revealed’

Reading: John 2. 1 – 11 read by Elsje 
2 On the third day a wedding took place at Cana in Galilee. Jesus’ mother was there, 2 and Jesus and his disciples had also been invited to the wedding. 3 When the wine was gone, Jesus’ mother said to him, ‘They have no more wine.’
4 ‘Woman, why do you involve me?’ Jesus replied. ‘My hour has not yet come.’
5 His mother said to the servants, ‘Do whatever he tells you.’
6 Nearby stood six stone water jars, the kind used by the Jews for ceremonial washing, each holding from eighty to a hundred and twenty litres.  7 Jesus said to the servants, ‘Fill the jars with water’; so they filled them to the brim.  8 Then he told them, ‘Now draw some out and take it to the master of the banquet.’
They did so, 9 and the master of the banquet tasted the water that had been turned into wine. He did not realise where it had come from, though the servants who had drawn the water knew. Then he called the bridegroom aside 10 and said, ‘Everyone brings out the choice wine first and then the cheaper wine after the guests have had too much to drink; but you have saved the best till now.’
11 What Jesus did here in Cana of Galilee was the first of the signs through which he revealed his glory; and his disciples believed in him.

Prayer
When a daffodil or the first snowdrop comes into bloom:
We catch a glimpse of God in the ordinary.
When the sun is rising, or the sun is setting:
We catch a glimpse of God in the ordinary.
When a baby is born, or a chick is hatched:
We catch a glimpse of God in the ordinary.
When we feel the warm embrace of a family hug:
We catch a glimpse of God in the ordinary.
When we come to worship or offer a prayer:
We catch a glimpse of God in the ordinary.
Transforming God, wherever we are, whatever we do,
whether we are at home, work or school,
help us to see the miracle in the ordinary,
and to catch a glimpse of your glory in our midst.  
Amen.

WORSHIP SONGS
Jesus put this song into our hearts
Jesus stand among us

Introduction to the reading – ‘different but one’ – containers

Reading: 1 Corinthians 12.1-11 read by Tony 
12 Now about the gifts of the Spirit, brothers and sisters, I do not want you to be uninformed. 2 You know that when you were pagans, somehow or other you were influenced and led astray to dumb idols. 3 Therefore I want you to know that no one who is speaking by the Spirit of God says, ‘Jesus be cursed,’ and no one can say, ‘Jesus is Lord,’ except by the Holy Spirit.
4 There are different kinds of gifts, but the same Spirit distributes them. 5 There are different kinds of service, but the same Lord. 6 There are different kinds of working, but in all of them and in everyone it is the same God at work.
7 Now to each one the manifestation of the Spirit is given for the common good. 8 To one there is given through the Spirit a message of wisdom, to another a message of knowledge by means of the same Spirit, 9 to another faith by the same Spirit, to another gifts of healing by that one Spirit, 10 to another miraculous powers, to another prophecy, to another distinguishing between spirits, to another speaking in different kinds of tongues,[a] and to still another the interpretation of tongues.  11 All these are the work of one and the same Spirit, and he distributes them to each one, just as he determines.

SONG TP 61  Lord of the church  TUNE: Londonderry Air  

Address 

SONG TP 81 Spirit of God (chorus, vs 1 and chorus sung seated)

Prayers for the church and the world with the response
Loving Spirit: work among your people.

SONG TP 81 Spirit of God (chorus, vs 2 and chorus sung seated)

Offering Prayer 

HYMN R&amp;S 471  Bless and keep us, Lord

 - Closing blessing

 - Music after the service</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="27"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:7O9r3-iQJ04</id>
  <yt:videoId>7O9r3-iQJ04</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 9th January 2022</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7O9r3-iQJ04"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-01-09T12:03:46+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-01-12T08:40:33+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 9th January 2022</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/7O9r3-iQJ04?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/7O9r3-iQJ04/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00.00  Photos and music before service
16:37 - Welcome 
18:00 - Lighting of peace candle (an elder)

20:00 - Call to worship: Isaiah 43:1-3a
 But now thus says the Lord, 
 he who created you, O Jacob,
 he who formed you, O Israel:
 Do not fear, for I have redeemed you;
 I have called you by name, you are mine.
 When you pass through the waters, I will be with you;
 and through the rivers, they shall not overwhelm you;
 when you walk through fire you shall not be burned,
 and the flame shall not consume you.
 For I am the Lord your God,
 the Holy One of Israel, your Saviour.


21:07 - Hymn: R&amp;S 589  How firm a foundation

24:43 - Opening Prayers and the Lord’s Prayer

27:45 - 36:12 - Talk for all ages :  Life changing moments
How are you feeling this morning?  We all have ups and downs over time.
Sometimes we need things to lift us
Do you agree or disagree on these things that might lift you:
A good meal? A bar of chocolate? A run? A bottle of water?
Being with family
Pets
All of these things can lift us but they aren't permanent answers. We need something deeper to give us a boost when life changes direction.
Speaking to God and Him speaking to us
Looking at moments in Jesus' life - his baptism when God recognised him and sent him on into his ministry
Moments in his life when God speaks

36:44 - Worship songs 
R&amp;S 308/309 Spirit of the Living God
MP 465  Meekness and Majesty

44:13 - Blessing as Junior Church go to their activities:
 Adults: May the Lord be with you
 Junior Church: And also with you
 All: Amen

44:25 - Introduction to Bible readings

45:55 - Reading: Luke 3: 15-22   read by John Hillson
15 The people were waiting expectantly and were all wondering in their hearts if John might possibly be the Messiah. 16 John answered them all, ‘I baptise you with[b] water. But one who is more powerful than I will come, the straps of whose sandals I am not worthy to untie. He will baptise you with[c] the Holy Spirit and fire. 17 His winnowing fork is in his hand to clear his threshing-floor and to gather the wheat into his barn, but he will burn up the chaff with unquenchable fire.’ 18 And with many other words John exhorted the people and proclaimed the good news to them.
19 But when John rebuked Herod the tetrarch because of his marriage to Herodias, his brother’s wife, and all the other evil things he had done, 20 Herod added this to them all: he locked John up in prison.
21 When all the people were being baptised, Jesus was baptised too. And as he was praying, heaven was opened 22 and the Holy Spirit descended on him in bodily form like a dove. And a voice came from heaven: ‘You are my Son, whom I love; with you I am well pleased.’



48:20 - Reading: Acts 8: 14-17  read by Sue Thorne
14 When the apostles in Jerusalem heard that Samaria had accepted the word of God, they sent Peter and John to Samaria. 15 When they arrived, they prayed for the new believers there that they might receive the Holy Spirit, 16 because the Holy Spirit had not yet come on any of them; they had simply been baptised in the name of the Lord Jesus. 17 Then Peter and John placed their hands on them, and they received the Holy Spirit.

49:22 - Hymn:  R&amp;S 180  Before the world began


52:56 - 01:12:34 - Sermon:  We are loved 
We have God's affirmation of Christ at his baptism.
It's in all 4 gospels, two of which start with this story
John and Jesus were cousins, John just a few months older who as a young man went to live in the wilderness in very harsh conditions
John was preparing people for Jesus
The bible never suggests Jesus baptises with water, always with the laying on of hands
It always sounds simple - Jesus arrives, asks to be baptised, John is reluctant but agrees, performs the act, the spirit comes down.
Why did God choose this moment to speak
It contains much of the mystery and wonder of God
Why did Jesus need to be baptised?
Glimpses of hope and love all around us
We need to trust and look for God to find strength

Unconditional love
Archbishop Desmond Tutu speaking about respect and love for all

01:13:10 - Hymn:  R&amp;S 413  What a friend we have in Jesus

01:16:30 - 01:22:05 - Prayers for others and ourselves
Response:  Loving Lord,  we lift our prayers to you

01:22:08 - Hymn: R&amp;S 285  O for a thousand tongues to sing                       

01:25:54 - 01:26:12 - Closing blessing

01:26:48 - 01:33:46 - Music after the service</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="25"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:nQ9L2I11XRY</id>
  <yt:videoId>nQ9L2I11XRY</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Worship - Sunday, 2nd January 2022</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nQ9L2I11XRY"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-01-02T11:44:15+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-01-14T08:48:36+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Worship - Sunday, 2nd January 2022</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/nQ9L2I11XRY?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/nQ9L2I11XRY/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Service led by Rev Terry Hinks 
Organist Andrew Winton

00.00  - Photos and music before service
08:40 - Welcome and lighting of peace candle (an elder)
12:08 - Call to worship (based on Isaiah 60)

13:08 - Song R&amp;S 188  Born in the night

15:22 - Prayer of adoration and confession from Iona with responses:
Lord have mercy Lord have mercy
Christ have mercy Christ have mercy
Lord have mercy Lord have mercy

I believe that God forgives and sets us free
We believe that God forgives and sets us free
And at the day’s beginning we commit ourselves 
to following where Christ calls and loving as he loves us.  Amen

18:27 - 23:50 - Introduction: Not over yet!
How many of you have taken down your Christmas decorations?
Anyone who didn't put up any decorations at all?
We take some down but keep the rest up until Epiphany
Some churches don't bring out the wise men in the nativity scene until Epiphany
Today is the 9th day of Christmas - 9 ladies dancing
According to some, each of the gifts represents a Christian truth.  Some believe this to be related to the 9 fruits of the spirit - Love, Joy, Peace, Patience, Kindness, Goodness, Faithfulness, Gentleness, and Self-control
Starting anew, for ourselves and our world

23:52 - Reading: Matthew 2: 1 – 12 NIVUK 
27:32 - 29:06 - Poem ‘Don’t wait for an angel’ 

29:10 - Hymn 185 - Wise men seeking Jesus

33:02 - Reading: John 1. 10-18 NIVUK 

35:15 - Short Address 
Has anyone pulled a cracker this year? What local newspaper did Charles Dickens work on before he became famous?  Bicester Times and Worcester Times.
It was the best of times, it was the worst of times, it was the age of wisdom, it was the age of foolishness, it was the epoch of belief, it was the epoch of incredulity, it was the season of light, it was the season of darkness, it was the spring of hope, it was the winter of despair.
Set in the time of the French revolution with all its hopes and brutality and horrors
A time of enlightenment, rationality, revival, and John and Charles Wesley
We see all of these things, into this world comes the great affirmation of John's Gospel
Donald Rumsfeld and his unknown unknowns
&quot;Reports that say that something hasn't happened are always interesting to me, because as we know, there are known knowns; there are things we know we know. We also know there are known unknowns; that is to say we know there are some things we do not know. But there are also unknown unknowns—the ones we don't know we don't know. And if one looks throughout the history of our country and other free countries, it is the latter category that tends to be the difficult ones.&quot;
Today there are many people who don't know God but they also don't know that they don't know Him.  Not a judgement, merely a statement of many people in the western world

Hymn 395 - No one has ever seen God 
Time for quiet reflection and prayers for the world 

Offering the gifts of this last year and our lives for God’s work ahead – please stand for the Prayer of Dedication
Eternal God we come to you now 
 to offer the praise of our lips 
 and the service of our lives.
 We recommit ourselves 
 to walk the way of Jesus, 
 to seek your will for our lives and for our world.
 Unite us as one body in Christ, renew us by your Spirit, 
 that we may be true channels of your love and peace,
 through Jesus Christ our Saviour and Friend.  Amen.

Communion: we invite you to share in the bread and wine at church (or at home) united in the name of Christ.

SONG Jesu be the centre MP 1076 (sing vs 1 again at end)

A Prayer of thanksgiving with the response
We thank you Lord of life And praise your holy name
Lord’s Prayer 

Closing Prayer

SONG 603  Lord for the years

Blessing

Organ Music</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="43"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:i1kSlP8EYUo</id>
  <yt:videoId>i1kSlP8EYUo</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 26th December 2021 - Boxing Day</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=i1kSlP8EYUo"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2021-12-26T09:45:01+00:00</published>
  <updated>2021-12-26T09:45:01+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 26th December 2021 - Boxing Day</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/i1kSlP8EYUo?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/i1kSlP8EYUo/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Welcome to our Boxing Day service.  You can use the links below to skip to other parts of the service


00:00 - Music before worship and photos

18:04 - Welcome and Prayer

19:09 - Carol - Infant holy Engage worship

21:32 - Introduction…
….One boxing day a couple of years ago, I shut down the computer, ignored all my unread books and set up a lego railway set in the study – this was the result


23:02 - ….One of the carols linked to today is Good King Wenceslas – which takes up that theme of compassion and service.  It’s a great carol to sing outside on a frosty day.  It ends with the words
Therefore, Christian folk, be sure
Wealth or rank possessing
You who now will bless the poor
Shall yourselves find blessing.
26:31 - Carol - Good King Wenceslas (Official Music Video) 

29:14 - Intro to reading

32:09 - Reading: Colossians 3:12-17 The Message 

33:36 - Prayer
Lord’s Prayer
36:44 - 37:11 - Blessing

37:15 - Hymn - From heaven you came
42:03 - Carols from the RGS Carol Concert - Choir and Brass Ensemble from All  Saints Church, recorded on 14th December 2020.  https://www.rgshw.com/news/?pid=3&amp;nid=1&amp;storyid=228 with  grateful thanks 
42:03 - Once in Royal David’s City 
46:49 - Hark! The Herald Angels Sing 
50:12 - O Come, All Ye Faithful 
53:38 - O Little Town of Bethlehem 
56:47 - Unto us is Born a Son

#JoyToTheWorld
#BoxingDay
#OneCanTrust
#WycombeHomelessConnection
#RGSHW
#Christmas
#Lego
#SwitchOffTheTV
https://onecantrust.org.uk/
https://twitter.com/rgshw</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="28"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:1_KB-Tm9YnM</id>
  <yt:videoId>1_KB-Tm9YnM</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship - Saturday 25th December 2021 - Christmas Day</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1_KB-Tm9YnM"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2021-12-25T10:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2021-12-25T10:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship - Saturday 25th December 2021 - Christmas Day</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/1_KB-Tm9YnM?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/1_KB-Tm9YnM/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Welcome to our Christmas Day service.  You can use the links below to skip to other parts of the service

00:00 - Music before worship and photos

18:04 - Welcome / Introduction

19:45 - Hymn - O come all ye faithful Engage Worship Video

23:10 - Advent candles (film of Cores End)

23:52 - Prayer

Intro of video Unto us produced Christian Vision). It’s a modern-day account of the nativity, filmed and produced to be like a contemporary TV drama.  And after that we’ll hear the story from Luke’s Gospel – read by the Sparks family

26:02 - Video Unto Us

30:38 - 32:43 - Reading Luke 2. 1 – 20 

32:49 - Hymn - Once in Royal Engage worship Video

36:51 - Prayers
Lord’s Prayer

40:16 - 40:44 - Blessing

41:05 - Song - On Christmas Day Engage worship

45:50 - Carols from the RGS Carol Concert - Choir and Brass Ensemble from All  Saints Church, recorded on 14th December 2020.  https://www.rgshw.com/news/?pid=3&amp;nid=1&amp;storyid=228 with  grateful thanks 
45:50 -    Once in Royal David’s City 
53:58 -    Hark! The Herald Angels Sing 
53:59 -    O Come, All Ye Faithful 
57:15 -    O Little Town of Bethlehem 
01:00:33 -    Unto us is Born a Son

#Christmas
#JoyToTheWorld
#OneCanTrust
#RGSHW
#SwitchOffTheTV
#OpeningPresents
#WycombeHomelessConnection

https://twitter.com/rgshw
https://onecantrust.org.uk/</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="1" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="29"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:gl0IcgpVQh4</id>
  <yt:videoId>gl0IcgpVQh4</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Worship - Sunday, 19th  December 2021 - Carols with Candlelight</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gl0IcgpVQh4"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2021-12-19T17:18:39+00:00</published>
  <updated>2021-12-19T23:02:15+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Worship - Sunday, 19th  December 2021 - Carols with Candlelight</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/gl0IcgpVQh4?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/gl0IcgpVQh4/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00.00  Photos and music before service

Welcome given by a church elder, Angus Massie

Call to worship led by the minister, Terry Hinks

Carol: O come all ye faithful [on screen or R&amp;S 160 vs 1-5]

Lighting of the Advent Candles

Song: Christ our light (Tune: Frere Jacques unaccompanied)
Christ our light, Christ our light,
light our lives.
We’ll be lights to others.
Light our lives.
Prayer

1 st Bible Reading: Isaiah 40: 1 – 5 and 9 Ian Bogart

Carol: It came upon a midnight clear [on screen or R&amp;S 144]

2 nd Bible Reading: Luke 1: 26 – 38 Norma Garden

Worship Song ‘Adore’ by Chris Tomlin (video)

3 rd Bible Reading: Luke 2: 1–7 (Good News) Zion Ogbewe

Carol: See him lying on a bed of straw [on screen or R&amp;S 151]
led by Worship Group

Reading: ‘Mary looks into the eyes of Jesus’ Lesley Bogart

Carol: Silent night [on screen or R&amp;S 147]
Reading: ‘Silent night’ Elaysa Ogbewe

4 th Bible Reading: Luke 2: 8 – 20 Alan Yates

Reflection: ‘changed lives’

Worship Song ‘Emmanuel’ [on screen]

5 th Bible Reading: Matthew 2: 1 – 12 Richard Harding

Introducing our Christmas charity Embrace the Middle East (video)

Carol: In the bleak mid winter [on screen or R&amp;S 162]

Reading: ‘Holy Child’ Abigail Lokko

Prayers of intercession
Lord’s Prayer

All: Our Father, who art in heaven,
hallowed be thy name;
thy kingdom come; thy will be done;
on earth as it is in heaven.
Give us this day our daily bread.
And forgive us our trespasses,
as we forgive those who trespass against us.
And lead us not into temptation;
but deliver us from evil.
For thine is the kingdom,
the power, and the glory,
for ever and ever. Amen.

Carol: Hark! the herald angels sing [on screen or R&amp;S 159]

Minister: Blessing
All say: Amen.

Please stand as the Bible is taken out of church
Organ Voluntary: Organ Sonata No 1 - Alexandre Guilmant</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="47"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:eEshnx8Kjj0</id>
  <yt:videoId>eEshnx8Kjj0</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 12th  December 2021</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eEshnx8Kjj0"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2021-12-12T11:45:08+00:00</published>
  <updated>2021-12-17T08:50:42+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 12th  December 2021</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/eEshnx8Kjj0?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/eEshnx8Kjj0/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00.00  Photos and music before service

07:55 - Welcome and lighting of peace candle (an elder)
09:33 - Call to worship 
With hearts changed by love,
with lives shaped by grace,
with relationships braced by integrity,
and with the blessing of the Holy Spirit upon us,
come as you are and as you hope to be
to worship the Lord of Advent. Amen.

10:40 - Hymn R&amp;S 134 On Jordan’s Banks the Baptist’s cry Tune: 537 Winchester new

13:00 - Opening Prayers

16:15 - Theme Introduction
Joy - not much of it around at the moment?
What might we be joyful about?
Printer paper being available
It's warmer
The fact we can still gather in person
A great view on a run
Thinking about what we can do to make others happy
Sharing a meal
Listening

21:05 - 21:45 - Prayer

21:47 - Lighting three candles on Advent crown

Let all who take refuge in God rejoice;
let them ever sing for joy. 

The candles are lit.
Jesus is the light of the world. 
A light no darkness can ever put out.
Will we be able to celebrate with our families this Christmas

23:10 - Song R&amp;S 522 From heaven you came, helpless babe

28:26 - 29:27 - Reading: Philippians 4.4-7 read by Aurelia Awuku

4 Rejoice in the Lord always. I will say it again: rejoice! 5 Let your gentleness be evident to all. The Lord is near. 6 Do not be anxious about anything, but in every situation, by prayer and petition, with thanksgiving, present your requests to God. 7 And the peace of God, which transcends all understanding, will guard your hearts and your minds in Christ Jesus.

30:15 - Song R&amp;S 286 Rejoice in the Lord always (as a round)

33:26 - 36:01 - Reading:  Luke 3.7-18 read by Alan Yates

7 John said to the crowds coming out to be baptised by him, ‘You brood of vipers! Who warned you to flee from the coming wrath? 8 Produce fruit in keeping with repentance. And do not begin to say to yourselves, “We have Abraham as our father.” For I tell you that out of these stones God can raise up children for Abraham. 9 The axe has been laid to the root of the trees, and every tree that does not produce good fruit will be cut down and thrown into the fire.’
10 ‘What should we do then?’ the crowd asked.
11 John answered, ‘Anyone who has two shirts should share with the one who has none, and anyone who has food should do the same.’
12 Even tax collectors came to be baptised. ‘Teacher,’ they asked, ‘what should we do?’
13 ‘Don’t collect any more than you are required to,’ he told them.
14 Then some soldiers asked him, ‘And what should we do?’

He replied, ‘Don’t extort money and don’t accuse people falsely – be content with your pay.’
15 The people were waiting expectantly and were all wondering in their hearts if John might possibly be the Messiah. 16 John answered them all, ‘I baptise you with[b] water. But one who is more powerful than I will come, the straps of whose sandals I am not worthy to untie. He will baptise you with[c] the Holy Spirit and fire. 17 His winnowing fork is in his hand to clear his threshing-floor and to gather the wheat into his barn, but he will burn up the chaff with unquenchable fire.’ 18 And with many other words John exhorted the people and proclaimed the good news to them.

37:07 - Hymn R&amp;S 200 The kingdom of God Tune: (ii) Out Skerries

38:47 - 56:50 - Sermon What then should we do?
Here we are this morning hopefully alive and well.
Recent news of the meteor the size of the Eiffel tower skimming past the earth
Context is important though as it passed 2.4 million miles away
The gospel reading leaves us with an image of the sandwich board stating &quot;The end is nigh&quot;
If that's good news, what does bad news look like
Repentance is the foundation of the new kingdom
He who is faithful and just will forgive us of our sins
Repentance is about building a better world
Government parties around Christmas 2020 whilst the rest of the country was under restrictions
Saying sorry and resigning does show a level of repentance
When we get it wrong we need to hold up our hands and say sorry
Just saying sorry isn't the same as repentance
&quot;Turn around where possible&quot; from our sat-nav when we make a mistake

56:52 - Hymn MP 806 Beauty for brokenness

01:03:04 - Prayers of Intercession
Closing Prayers 

01:08:43 - Hymn R&amp;S 574 Go forth and tell Tune: 740 Woodlands

01:11:30 - 01:12:09 - Blessing

01:12:40 - 01:15:30 - Organ voluntary</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="26"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:G1cGNCqZQYI</id>
  <yt:videoId>G1cGNCqZQYI</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 5th  December 2021</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=G1cGNCqZQYI"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2021-12-05T11:48:29+00:00</published>
  <updated>2021-12-10T07:59:19+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 5th  December 2021</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/G1cGNCqZQYI?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/G1cGNCqZQYI/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00.00  Photos and music before service

07:30 - Welcome and lighting of peace candle 

09:33 - Call to worship
Minister: In our watching and waiting:
All: Come, Lord Jesus.
Minister: In our hopes and fears:
All: Come, Lord Jesus.
Minister: In our stillness and worship:
All: Come, Lord Jesus.
Minister: Come, Lord Jesus, bless and surprise us
as we look forward to the celebration of your birth.

10:00 - Hymn 141 Make way, make way

13:06 - Opening Prayers

15:45 18:45 - Introduction: ‘Clear the way’
When cars were first introduced in this country, red flags were required to be carried in advance to clear the way and make sure all was safe
Clearing the way is a theme in Advent thinking about John the Baptist clearing the way for Jesus
John was a strange challenging figure
Looking at my bookshelf makes me thing I could do with clearing it somewhat
When they introduce John, the gospel writers use words from Isaiah


18:55 - Lighting two candles on Advent crown
Reader: We light our first candle, as a sign of our hope in
Jesus Christ. And we light the second candle to give
thanks for the Bible that is a light to guide and
inspire us:

All: God of hope, come to us again this Advent.
May your Word be a lamp to our feet
and a light on our path. Amen.

20:17 - Song MP 1086 Light of the world

23:03 - Introduction to the reading
Who knows where Malachi actually is in the bible?
It only appears once in the 3 year 
Malachi was the last of the 12 minor prophets and the last book in the old testament. From about 450 years before the birth of Christ
Malachi may not be the name of the writer of this book, &quot;malachi&quot; means messenger
The original words were arranged on a scroll by the ancient editor and as the words were a message, it's thought this led to the nickname
At his time he was exhorting people to change their ways, warning them of the judgement to come.

25:19 - 26:29 - Reading: Malachi 3. 1-4 NIVUK 
3 ‘I will send my messenger, who will prepare the way before me.
Then suddenly the Lord you are seeking will come to his temple;
the messenger of the covenant, whom you desire, will come,’ says
the LORD Almighty.
2  But who can endure the day of his coming? Who can stand when
he appears? For he will be like a refiner’s fire or a launderer’s
soap.  3  He will sit as a refiner and purifier of silver; he will purify
the Levites and refine them like gold and silver. Then the LORD will
have men who will bring offerings in righteousness,  4  and the
offerings of Judah and Jerusalem will be acceptable to the LORD, as
in days gone by, as in former years.

Music for reflection (Be still for the presence of the Lord)

27:45 - 31:17 - Reading: Luke 3.1-6 NIVUK read by Olive Shepherd (seated)
3 In the fifteenth year of the reign of Tiberius Caesar – when
Pontius Pilate was governor of Judea, Herod tetrarch of Galilee, his
brother Philip tetrarch of Iturea and Traconitis, and Lysanias
tetrarch of Abilene –  2  during the high-priesthood of Annas and
Caiaphas, the word of God came to John son of Zechariah in the
wilderness.  3  He went into all the country around the Jordan,
preaching a baptism of repentance for the forgiveness of sins.  4  As
it is written in the book of the words of Isaiah the prophet:
‘A voice of one calling in the wilderness,
“Prepare the way for the Lord,
    make straight paths for him.
5  Every valley shall be filled in,
    every mountain and hill made low.
The crooked roads shall become straight,
    the rough ways smooth.

6  And all people will see God’s salvation.

31:25 - Hymn 137 Hark the glad sound

34:06 - Prayer
34:36 - 46:56 - Short Address
Are we prepared to be surprised this Advent season?
Ready to find God at work where we thought he was absent, to find him in unexpected places
Luke tells us to expect the unexpected
The reading starts with the messy world of politics and power
Luke reminds his readers who is in power
When he introduces John the Baptiser he also tells us who is in power
It's this messy, conflict ridden world that God sends his message into
So here we have a world of power, conflict and tension
We are then shifted to the wilderness, a place with no rules
God's power is very different to human power and authority
It brings transformation, hope and new beginnings

46:57 - 48:28 - Prayer
48:52 - Prayers for others

53:35 - Hymn MP 1201 Longing for light

58:10 Offering of bread and wine and Offering Prayer
We invite you to share in the bread and wine at church (or at
home) united in the name of Christ.
Thanksgiving Prayer and Lord’s Prayer
Distribution of bread and wine (Music during distribution)
Closing Prayers

01:07:28 - Hymn 740 - Tell out my soul

01:10:37 - 01:10:57 - Blessing

01:11:44 - 01:15:03 - Organ Voluntary</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="39"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:nKrtK0DSDSw</id>
  <yt:videoId>nKrtK0DSDSw</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship, Sunday, 28th  November 2021</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nKrtK0DSDSw"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2021-11-28T11:34:50+00:00</published>
  <updated>2021-11-30T21:06:51+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship, Sunday, 28th  November 2021</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/nKrtK0DSDSw?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/nKrtK0DSDSw/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00.00  Photos and music before service

09:35 - Welcome and lighting of peace candle (elder)
10:35 - Introduction and Call to worship 

11:23 - Hymn - O Come, O Come Emmanuel

18:16 - Opening Prayers and Lord’s Prayer 

20:27 - Introducing theme: Faithful One

23:52 - Song - At The Name of Jesus

26:57 - Lighting of the first advent candle
27:42 - Advent song - Like a candle flame

28:49 - Introduction to Bible readings

31:07 - Reading - Psalm 25:1-10
33:00 - Reading - Luke 21:25-36 

34:43 - Hymn - Lo He Comes With Clouds Descending

39:55 - 51:42 - Address
An address in two parts: 1) An update on Wycombe Youth for Christ, 2) Reflections on the readings
God's impact in WYFC: Growing the team, outreach in schools, giving out hot chocolate, chance encounters, opportunities to help, detached youth work, sharing Jesus with young people.
Relationships - bringing our concerns before God
A man crying out to God
David declaring his dependence on the Lord - an expression of trust
&quot;All the ways of the Lord are loving towards those who keep His covenants&quot;
This advent, will you join me in moving forward in hope, hope in what the Lord is doing here and now
Praying that God will fill you with joy and hope

51:39 - Hymn - Come Thou Long Expected Jesus

54:06 - Offering prayer (acknowledging our gifts to God)

54:49 - Prayers of Intercession
Leader: Lord, show us how to live
ALL: And give us the courage to go forward in hope

58:27 - Hymn - Hail To The Lords Anointed

01:03:34 - 01:03:06 - Blessing  

01:03:57 - 01:08:52 - Organ Voluntary</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="44"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:yfMTA26H9ww</id>
  <yt:videoId>yfMTA26H9ww</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship, Sunday, 21st November 2021</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yfMTA26H9ww"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2021-11-21T11:41:36+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-01-05T09:34:00+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship, Sunday, 21st November 2021</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/yfMTA26H9ww?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/yfMTA26H9ww/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00.00  Photos and music before service

11:45 - Welcome and lighting of peace candle (elder)

12:46 - Introduction and Call to worship
Psalm 93 v 1-5
The LORD reigns, he is robed in majesty;
the LORD is robed in majesty and armed with strength;
indeed, the world is established, firm and secure.
Your throne was established long ago;
you are from all eternity.
The seas have lifted up, LORD,
the seas have lifted up their voice;
the seas have lifted up their pounding waves.
Mightier than the thunder of the great waters,
mightier than the breakers of the sea –
the LORD on high is mighty.
Your statutes, LORD, stand firm;
holiness adorns your house
for endless days

15:07 - Hymn MP13 All hail the power of Jesus name

18:01 - Opening prayers and the Lord’s prayer

21:21 - Reading Revelation Ch 1 vv 4b – 8 

23:05 - 25:45 - Introduction to theme of the service
What if I told you that on this piece of paper I had every word in the bible, every word ever spoken?
God is like an A-Z, the beginning and end of everything
God has always been
God is at this very moment now
God will always be forever
God's kingdom is wherever Jesus reigns in our hearts

25:59 - Hymn MP 207 Hallelujah sing to Jesus

29:52 - 30:48 - Reading John18 vv 33b – 37 

Young people leave for their group

31:44 - Hymn R&amp;S 638 Thy kingdom come o God

34:25 - 48:13 - Address
Here we are at the end of another Christian church year
Next week is the start of advent
Today is when we remember Christ the King
This festival is not an ancient one in the calendar
Only established in 1925 by Pope Pious the 11th when Europe was in chaos, inflation was rampant and the seeds of the forthcoming disaster were being sowed
The conversation from John's reading allows John to pronounce that Jesus is a king with divine authority
Too often truth is often what power says it is
Jesus defied logic by the way he lived and taught
Teaching that truth is the cornerstone of a decent society

48:21 - Hymn R&amp;S 522 From heaven you came helpless babe

52:46 - Prayers of intercession

56:33 - Hymn R&amp;S 262 Crown him with many crowns


01:00:02 - 01:00:20 - Blessing
01:00:45 - 01:05:18 - Organ voluntary</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="43"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:UbbeU7nICMQ</id>
  <yt:videoId>UbbeU7nICMQ</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship, Sunday, 14th November 2021</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UbbeU7nICMQ"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2021-11-14T11:43:49+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-01-06T10:12:24+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship, Sunday, 14th November 2021</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/UbbeU7nICMQ?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/UbbeU7nICMQ/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00.00  Photos and music before service

14:45 - Welcome and lighting of peace candle (Sue)

11:54 - Introduction and Call to worship Psalm 33  v 2-5 

13:04 - Hymn - God is Love, let heaven adore Him

16:50 - Opening Prayers and Lord’s Prayer 

20:08 - 25:49 - Introductory Talk – “Dark and Light”

What was special about Sunday, 31st October, 2 weeks ago
A 25 hour day - what did you do with the additional hour?
Darker earlier in the day
Different shades of light and dark
Close your eyes and cover them to experience the darkness
Remembering the dark times of war

Being able to meet family again


25:50 - Song - The Lord’s my Shepherd led by the worship band

Blessing as Junior Church depart

30:18 - Act of Remembrance

32:15 - Prayers for peace (using R&amp;S 641 – We pray for peace)

37:46 - Last Post   Video 

39:00 - Two minutes silence

41:34 - 42:05 - Poem: “They shall not grow old …”
  
42:38 - 45:52 - Readings: Mark 13 v1-8; Hebrews10 11-25  

46:18 - Prayer 
47:30 - 01:00:18 - Sermon – “Promises, promises!”
The gospel reading talks about war.
It follows on from Jesus' triumphant entry into Jerusalem but we know it comes before the darkest of dark times when Jesus was crucified
The disciples comment to Jesus about how magnificent the temple stones were.
12m long, 4m deep and 6m high, huge pieces of stone that look as if they will be there for ever
Jesus disabuses the disciples of this saying the stones will collapse and every stone will be thrown down.
A shock to the disciples
Jesus is anticipating the destruction of Jerusalem in AD70
Jesus gives the disciples some of the signs of the end of the age
Jesus makes it clear that they should not worry but to watch and be prepared.
Promises made and promises kept?  Do our politicians keep their promises?
COP26 in Glasgow, what promises have been made and which will be kept
Greta Thunberg and &quot;Blah, blah, blah&quot;


01:00:31 - Hymn - Rejoice the Lord is King

 
01:04:03 - 01:09:13 - Offering Prayer &amp; Prayers for Others

01:09:21 - Closing Hymn - All I once held dear

01:12:44 - 01:13:03 - Blessing


01:13:26 - 01:16:50 - Organ voluntary</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="20"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:KUX5O2c5jKs</id>
  <yt:videoId>KUX5O2c5jKs</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship, Sunday, 7th November 2021</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KUX5O2c5jKs"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2021-11-07T11:41:38+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-01-13T07:31:55+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship, Sunday, 7th November 2021</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/KUX5O2c5jKs?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/KUX5O2c5jKs/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00 Introductory photos and notices

09:24 - Welcome, introduction and call to worship (from Psalm 146.1-5)

09:58 - Lighting of the peace candle
10:40 - Call to worship

Praise the LORD, my soul.
I will praise the LORD all my life;
I will sing praise to my God as long as I live.
Blessed are those whose help is the God of Jacob,
whose hope is in the LORD their God.
The Lord is the Maker of heaven and earth,
the sea, and everything in them –
God remains faithful for ever.

11:30 - Hymn  For all the saints

15:18 - Opening Prayer of adoration and confession

17:19 - 23:43 - Introduction: ‘Not to be forgotten’

A glorious autumn day, the leaves are falling but taking their time
A month of remembering
Remembering and forgetting
Every piece matters
A community of faith
A challenge - remembering the people who feel forgotten
Those who died in conflict
The planet on which we depend
No-one if forgotten by God
The ribbons from the gate to remember loved ones



23:49 - HYMN R&amp;S 549  One more step along the world

26:50 - 32:55 - Introducing the readings, stories of two widows

Reading 1 Kings 17:8-16 (NIVUK) 
Reading: Psalm 146. 6 – 10
Reading: Mark 12:38-44 (NIVUK) 



33:04 - Song - In my life, Lord

35:05 - 49:14 - Short Address
We have seen weighty discussions this week about the climate crisis
Stepping back from the big things to the small ones
Small things can challenge the big and powerful interests - Greta Thunberg
Small is beautiful by E. F. Schumacher - humane economics appropriate to the situation. 
Ecomonics for the people who matter

Our readings focus on small things
The widow's generosity keeps flowing
Hope for all
Jesus had an eye for small things too

Praying the voices of the smallest nations will be heard in Glasgow



49:35 - Prayer 

50:50 - Hymn - I come with joy to meet my Lord

53:54 - Offering of bread and wine and Offering Prayer
We invite you to share in the bread and wine at church (or at home) united in the name of Christ.

Thanksgiving Prayer and Lord’s Prayer

Distribution of bread and wine (Music during distribution)

01:02:25 - Closing Prayers 

01:04:20 - HYMN R&amp;S 21  Praise God from whom all blessings flow

01:05:15 - 01:05:38 - Blessing
01:06:05 - 01:10:45 - Organ voluntary

Refreshments are being served after church (in the Meeting Place – please bring it back into church to drink).  Do stay if you can.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="1" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="27"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:xqr37REZJig</id>
  <yt:videoId>xqr37REZJig</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship, Sunday, 31st October 2021</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xqr37REZJig"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2021-10-31T11:48:57+00:00</published>
  <updated>2021-11-01T14:43:50+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship, Sunday, 31st October 2021</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/xqr37REZJig?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/xqr37REZJig/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00 Introductory photos and notices

Worship led by Terry Hinks 
Organist: Graham Nash

09:45 - Welcome, introduction and call to worship

10:16 - Lighting of the peace candle

11:38 - Hymn - All people that on earth do dwell

14:44 - Opening Prayer of adoration and confession with the response
With all creation
We praise you, Loving God.
Lord’s Prayer



18:01 - Thinking of those whose lives are challenging in Eastern Europe
19:03 - Shoebox collection – Daphne Stopworth
1 million shoeboxes distributed since the start of Link to Hope in 1992, 20,000 in 2020
Donations of money as well as items in shoeboxes

25:04 - Prayer
25:57 - 28:22 - One World Week – act now for our children’s world

28:29 - Song - Let there be love shared among us

30:35 - Introducing the readings

31:17 - Reading: Deuteronomy 6.1-9 (NIVUK) read by Jeany Bien  

33:22 - Psalm 148 read by minister and congregation 

35:34 - 37:00 - Reading: Mark 12.28-34 (NIVUK) read by Fiona Warden

37:15 - Song - Such love

39:55 - 55:57 - Address
Today we have heard familiar readings
They are familiar but stretch our minds and hearts
Deuteronomy covers how people will live with God, facing both triumph and disaster yet still go forward
Moses says the commandments are to be part of daily life
Stretch your mind across the amazing universe which we are discovering more about but still have so much to find; across this planet with all the diverse species
Have you come to worship this morning feeling nothing of God's presence?  We can offer worship all the same
We cannot do it on our own, we need the grace of our Lord Jesus Christ



55:58 - Music for reflection

57:22 - Offering Prayer (gifts are brought forward)

57:59 - Hymn - Day by day dear Lord (sung seated as a prayer)

59:41 - Prayers for the world

01:06:14 - Hymn  Love divine all loves excelling

01:09:58 - 01:10:20 - Blessing

01:10:45 - 01:14:54 - Organ voluntary 

Refreshments are being served after church (in the Meeting Place – please bring it back into church to drink).  Do stay if you can.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="2" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="41"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:9mZy9X-hYCE</id>
  <yt:videoId>9mZy9X-hYCE</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship, Sunday, 24th October 2021</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9mZy9X-hYCE"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2021-10-24T10:51:41+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-01-13T00:39:18+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship, Sunday, 24th October 2021</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/9mZy9X-hYCE?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/9mZy9X-hYCE/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00 Introductory photos and notices


Worship led by Steve Burton
Organist: Charles Brewster

11:10 - Welcome 
11:35 - Lighting of the peace candle

12:12 - Call to worship
13:25 - Hymn - To the name of our salvation
17:30 - Prayers of adoration and confession
20:37 - 23:32 - Talk - The reading from Mark and Bartimaeus 
How would we deal with losing our sight?
Listening to Nunc Dimitus
The more I heard the music, the thought of not hearing felt worse than not being able to see
Close your eyes for a few moments and imagine you are blind
How will you survive, how will you work, how will you move around.
23:45 - Song - Jesus, Hope of the nations
28:23 - 30:08 - Reading - Mark 10, 46-52
30:20 - Hymn - A Glorious Company We Sing
32:30 - 47:50 - Address
Lines from the reading from Mark
The striking contrast in the reading, a great multitude and a lone individual
It is impressive to see Jesus turn his attention from the crowd to the one.
There is evidence of something deeper than just being aware of surroundings
This narrative comes with pertinence for a generation that acts on multitudes and quantities
The lowest in society can too easily get lost
What does our manner say about us
Are we like the crowd or Jesus?

48:00 - Hymn - Lord of light whose name outshineth
52:14 - Prayers of intercession
55:11 - HYMN - God is love let heaven adore Him
59:11 - 59:32 - Blessing
59:53 - 01:03:18 - Organ voluntary


Refreshments are being served after church (in the Meeting Place – please bring it back into church to drink).  Do stay if you can.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="58"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:uYo7rhI9A14</id>
  <yt:videoId>uYo7rhI9A14</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship, Sunday, 17th October 2021</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uYo7rhI9A14"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2021-10-17T10:27:27+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-01-14T13:10:47+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship, Sunday, 17th October 2021</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/uYo7rhI9A14?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/uYo7rhI9A14/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00 Introductory photos and notices

SIGHT LOSS SUNDAY
Worship led by Sue Thorne
Organist: Charles Brewster

14:40 - Welcome 
15:01 - Lighting of peace candle

15:27 - Introduction and Call to worship led by Sue Thorne 

16:45 - Hymn MP 1201 Longing for Light, We wait in the Darkness (Christ be our Light)

20:54 - Opening Prayers and Lord’s Prayer 

23:07 - Introducing theme: Sight Loss Sunday 

25:45 - 28:10 - A recorded message from David Reynolds 
Sight loss Sunday is the day we try to understand sight loss and those people suffering from it.
The impact of COVID on those with sight loss
We are not a minority that shouts from the rooftops
Can we examine the attitudes to people with disabilities
Hope that we will gain a greater understanding of people with sight loss within the church

28:11 - Song MP 1008 The Lord’s my Shepherd (Townend)

30:09 - Introduction to Bible readings

Readings  2 Kings 6:8-22 NIVUK read by Kate Yates 
Mark 10 46-52 NIVUK read by Alan Yates 

35:20 - Song R&amp;S 522 From Heaven you came (Servant King)

39:30 -  50:09 - A recorded reflection by Dr Mike Townsend (Torch Trust)
Sight loss and sight from a Christian point of view
Sight loss and spiritual sight 
Sight is not just on and off, it's variable
Elisha found in Syria and the army being struck with sight loss
 


50:16 - Offering prayer (acknowledging our gifts to God) and prayers for the world

53:35 - Hymn R&amp;S 117 How Great Thou Art

58:27 - 58:37 - Blessing  

58:55 - Organ voluntary

There is a basket in the entrance for gifts of money and a box for donations to One Can Foodbank.

HOW TO GIVE  Donations can be left in the collection basket at the back of church.  We are grateful for people’s regular giving and donations.  If you would like to give to the church by Standing Order, bank transfer or cheque please contact the treasurer: Sue Thorne (Trinity) suethorne24@btinternet.com 01494 564635

Refreshments are being served after church (in the Meeting Place – please bring it back into church to drink).  Do stay if you can.  

Sight Loss Sunday is a new initiative from Torch Trust. It has two main purposes: 
• To raise awareness of the prevalence of sight loss in church and local community. 
• To encourage Christians to nurture the unique gifts, talents and abilities that people with sight loss can bring to church life. 
Torch Trust believes that all people with sight loss have a valuable part to play in churches and Christian communities, and Sight Loss Sunday is designed to equip us to live out these values in our own congregation.  Founded in 1959, Torch Trust offers Christian products and services to improve the lives of people with sight loss. They offer Bibles, hymn books and a whole variety of publications in a range of accessible formats including braille, large print and audio. They contribute to RNIB Connect Radio with &quot;Reflections&quot; which airs on a Sunday morning.   They also offer a range of bespoke Christian holidays for people with sight loss.  Their &quot;Sight Loss Friendly Church&quot; initiative offers training, support and advice to churches of all denominations who wish to be more inclusive of people with sight loss.  They provide regular training sessions and catch-up sessions online.

Both Trinity and Cores End Churches are registered as Sight Loss Friendly Churches and we want to do everything we can to include all people, whatever their abilities, in the life and work of the church.  For more information please speak to Sue after the service or visit the Torch Trust website:
www.sightlossfriendlychurch.org.uk</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="1" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="23"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
</feed>
