<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns:yt="http://www.youtube.com/xml/schemas/2015" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 <link rel="self" href="http://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=PLrggWHcy3azrunmSfTCSlS5JRuB4zTgCY"/>
 <id>yt:playlist:PLrggWHcy3azrunmSfTCSlS5JRuB4zTgCY</id>
 <yt:playlistId>PLrggWHcy3azrunmSfTCSlS5JRuB4zTgCY</yt:playlistId>
 <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
 <title>Worship services - Trinity and Cores End URCs</title>
 <author>
  <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
  <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
 </author>
 <published>2020-04-04T11:11:34+00:00</published>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:LJAzGtKoS-g</id>
  <yt:videoId>LJAzGtKoS-g</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship, Sunday, 6th March 2022</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LJAzGtKoS-g"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-03-06T11:55:24+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-03-06T12:19:18+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship, Sunday, 6th March 2022</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/LJAzGtKoS-g?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/LJAzGtKoS-g/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00:00 - Music and notices before the service

00:10:52 - Welcome and lighting of peace candle (an elder)
Call to worship 
As we come to worship today let us say of our God:
You are the One who is my refuge and my fortress, 
my God, in whom I trust.  
Lord open our lips
And our mouths shall proclaim your praise! 

SONG R&amp;S 292  When morning gilds the skies

Prayer of adoration and confession 

SONG TP 102 You laid aside your majesty

Reading: Luke 4.1-13 NIVUK read by Lesley Bogart

Introduction: ‘Into Lent’

Reading: Romans 10.8b – 13 (Good News) read by Ian Bogart

Short Address: ‘Jesus – Son of God, Son of Man’

Worship Song from Ukraine 
“I will Sing,” by Maria Kuchurian &amp; Diana Yakovyn

He is the One who lifts up and surrounds with peace.
His love is great! I will hold on to Him.
When the heart is heavy, He takes away the stone,
Gently hugs. O my holy Jesus!
I will sing, I will sing, I will sing to the Risen King!
His hand is with me. He's near, here, I know
I feel in my heart, I pray to Him!
He warms with love and wipes away tears
Loyal Friend forever. His name is Jesus!
You chose me and set me up, You chose me, raised me up!
You chose me and forgave me, You chose me, raised me!
You chose me and filled me, You chose me, raised me!

Prayer for peace in Ukraine
The psalmist writes: “I call on the Lord in my distress,
and he answers me.”
Lord, we call to you in our distress.
We trust you to answer us.
We lift up the people of Ukraine before you…

Lord’s Prayer 

Offering our lives for God’s work today 

Communion: we invite you to share in the bread and wine at church (or at home) united in the name of Christ.
W
HYMN  TP 48  Jesus calls us here to meet him 

A Prayer of thanksgiving and distribution of communion

Closing Prayer

HYMN R&amp;S 463ii  Now let us from this table rise

Blessing

#Ukraine #HappyBirthdayGlyn #GuideMeOThouGreatJehovah</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="12"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:Ozyqrj7t1hY</id>
  <yt:videoId>Ozyqrj7t1hY</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship, Sunday, 27th February 2022</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ozyqrj7t1hY"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-02-27T11:44:11+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-03-03T08:58:50+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship, Sunday, 27th February 2022</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/Ozyqrj7t1hY?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/Ozyqrj7t1hY/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00:00 -  Music and notices
WE APPROACH GOD

07:35 - Entry of the bible and lighting of the peace candle
09:00 - Call to worship – based on Matthew 5 and Luke 6 
Blest are the poor in spirit, 
For theirs is the kingdom of heaven. 
Blest are they that mourn, 
For they shall be comforted. 
Blest are the meek,
For they shall inherit the earth.

09:51 - Hymn - R&amp;S 339 – Great God, your love has called us here. 
 -
14:25 Introduction
15:25 - PRAYERS - of Approach, Thanksgiving, Confession &amp;  Praise     
LORD'S PRAYER
-
20:27 - 25:30 - FAMILY TALK – In search of happiness
Who knows Timpson's?
A well known, family run business.
Run with great integrity.
They have just appointed a director of happiness.
What makes you happy? Arguing about one's age?
Family and friends, Lego spaceships, sunshine, sweets, ice cream, friends
The next question - what makes your parents happy?
A tidy room? Space and time?
The real question - what makes God happy?
We can get an understanding of this when we read the Beatitudes
Those who are humble, not constantly taking selfies, merciful, not vengeful, those who work for peace, not trying to conquer lands 

-
25:33 - Hymn 2 – R&amp;S 512 – Seek ye first the kingdom of God.
-
28:53 - OFFERTORY PRAYER 
-
PRAYER for young people as they leave
 May the Lord be with you
 And also with you
-
29:57 - WE LISTEN FOR GOD’S WORD
-
31:39 - Reading 1 – Jeremiah 17 v5-10
-
33:03 - 36:18 - Reading 2 - Luke 6 v17-26
-
36:28 - Hymn 3 - R&amp;S 586 – All my hope on God is founded.
- 
40:18 - 55:30 - SERMON – Jam tomorrow?
An amusing story about the last hymn (All my hope on God is founded)
This service was first used at Chesham a couple of weeks ago. Chesham have some masonry fallen off one of the towers.
As the hymn was sung, most of the Elders were struggling not to giggle as the words &quot;with what care and toil is build-ed, tower and temple fall to dust&quot; rang out
Do you remember more than a decade ago when David Cameron asked the Office for National Statistics to come up with a happiness index?
The sermon on the mount and sermon on the plain having the same roots, extending into the Old Testament
Listeners to Christ would have known the links and known that Jesus was referring back to Chronicles, Psalms, and Isaiah.
Luke presents us with a choice - do you want to be a citizen of God's kingdom or a citizen of the Roman Empire (or whatever empire is around today)?
Do you want to be generous or greedy, merciful or vengeful, peaceful or militant, part of the solution or part of the problem
May we live full lives in this topsy turvy world
-
WE MAKE OUR RESPONSE
-
55:45 - Hymn 4 - R&amp;S 367 – I want to walk with Jesus Christ. 
-
59:32 - PRAYERS for Others and Ourselves. 
-
WE GO OUT TO SERVE

01:06:42 - Hymn 5 - R&amp;S 530 – Living God, your joyful spirit.     
-
01:11:33 - 01:12:11 - BLESSING

01:13:11 - 01:14:40 - Closing Music. 

Worship Leader Alan Yates - Organist Angus Massie.</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="33"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:6PBxJNSF0Lg</id>
  <yt:videoId>6PBxJNSF0Lg</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship, Sunday, 20th February 2022 - Compassion Sunday</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6PBxJNSF0Lg"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-02-20T11:50:49+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-02-28T08:49:14+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship, Sunday, 20th February 2022 - Compassion Sunday</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/6PBxJNSF0Lg?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/6PBxJNSF0Lg/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00:00 -  Music and notices

08:03 - Welcome and lighting of peace candle (an elder)
12:03 - Call to worship
The Lord is gracious and makes things right:
our God is full of compassion.

12:27 - Hymn -  R&amp;S 522  From heaven you came, helpless babe

16:35 - Opening Prayers 
Lord’s Prayer

19:10 - Introducing Compassion UK 
Good that we are focusing on Compassion this year, one of the leading Christian Childrens' charities
Sponsors are connected to and known by the children they support
Sponsors play a vital role in building the confidence and self-worth of the children
Over 2M infants and children supported

21:40 - Compassion UK Sponsorship Animation Video

22:34 - Celebration Presentation  
Our impact, our gifts: more than 3000 hours of support and 1000 meals
25:31 - letters from supported Children - Mary and Christian

38:05 - 40:18 - Reading John 5. 1-15 NIVUK 

41:20 - Song - MP 181  God forgave my sin in Jesus’ name

43:49 - 46:08 - Reading: Ephesians 4. 1-16 NIVUK 

46:17 - Song -  MP 1000 King of kings majesty

49:40 - 01:05:16 - Talk : Empowerment
What makes you feel empowered?  Think of moments that have caused you to feel confidence or courage to step up.
2 years ago I felt empowered by the technical team to speak to people in their homes - scary and creative!
When have you felt dis-empowered?
If Hayley were here she would share how she was empowered to help people
Memories of a woman at a market begging people to help feed her children
Becoming aware of Compassion through her church
Pen pals to share stories and help
Feeling the need to help but not knowing where to do so
How to be part of a sustainable, God built change
Empowering people to do it the right way
Jesus is the original example of empowering others

01:05:27 - 01:08:14 - Compassion UK Video: ‘Least of These’ 

01:08:58 - Prayers for the church and the world 
God of compassion,
Hear our prayer.

01:13:31 - Offering and Commitment prayer
God of all creation,
we stand before you now.
We thank you for all your goodness.
We offer our gifts and our lives, 
for the work of your kingdom of justice and joy.
Deepen our care for each other,
for all humanity and the planet itself.
Make us channels of your love and peace.  Amen.

01:15:06 - Hymn R&amp;S 531  Lord of all hopefulness

01:17:56 - 01:18:25 - Blessing

01:18:54 - 01:23:21 - Organ voluntary and notices

#StormEunice, #Compassion, #CompassionSunday</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="1" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="51"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:8JJouPcHn1Q</id>
  <yt:videoId>8JJouPcHn1Q</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship, Sunday, 13th February 2022 led by Rev John Mackerness</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8JJouPcHn1Q"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-02-13T11:36:48+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-02-15T02:35:01+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship, Sunday, 13th February 2022 led by Rev John Mackerness</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/8JJouPcHn1Q?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/8JJouPcHn1Q/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00:00 -  Music and notices

08:26 - Welcome and lighting of peace candle

10:43 - Call to worship 

12:21 - Hymn MP 564 Praise to the Lord

15:51 - Intro to theme – The story of Robin Hood
Many versions of the story of Robin Hood
Disney Fox through Errol Flynn, Richard Green
A Saxon lord, made outlaw, gains the trust of the poor, falls in love, wins an archery contest, defeats the bad guys and live happily ever after until being betrayed by his sister.
A great story with many changes over the times
A love interest
Robin and most of the outlaws are Saxons but all of the power is transferring to the conquering Normans.
They unfairly use their power against the people
We know that if there is going to be justice that the law needs to be applied equally to all
Imagine you were a nobleman hearing the story for the first time, or a peasant or a priest.  How would you feel about it?
Positive or negative - generally the lower in the pecking order, the more positive
When we hear the passage from Luke's gospel later, listen and imagine the different reactions that people might have

21:22 - 24:26 - Opening Prayers 
The Lord’s Prayer
 
24:27 - Worship song  MP 1201 Longing for light
 
29:49 - Introduction to Bible readings

30:30 - Reading: Jeremiah 17:5-10 read by Norma Garden

31:54 - 33:47 - Reading: Luke 6:17-26 read by Norma Garden

33:58 - Hymn MP 16 All my hope on God is founded

36:57 - 51:20 - Sermon followed by time of quiet reflection 
We are very used to hearing a comfortable gospel message
One of peace, a loving God sending his Son to forgive our sins, Jesus raising on the third day, how at the end of time he will return to judge the living and the dead.  
Most of it is fairly nice and cosy, but should it be that comfortable?
From the passage in Luke, Jesus tells of those who will be blessed
After the blessings come the sorrows: those of the rich, fat and prosperous.  Those who laugh now, those who are praised by the crowds.
Remember the story of Robin Hood, how you feel depends on where you fit into the story.
If you are sorrowful, how do you feel if God tells you that you are blessed in the next life?
The bible has a lot to say about justice
It's God's word and we should love justice because God loves justice
Racism and wider justice issues deny basic human dignity to men and women made in the image of God
However, God is a just God.  

51:27 - Hymn MP 1261 Brother, Sister, let me serve you

54:29 - Prayers for the world

59:34 - Hymn MP 77 Christ triumphant

01:02:49 - 01:03:34 - Closing blessing 

01:04:10 - 01:07:40 - Organ voluntary and notices

Thank you to our Organist today Charles Brewster</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="1" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="20"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:ej-36em2Fjo</id>
  <yt:videoId>ej-36em2Fjo</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship, Sunday, 6th February 2022 led by Terry Hinks</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ej-36em2Fjo"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-02-06T11:55:16+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-03-01T01:20:53+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship, Sunday, 6th February 2022 led by Terry Hinks</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/ej-36em2Fjo?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/ej-36em2Fjo/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00:00 -  Music and notices

15:37 - Welcome and lighting of peace candle

17:14 - Call to worship (based on Isaiah 60)
I will praise you, Lord, with all my heart:
  Before all else we will sing your praise.
We will praise your name, God of all:
  We give thanks for your unfailing love and faithfulness.

18:46 - Song - R&amp;S 34  Holy, holy, holy

22:20 - Prayer of adoration and confession 

24:30 - Introduction: ‘ready for new challenges?’
Already in February, January has gone like a dream
Thinking of new challenges like those faced by Isaiah or Simon Peter
Are you ready for new challenges?  A new system at work, GCSE choices, driving test, making soft rolls.
Challenges faced by Nina Sparks as she gained a position on the GB para snowboard team, representing her country at the World Para Snowsports championships in Lillehammer 
Staff shortages in schools due to COVID
Cancer Research London Winter run 2022
God's word of challenge in the bible
Our two readings this morning will have those words of challenge
God's challenge to Isiah, &quot;who shall I send?&quot;
An all church challenge - walking with Jesus

34:26 - 35:42 - Prayer for all ages
Jesus wants us to get involved in God’s story. So, I ask you:
Are we ready to listen to Jesus?
  Yes, we are ready.
Are we ready to learn new ways of living?
  Yes, we are ready.
Are we ready to use our skills and gifts to help others?
  Yes, we are ready.
Are we ready to say thank you to Jesus,
for being our friend and Saviour?
  Yes, we are ready.
Let’s say it again!
  Yes, we are ready.

35:44 - Song MP 3 Abba Father let me be

38:12 - 40:53 - Reading: Isaiah 6.1-8 

40:55 - Hymn - MP 857   I the Lord of sea and sky

46:33 - Reading: Luke 5.1-11NIVUK 

48:50 - Short Address: ‘called to go deeper’
Building and launching a yacht at Lyme Regis
Circumnavigating the British Isles, beautiful and frightening
The ferocity of the sea
The story of the net washing, the teaching, and the huge catch
Using his boat brought Simon into contact with this amazing man Jesus
Ultimately the fish are not important as Jesus is talking about fishing for people
Simon recognizes his own failures in the presence of this extraordinary figure
Jesus says not for the last time - &quot;do not be afraid, follow me&quot;
After the assurance becomes the invitation to become a fisher of people
Are we willing to follow?  To the table, to our daily life, to our hurting life.  To draw others into the net of God's grace

59:48 - 01:00:42 - Prayer  

01:00:50 - Offering our lives for God’s work today 

Communion: we invite you to share in the bread and wine at church (or at home) united in the name of Christ.

01:02:09 - Song - MP 50 Be still for the presence of the Lord

01:05:16 - A Prayer of thanksgiving 
Lord’s Prayer 

01:07:58 - Communion 

01:12:05 - Closing Prayer

01:15:05 - Hymn R&amp;S 261 At the name of Jesus (Tune Camberwell)

01:18:05 - 01:18:31 - Blessing

01:19:08 - 01:22:14 - Organ voluntary and notices
Thank you to our Organist today Andrew Winton</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="27"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:Z6FpI8xsgAE</id>
  <yt:videoId>Z6FpI8xsgAE</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship, Sunday, 30th Jan 2022 led by Peter Green</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Z6FpI8xsgAE"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-01-30T11:35:52+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-01-31T08:47:11+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship, Sunday, 30th Jan 2022 led by Peter Green</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/Z6FpI8xsgAE?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/Z6FpI8xsgAE/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00:00 - Music and notices before the service

09:04 - Welcome and lighting of peace candle (an elder)

10:55 - Call to worship 

11:19 - Hymn R&amp;S   117 O Lord, my God, when I in awesome wonder

15:28 - Opening Prayers and the Lord’s Prayer

18:12 - 22:06 - Talk for all ages
Francis, the monks, and public speaking
Not knowing what to speak about
Sharing the Gospel message with others
Knowing Jesus, sharing things with him

Blessing as Junior Church go to their activities:

22:57 - Worship songs led by the worship band
Give thanks with a grateful heart

26:50 - Reading: Jeremiah Chapter 1, verses4-10 

28:00 -30:07 -  Reading: Luke Chapter 4, verses 20-30  

30:17 - Hymn R&amp;S   355 Jesus calls us! O’er the tumult

33:00 - 54:05 - Sermon followed by time of quiet reflection 
Sharing pulpits
Living and growing up in Southall
Jesus living the words from Isiah &quot;the spirit of the Lord is upon me&quot;
The symbolism of sitting down after the reading
Jesus showing how people had benefited from Gods presence in their lives
&quot;Who is this Jesus to say these things!&quot;
Times when God has called us to speak yet we remain silent
Would you have been one of the crowd in the synagogue?
When did we last speak to friends or family about our faith?
Where does God want us to go, what does He want us to say and to whom?


54:52 - Hymn R&amp;S 367 I want to walk with Jesus Christ

58:42 - Prayers for others and ourselves

01:04:39 - Hymn R&amp;S 531 Lord of all hopefulness, Lord of all joy
 
01:07:23 - 01:07:47 - Closing blessing

01:08:25 - 01:10:57 - Music and notices</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="1" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="34"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:tqxWRxAg0X4</id>
  <yt:videoId>tqxWRxAg0X4</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship, Sunday, 23rd Jan 2022</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tqxWRxAg0X4"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-01-23T11:27:19+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-01-25T23:07:29+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship, Sunday, 23rd Jan 2022</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/tqxWRxAg0X4?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/tqxWRxAg0X4/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00:00 - Music and notices before the service

06:57 - Welcome and lighting of peace candle 

09:21 - Call to worship

10:05 - Hymn R&amp;S 557 - Who would true valour see

12:45 - Opening Prayers of adoration and confession
Followed by the Lord’s Prayer

15:26 - 20:27 - Talk for all ages
Relationships
Our relationship with God
Our relationships with each other
A big subject - what does it mean
Feeling lonely and alone
What do you feel when you think about relationships?
Connections and saying hello
God is with us all the time
Not visible but here 
Relaxing and being with God

21:25 - Worship song: We are marching in the light of God
Led by the worship band

23:43 - Blessing as Junior Church go to their activities:
Adults: May the Lord be with you
Junior Church: And also with you
All: Amen

Offering Dedication

25:28 - Reading: Nehemiah 8 vv1-3, 5-6, 8-10

28:10 - 29:42 - Reading: 1 Corinthians 7 vv 17-24 read by Linda Curley

30:29 - Hymn RS 745 A new commandment I give unto you
Led by the worship band

33:18 - 44:15 - Sermon followed by time of quiet reflection
Our relationship with God
Nehemiah was written in the 5th Century BC by the same author as the Chronicles and Ezra
These books are important as they tell the history of the Jews up to the end of their 50 years of exile in Babylon and their return
Rebuilding the temple which was destroyed
 Fast forward to AD 55.  The Persian empire has given way to the Greeks and Romans, Jesus has been born, crucified and risen from the dead. Saul had made his journey and been blinded by the light, meeting Christ.
From that moment on, nothing was the same.  Saul became Paul, realising Jesus was the messiah he had been waiting for all his life.
Paul felt God meets us just where we are
Nearly 2000 years later, the same applies to us

44:29 - Hymn R&amp;S 353 There’s a wideness in God’s mercy

47:42 - Prayers of intercession

52:05 - Hymn R&amp;S 72 Now thank we all our God

55:03 - 56:00 - Closing blessing

56:20 - 59:50 - Music and notices</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="24"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:_g_QzcCRz_o</id>
  <yt:videoId>_g_QzcCRz_o</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship, Sunday, 16th May 2021</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_g_QzcCRz_o"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2021-05-16T09:48:32+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-01-20T08:52:21+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship, Sunday, 16th May 2021</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/_g_QzcCRz_o?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/_g_QzcCRz_o/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00 - Notices and photo's from the the week.

05:24 - Welcome and call to worship
06:03 - Lighting the peace candle thinking of the events in the Middle East at this time
07:16 - Shared response:
All who are hungry
Come and eat
All who are thirsty
Come and drink
All who are weary
Come and rest
All who are happy
Come and smile
All who seek life and blessing
Come and worship your Lord and your God

07:50 - Song Jesus is Lord (recording by TCE Singers)

10:50 - Opening Prayers

12:20 - Introduction: ‘Unconfined, set free’
Last Thursday was Ascension day where we celebrate Jesus as Lord, risen and ascended, free from the bounds of flesh and blood
What does &quot;confined&quot; mean to you?
A lot of us have felt confined over the past year, imprisoned even?
What does &quot;unconfined&quot; mean to you, where do you experience feeling unconfined?

15:06 - Reading:  Luke 24.44-53 NIVUK read by a member of the church

16:33 - Prayer: ‘Jesus unconfined’
Struggling with what the ascension of Jesus means
Pictures of Jesus with his feet dangling out of a cloud
Thinking of unconfined Jesus in the world today in Jerusalem, the middle east and India especially
Sharing communion allows Jesus to be unconfined, working in our lives
When the disciples returned to Jerusalem, they returned with joy knowing Jesus was with them

20:56 - Acts 1.12-13a, 14 read by the minister

21:34 - Short Address – Praying the kingdom
We gather in our place of worship and homes just as the disciples did to pray together and praise the Lord.  
A disparate group of people, just Jews at the start then a growing group of Jews and Gentiles
Thinking of Jerusalem today, the suffering of the people in Israel and Palestine

27:20 - Reading: John 17.15 – 19 (the Message) read by church member
28:34 - Prayer

32:23 - Offering of bread and wine and Offering Prayer
We invite you to share in the bread and wine at church (or at home) united in the name of Christ.

Music to prepare for communion

Thanksgiving Prayer and Lord’s Prayer
Lord’s Prayer

36:30 - Distribution of bread and wine (Music during distribution at Trinity)

Closing Prayer 

39:47 - Hymn - Christ triumphant 

43:06 - 43:28 - Blessing
43:38 - 45:55 - Notices and music to close</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="36"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:ya4ZYEHXa2k</id>
  <yt:videoId>ya4ZYEHXa2k</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 16th January 2022</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ya4ZYEHXa2k"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-01-16T11:48:53+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-01-18T08:50:16+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 16th January 2022</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/ya4ZYEHXa2k?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/ya4ZYEHXa2k/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00.00  Photos and music before service
06:13 - Welcome and lighting of peace candle (an elder)

08:12 - Call to worship (based on Isaiah 60)
We are met in the presence of God;
and we do not meet alone.
With the Church throughout the world,
we gather to worship the Lord.
In Cathedrals, tin tabernacles and fields,
God’ holy name is praised. 
And here with our hearts and our voices,
God’ holy name is praised. 
We are met in the presence of God;
and we do not meet alone.

09:03 - Hymn R&amp;S 293  Ye servants of God

11:58 - Prayers of adoration and confession 
Lord’s Prayer 

14:21 - Introduction: ‘Jesus revealed’
Today is the second Sunday in Epiphany
Not as familiar as Easter or Lent but still one of the great seasons
Thinking about hidden things
Snowdrops, daffodils, the promise of things to come
Anyone can count the seeds in an apple but only God can count the number of apples in a seed
Jesus revealed
The wedding in Cana
6x 120 litres of wine!


22:41 - 24:10 - Reading: John 2. 1 – 11

24:12 - 26:03 - Prayer
When a daffodil or the first snowdrop comes into bloom:
We catch a glimpse of God in the ordinary.
When the sun is rising, or the sun is setting:
We catch a glimpse of God in the ordinary.
When a baby is born, or a chick is hatched:
We catch a glimpse of God in the ordinary.
When we feel the warm embrace of a family hug:
We catch a glimpse of God in the ordinary.
When we come to worship or offer a prayer:
We catch a glimpse of God in the ordinary.
Transforming God, wherever we are, whatever we do,
whether we are at home, work or school,
help us to see the miracle in the ordinary,
and to catch a glimpse of your glory in our midst.  
Amen.

26:40 - 31:20 - WORSHIP SONGS
Jesus put this song into our hearts
Jesus stand among us

31:42 - Introduction to the reading – ‘different but one’ – containers

34:10 - 35:40 - Reading: 1 Corinthians 12.1-11 

35:51 - Song TP 61  Lord of the church  TUNE: Londonderry Air  

40:53 - Prayer
41:28 - 59:08 - Address : Today
Focusing on today in 3 different ways
This Sunday first marks the second Sunday of Epiphany with Jesus being revealed
John says not to get fixated on the details like the huge amount of wine, but to treat this as a sign of when glory was first revealed
Allow the story to reveal to you something extraordinary in the light of God's love
Corinthian Christians lived in an amazing and diverse court. They were sometimes carried away with religious fervour. 
Origins of the creed of the Christian church
This year may we continue to pray for unity in the Church of Christ

59:10 - Song TP 81 Spirit of God (chorus, vs 1 and chorus sung seated)

Prayers for the church and the world with the response
Loving Spirit: work among your people.

Song TP 81 Spirit of God (chorus, vs 2 and chorus sung seated)

01:07:07 - Offering Prayer 

01:08:20 - Hymn R&amp;S 471  Bless and keep us, Lord

 01:11:40 - 01:12:02 - Closing blessing

01:12:22 - 01:15:56 - Music after the service

#WorldParaSnowboard #LisaBunschoten #WPSS</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="46"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:7O9r3-iQJ04</id>
  <yt:videoId>7O9r3-iQJ04</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 9th January 2022</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7O9r3-iQJ04"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-01-09T12:03:46+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-03-02T20:19:12+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 9th January 2022</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/7O9r3-iQJ04?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/7O9r3-iQJ04/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00.00  Photos and music before service
16:37 - Welcome 
18:00 - Lighting of peace candle (an elder)

20:00 - Call to worship: Isaiah 43:1-3a
 But now thus says the Lord, 
 he who created you, O Jacob,
 he who formed you, O Israel:
 Do not fear, for I have redeemed you;
 I have called you by name, you are mine.
 When you pass through the waters, I will be with you;
 and through the rivers, they shall not overwhelm you;
 when you walk through fire you shall not be burned,
 and the flame shall not consume you.
 For I am the Lord your God,
 the Holy One of Israel, your Saviour.


21:07 - Hymn: R&amp;S 589  How firm a foundation

24:43 - Opening Prayers and the Lord’s Prayer

27:45 - 36:12 - Talk for all ages :  Life changing moments
How are you feeling this morning?  We all have ups and downs over time.
Sometimes we need things to lift us
Do you agree or disagree on these things that might lift you:
A good meal? A bar of chocolate? A run? A bottle of water?
Being with family
Pets
All of these things can lift us but they aren't permanent answers. We need something deeper to give us a boost when life changes direction.
Speaking to God and Him speaking to us
Looking at moments in Jesus' life - his baptism when God recognised him and sent him on into his ministry
Moments in his life when God speaks

36:44 - Worship songs 
R&amp;S 308/309 Spirit of the Living God
MP 465  Meekness and Majesty

44:13 - Blessing as Junior Church go to their activities:
 Adults: May the Lord be with you
 Junior Church: And also with you
 All: Amen

44:25 - Introduction to Bible readings

45:55 - Reading: Luke 3: 15-22   read by John Hillson
15 The people were waiting expectantly and were all wondering in their hearts if John might possibly be the Messiah. 16 John answered them all, ‘I baptise you with[b] water. But one who is more powerful than I will come, the straps of whose sandals I am not worthy to untie. He will baptise you with[c] the Holy Spirit and fire. 17 His winnowing fork is in his hand to clear his threshing-floor and to gather the wheat into his barn, but he will burn up the chaff with unquenchable fire.’ 18 And with many other words John exhorted the people and proclaimed the good news to them.
19 But when John rebuked Herod the tetrarch because of his marriage to Herodias, his brother’s wife, and all the other evil things he had done, 20 Herod added this to them all: he locked John up in prison.
21 When all the people were being baptised, Jesus was baptised too. And as he was praying, heaven was opened 22 and the Holy Spirit descended on him in bodily form like a dove. And a voice came from heaven: ‘You are my Son, whom I love; with you I am well pleased.’



48:20 - Reading: Acts 8: 14-17  read by Sue Thorne
14 When the apostles in Jerusalem heard that Samaria had accepted the word of God, they sent Peter and John to Samaria. 15 When they arrived, they prayed for the new believers there that they might receive the Holy Spirit, 16 because the Holy Spirit had not yet come on any of them; they had simply been baptised in the name of the Lord Jesus. 17 Then Peter and John placed their hands on them, and they received the Holy Spirit.

49:22 - Hymn:  R&amp;S 180  Before the world began


52:56 - 01:12:34 - Sermon:  We are loved 
We have God's affirmation of Christ at his baptism.
It's in all 4 gospels, two of which start with this story
John and Jesus were cousins, John just a few months older who as a young man went to live in the wilderness in very harsh conditions
John was preparing people for Jesus
The bible never suggests Jesus baptises with water, always with the laying on of hands
It always sounds simple - Jesus arrives, asks to be baptised, John is reluctant but agrees, performs the act, the spirit comes down.
Why did God choose this moment to speak
It contains much of the mystery and wonder of God
Why did Jesus need to be baptised?
Glimpses of hope and love all around us
We need to trust and look for God to find strength

Unconditional love
Archbishop Desmond Tutu speaking about respect and love for all

01:13:10 - Hymn:  R&amp;S 413  What a friend we have in Jesus

01:16:30 - 01:22:05 - Prayers for others and ourselves
Response:  Loving Lord,  we lift our prayers to you

01:22:08 - Hymn: R&amp;S 285  O for a thousand tongues to sing                       

01:25:54 - 01:26:12 - Closing blessing

01:26:48 - 01:33:46 - Music after the service</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="29"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:nQ9L2I11XRY</id>
  <yt:videoId>nQ9L2I11XRY</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Worship - Sunday, 2nd January 2022</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nQ9L2I11XRY"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-01-02T11:44:15+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-01-17T08:29:04+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Worship - Sunday, 2nd January 2022</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/nQ9L2I11XRY?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/nQ9L2I11XRY/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Service led by Rev Terry Hinks 
Organist Andrew Winton

00.00  - Photos and music before service
08:40 - Welcome and lighting of peace candle (an elder)
12:08 - Call to worship (based on Isaiah 60)

13:08 - Song R&amp;S 188  Born in the night

15:22 - Prayer of adoration and confession from Iona with responses:
Lord have mercy Lord have mercy
Christ have mercy Christ have mercy
Lord have mercy Lord have mercy

I believe that God forgives and sets us free
We believe that God forgives and sets us free
And at the day’s beginning we commit ourselves 
to following where Christ calls and loving as he loves us.  Amen

18:27 - 23:50 - Introduction: Not over yet!
How many of you have taken down your Christmas decorations?
Anyone who didn't put up any decorations at all?
We take some down but keep the rest up until Epiphany
Some churches don't bring out the wise men in the nativity scene until Epiphany
Today is the 9th day of Christmas - 9 ladies dancing
According to some, each of the gifts represents a Christian truth.  Some believe this to be related to the 9 fruits of the spirit - Love, Joy, Peace, Patience, Kindness, Goodness, Faithfulness, Gentleness, and Self-control
Starting anew, for ourselves and our world

23:52 - Reading: Matthew 2: 1 – 12 NIVUK 
27:32 - 29:06 - Poem ‘Don’t wait for an angel’ 

29:10 - Hymn 185 - Wise men seeking Jesus

33:02 - Reading: John 1. 10-18 NIVUK 

35:15 - 49:36 - Short Address 
Has anyone pulled a cracker this year? What local newspaper did Charles Dickens work on before he became famous?  Bicester Times and Worcester Times.
It was the best of times, it was the worst of times, it was the age of wisdom, it was the age of foolishness, it was the epoch of belief, it was the epoch of incredulity, it was the season of light, it was the season of darkness, it was the spring of hope, it was the winter of despair.
Set in the time of the French revolution with all its hopes and brutality and horrors
A time of enlightenment, rationality, revival, and John and Charles Wesley
We see all of these things, into this world comes the great affirmation of John's Gospel
Donald Rumsfeld and his unknown unknowns
&quot;Reports that say that something hasn't happened are always interesting to me, because as we know, there are known knowns; there are things we know we know. We also know there are known unknowns; that is to say we know there are some things we do not know. But there are also unknown unknowns—the ones we don't know we don't know. And if one looks throughout the history of our country and other free countries, it is the latter category that tends to be the difficult ones.&quot;
Today there are many people who don't know God but they also don't know that they don't know Him.  Not a judgement, merely a statement of many people in the western world

49:51 - Hymn 395 - No one has ever seen God 
Time for quiet reflection and prayers for the world 

Offering the gifts of this last year and our lives for God’s work ahead – please stand for the Prayer of Dedication
Eternal God we come to you now 
 to offer the praise of our lips 
 and the service of our lives.
 We recommit ourselves 
 to walk the way of Jesus, 
 to seek your will for our lives and for our world.
 Unite us as one body in Christ, renew us by your Spirit, 
 that we may be true channels of your love and peace,
 through Jesus Christ our Saviour and Friend.  Amen.

57:02 - Song Jesu be the centre MP 1076 

59:15 - Communion: we invite you to share in the bread and wine at church (or at home) united in the name of Christ.

A Prayer of thanksgiving with the response
We thank you Lord of life And praise your holy name
Lord’s Prayer 

01:06:44 - Closing Prayer

01:07:45 - Song 603  Lord for the years

01:11:26 - 01:11:44 - Blessing

01:12:20 - 01:12:32 - Organ Music</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="46"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:i1kSlP8EYUo</id>
  <yt:videoId>i1kSlP8EYUo</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 26th December 2021 - Boxing Day</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=i1kSlP8EYUo"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2021-12-26T09:45:01+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-03-01T00:36:15+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 26th December 2021 - Boxing Day</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/i1kSlP8EYUo?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/i1kSlP8EYUo/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Welcome to our Boxing Day service.  You can use the links below to skip to other parts of the service


00:00 - Music before worship and photos

18:04 - Welcome and Prayer

19:09 - Carol - Infant holy Engage worship

21:32 - Introduction…
….One boxing day a couple of years ago, I shut down the computer, ignored all my unread books and set up a lego railway set in the study – this was the result


23:02 - ….One of the carols linked to today is Good King Wenceslas – which takes up that theme of compassion and service.  It’s a great carol to sing outside on a frosty day.  It ends with the words
Therefore, Christian folk, be sure
Wealth or rank possessing
You who now will bless the poor
Shall yourselves find blessing.
26:31 - Carol - Good King Wenceslas (Official Music Video) 

29:14 - Intro to reading

32:09 - Reading: Colossians 3:12-17 The Message 

33:36 - Prayer
Lord’s Prayer
36:44 - 37:11 - Blessing

37:15 - Hymn - From heaven you came
42:03 - Carols from the RGS Carol Concert - Choir and Brass Ensemble from All  Saints Church, recorded on 14th December 2020.  https://www.rgshw.com/news/?pid=3&amp;nid=1&amp;storyid=228 with  grateful thanks 
42:03 - Once in Royal David’s City 
46:49 - Hark! The Herald Angels Sing 
50:12 - O Come, All Ye Faithful 
53:38 - O Little Town of Bethlehem 
56:47 - Unto us is Born a Son

#JoyToTheWorld
#BoxingDay
#OneCanTrust
#WycombeHomelessConnection
#RGSHW
#Christmas
#Lego
#SwitchOffTheTV
https://onecantrust.org.uk/
https://twitter.com/rgshw</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="30"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:1_KB-Tm9YnM</id>
  <yt:videoId>1_KB-Tm9YnM</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship - Saturday 25th December 2021 - Christmas Day</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1_KB-Tm9YnM"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2021-12-25T10:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2021-12-25T10:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship - Saturday 25th December 2021 - Christmas Day</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/1_KB-Tm9YnM?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/1_KB-Tm9YnM/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Welcome to our Christmas Day service.  You can use the links below to skip to other parts of the service

00:00 - Music before worship and photos

18:04 - Welcome / Introduction

19:45 - Hymn - O come all ye faithful Engage Worship Video

23:10 - Advent candles (film of Cores End)

23:52 - Prayer

Intro of video Unto us produced Christian Vision). It’s a modern-day account of the nativity, filmed and produced to be like a contemporary TV drama.  And after that we’ll hear the story from Luke’s Gospel – read by the Sparks family

26:02 - Video Unto Us

30:38 - 32:43 - Reading Luke 2. 1 – 20 

32:49 - Hymn - Once in Royal Engage worship Video

36:51 - Prayers
Lord’s Prayer

40:16 - 40:44 - Blessing

41:05 - Song - On Christmas Day Engage worship

45:50 - Carols from the RGS Carol Concert - Choir and Brass Ensemble from All  Saints Church, recorded on 14th December 2020.  https://www.rgshw.com/news/?pid=3&amp;nid=1&amp;storyid=228 with  grateful thanks 
45:50 -    Once in Royal David’s City 
53:58 -    Hark! The Herald Angels Sing 
53:59 -    O Come, All Ye Faithful 
57:15 -    O Little Town of Bethlehem 
01:00:33 -    Unto us is Born a Son

#Christmas
#JoyToTheWorld
#OneCanTrust
#RGSHW
#SwitchOffTheTV
#OpeningPresents
#WycombeHomelessConnection

https://twitter.com/rgshw
https://onecantrust.org.uk/</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="1" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="30"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:gl0IcgpVQh4</id>
  <yt:videoId>gl0IcgpVQh4</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Worship - Sunday, 19th  December 2021 - Carols with Candlelight</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gl0IcgpVQh4"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2021-12-19T17:18:39+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-01-18T20:39:45+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Worship - Sunday, 19th  December 2021 - Carols with Candlelight</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/gl0IcgpVQh4?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/gl0IcgpVQh4/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00.00  Photos and music before service

Welcome given by a church elder, Angus Massie

Call to worship led by the minister, Terry Hinks

Carol: O come all ye faithful [on screen or R&amp;S 160 vs 1-5]

Lighting of the Advent Candles

Song: Christ our light (Tune: Frere Jacques unaccompanied)
Christ our light, Christ our light,
light our lives.
We’ll be lights to others.
Light our lives.
Prayer

1 st Bible Reading: Isaiah 40: 1 – 5 and 9 Ian Bogart

Carol: It came upon a midnight clear [on screen or R&amp;S 144]

2 nd Bible Reading: Luke 1: 26 – 38 Norma Garden

Worship Song ‘Adore’ by Chris Tomlin (video)

3 rd Bible Reading: Luke 2: 1–7 (Good News) Zion Ogbewe

Carol: See him lying on a bed of straw [on screen or R&amp;S 151]
led by Worship Group

Reading: ‘Mary looks into the eyes of Jesus’ Lesley Bogart

Carol: Silent night [on screen or R&amp;S 147]
Reading: ‘Silent night’ Elaysa Ogbewe

4 th Bible Reading: Luke 2: 8 – 20 Alan Yates

Reflection: ‘changed lives’

Worship Song ‘Emmanuel’ [on screen]

5 th Bible Reading: Matthew 2: 1 – 12 Richard Harding

Introducing our Christmas charity Embrace the Middle East (video)

Carol: In the bleak mid winter [on screen or R&amp;S 162]

Reading: ‘Holy Child’ Abigail Lokko

Prayers of intercession
Lord’s Prayer

All: Our Father, who art in heaven,
hallowed be thy name;
thy kingdom come; thy will be done;
on earth as it is in heaven.
Give us this day our daily bread.
And forgive us our trespasses,
as we forgive those who trespass against us.
And lead us not into temptation;
but deliver us from evil.
For thine is the kingdom,
the power, and the glory,
for ever and ever. Amen.

Carol: Hark! the herald angels sing [on screen or R&amp;S 159]

Minister: Blessing
All say: Amen.

Please stand as the Bible is taken out of church
Organ Voluntary: Organ Sonata No 1 - Alexandre Guilmant</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="47"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:eEshnx8Kjj0</id>
  <yt:videoId>eEshnx8Kjj0</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 12th  December 2021</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eEshnx8Kjj0"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2021-12-12T11:45:08+00:00</published>
  <updated>2021-12-17T08:50:42+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 12th  December 2021</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/eEshnx8Kjj0?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/eEshnx8Kjj0/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00.00  Photos and music before service

07:55 - Welcome and lighting of peace candle (an elder)
09:33 - Call to worship 
With hearts changed by love,
with lives shaped by grace,
with relationships braced by integrity,
and with the blessing of the Holy Spirit upon us,
come as you are and as you hope to be
to worship the Lord of Advent. Amen.

10:40 - Hymn R&amp;S 134 On Jordan’s Banks the Baptist’s cry Tune: 537 Winchester new

13:00 - Opening Prayers

16:15 - Theme Introduction
Joy - not much of it around at the moment?
What might we be joyful about?
Printer paper being available
It's warmer
The fact we can still gather in person
A great view on a run
Thinking about what we can do to make others happy
Sharing a meal
Listening

21:05 - 21:45 - Prayer

21:47 - Lighting three candles on Advent crown

Let all who take refuge in God rejoice;
let them ever sing for joy. 

The candles are lit.
Jesus is the light of the world. 
A light no darkness can ever put out.
Will we be able to celebrate with our families this Christmas

23:10 - Song R&amp;S 522 From heaven you came, helpless babe

28:26 - 29:27 - Reading: Philippians 4.4-7 read by Aurelia Awuku

4 Rejoice in the Lord always. I will say it again: rejoice! 5 Let your gentleness be evident to all. The Lord is near. 6 Do not be anxious about anything, but in every situation, by prayer and petition, with thanksgiving, present your requests to God. 7 And the peace of God, which transcends all understanding, will guard your hearts and your minds in Christ Jesus.

30:15 - Song R&amp;S 286 Rejoice in the Lord always (as a round)

33:26 - 36:01 - Reading:  Luke 3.7-18 read by Alan Yates

7 John said to the crowds coming out to be baptised by him, ‘You brood of vipers! Who warned you to flee from the coming wrath? 8 Produce fruit in keeping with repentance. And do not begin to say to yourselves, “We have Abraham as our father.” For I tell you that out of these stones God can raise up children for Abraham. 9 The axe has been laid to the root of the trees, and every tree that does not produce good fruit will be cut down and thrown into the fire.’
10 ‘What should we do then?’ the crowd asked.
11 John answered, ‘Anyone who has two shirts should share with the one who has none, and anyone who has food should do the same.’
12 Even tax collectors came to be baptised. ‘Teacher,’ they asked, ‘what should we do?’
13 ‘Don’t collect any more than you are required to,’ he told them.
14 Then some soldiers asked him, ‘And what should we do?’

He replied, ‘Don’t extort money and don’t accuse people falsely – be content with your pay.’
15 The people were waiting expectantly and were all wondering in their hearts if John might possibly be the Messiah. 16 John answered them all, ‘I baptise you with[b] water. But one who is more powerful than I will come, the straps of whose sandals I am not worthy to untie. He will baptise you with[c] the Holy Spirit and fire. 17 His winnowing fork is in his hand to clear his threshing-floor and to gather the wheat into his barn, but he will burn up the chaff with unquenchable fire.’ 18 And with many other words John exhorted the people and proclaimed the good news to them.

37:07 - Hymn R&amp;S 200 The kingdom of God Tune: (ii) Out Skerries

38:47 - 56:50 - Sermon What then should we do?
Here we are this morning hopefully alive and well.
Recent news of the meteor the size of the Eiffel tower skimming past the earth
Context is important though as it passed 2.4 million miles away
The gospel reading leaves us with an image of the sandwich board stating &quot;The end is nigh&quot;
If that's good news, what does bad news look like
Repentance is the foundation of the new kingdom
He who is faithful and just will forgive us of our sins
Repentance is about building a better world
Government parties around Christmas 2020 whilst the rest of the country was under restrictions
Saying sorry and resigning does show a level of repentance
When we get it wrong we need to hold up our hands and say sorry
Just saying sorry isn't the same as repentance
&quot;Turn around where possible&quot; from our sat-nav when we make a mistake

56:52 - Hymn MP 806 Beauty for brokenness

01:03:04 - Prayers of Intercession
Closing Prayers 

01:08:43 - Hymn R&amp;S 574 Go forth and tell Tune: 740 Woodlands

01:11:30 - 01:12:09 - Blessing

01:12:40 - 01:15:30 - Organ voluntary</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="28"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
</feed>
