<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns:yt="http://www.youtube.com/xml/schemas/2015" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 <link rel="self" href="http://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=PLrggWHcy3azrunmSfTCSlS5JRuB4zTgCY"/>
 <id>yt:playlist:PLrggWHcy3azrunmSfTCSlS5JRuB4zTgCY</id>
 <yt:playlistId>PLrggWHcy3azrunmSfTCSlS5JRuB4zTgCY</yt:playlistId>
 <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
 <title>Worship services - Trinity and Cores End URCs</title>
 <author>
  <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
  <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
 </author>
 <published>2020-04-04T11:11:34+00:00</published>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:RtiFdvJ1hBU</id>
  <yt:videoId>RtiFdvJ1hBU</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 23rd July 2023</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RtiFdvJ1hBU"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2023-07-23T22:48:41+00:00</published>
  <updated>2023-07-26T21:52:00+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 23rd July 2023</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/RtiFdvJ1hBU?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/RtiFdvJ1hBU/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00 - Opening music, photos, and notices - 

03:56 - Entry of the Bible

00:04:18 - Welcome and lighting of peace candle (Duty Elder)

00:06:16 - Call to worship - Matthew 6: 31&amp;33

00:06:52 - 00:10:22 - HYMN - R&amp;S 104 – Praise, my soul, the King of heaven

10:30 - 17:21 - Opening Prayer and Lord's Prayer

17:29 - 20:34 - Reading: Matthew 13:31-33, 44-50

20:42 - 29:58 - Talk for all ages – The kingdom of God
The kingdom of God is not a place, club or building.
It is a personal encounter with God through prayer, listening and obedience.
We experience the kingdom when we are in communion with God.
When we listen and obey God, we experience more of the kingdom.
The kingdom is defined by God's perfect love.
The kingdom seems beyond limits of time.
We can feel far from God and the kingdom when life is hard.
But God's love remains through good and bad times.
The Lord's Prayer says the kingdom comes when God's will is done on earth.
As we follow God's will, we experience more of the kingdom.

The kingdom of God is not a physical place, but rather a personal encounter with God through prayer, diligent listening and obedience. We experience the kingdom when we are in full communion with the Lord, truly listening and following His will. The more we listen and obey, the more we live in the kingdom. God's perfect love defines the kingdom, which seems beyond earthly limits of time. Though we can feel far from God when life gets hard, His love remains constant. The kingdom comes when God's will is done on earth, as the Lord's Prayer says. As we seek and follow the will of God in our lives, we come to know the kingdom in a real and personal way.


00:30:27 - 00:33:09 - HYMN - R&amp;S 141 – Make way, make way

00:33:11 - 37:07 - Reading: Romans 8: 31-39

00:37:54 - 40:24 - HYMN: R&amp;S 200 – The kingdom of God is justice and joy

00:40:28 - 00:53:39 - Address: The Kingdom of God. followed by a time of quiet reflection
Why do people come to church?  The promise of eternal life is not a motivating factor.
The kingdom of God is exciting but hard to grasp
Jesus told parables to describe the kingdom
The kingdom starts small but grows large
It changes us with just a small presence
The kingdom is of greatest value
We must seek the kingdom like hidden treasure
It is for everyone, no one is excluded
God's perfect love defines the kingdom
The kingdom is beyond limits of time
We live the kingdom by following God's will
Jesus used parables to convey the kingdom of God, which begins humbly but grows to greatness. Though elusive, we must seek the kingdom like a treasure.  It holds supreme value and is defined by God's perfect love, extending to all people without limits of time. We live the kingdom by seeking and following God's will in our lives.

00:54:21 - 00:58:10 - HYMN - R&amp;S 107 – The love of God comes close

00:58:54 - 01:03:53 - Prayers for the church and the world

01:04:11 - 01:06:39 - HYMN - R&amp;S 293 – Ye servants of God

01:06:40 - 01:07:03 - Closing blessing

01:07:24 - 01:12:21 - Music, notices and photos after the service

01:12:39 - RIP John Standfield

#KingdomOfGod
#GodsLove
#SeekTheKingdom
#JesusParables
#AllAreWelcome

#Church #Worship #Sing #Organ #Faithful #Jesus #URC #UnitedReformedChurch  #Blessings #GoodNews #NIV #NIVUK #Bible #Lessons #GoodNews #Hymns #AllAreWelcome #JoinIn #Christian

#Revelation #AlphaAndOmega #BookOfRevelation #WhatDoesItAllMean</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="21"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:XE4V8KXvOAs</id>
  <yt:videoId>XE4V8KXvOAs</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 16th July 2023</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XE4V8KXvOAs"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2023-07-16T23:00:17+00:00</published>
  <updated>2023-07-28T21:37:27+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 16th July 2023</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/XE4V8KXvOAs?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/XE4V8KXvOAs/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00 - Opening music, photos, and notices - 

03:52 - Entry of the bible

04:04 - Welcome and lighting of peace candle (Duty Elder)

06:00 - Call to worship
This is the day that the LORD has made;
we will rejoice and be glad in it.
It is good to give thanks to the Lord
For God’s love endures for ever.

06:38 - Hymn - R&amp;S 377 This is the day, this is the day

09:09 - 10:11 - Opening Prayer

10:15 - 17:15 - Introduction and reading 

10:15 - Introduction to reading – a glimpse of heaven

14:45 - Reading: Revelation 4 (Good News)


18:15 - 21:32 - Song - MP 1040 Come now is the time to worship

21:38 - Activity: ‘flight of praise’

31:11 - WORSHIP SONGS led by Praise Group
MP 883 Lord I lift your name on high
MP454 Majesty, worship His Majesty

37:39 - 45:45 - Short Talk: ‘Numbers and symbols’
The sermon reflects on the imagery in Revelation, especially the four &quot;heavenly creatures&quot; repr esenting all creation worshiping God, and the image of Jesus as a sacrificed lamb. The preacher discusses how Revelation reveals the glory and majesty of God.
Revelation is a visionary book filled with symbolic imagery and numbers.
It reveals God's heavenly perspective on history and current events.
The four &quot;heavenly creatures&quot; may represent the heights of creation - lion, ox, eagle, human.
They are also linked to the four Gospel writers - lion for Mark, human for Matthew, ox for Luke, eagle for John.
Numbers like 4, 7, and 12 have symbolic meaning coming from the Old Testament.
Revelation portrays heaven as a place of continuous worship with God at the center.
Jesus is portrayed as a sacrificed lamb, showing he conquered through self-sacrifice.
The slain lamb is worthy to open the scroll of God's plans.
The creatures and elders in heaven continually worship God and the lamb.
Revelation invites Christians on earth to join in the heavenly worship and praise of God.
The Book of Revelation uses vivid symbolic imagery and numbers, like the number 7 representing completeness, to reveal God's majestic heavenly realm, where the four wondrous creatures representing all of creation along with the twenty-four elders continually worship the Lord Almighty. At the center of this glorious worship stands the sacrificed Lamb, Jesus Christ, who is worthy to fulfill God's eternal plans. By portraying this awe-inspiring scene of ongoing praise in heaven, Revelation invites Christians on earth to envision ourselves participating in this eternal worship, caught up in wonder and awe of our magnificent, loving Creator and Redeemer. As we join in praise of God and the Lamb, we align our lives to their purposes and participate here and now in the cosmic worship that continues forever around God's throne.

46:27 - 49:43 - Hymn - R&amp;S 34 Holy, holy, holy

49:52 - Recap: Bible Project Video on Revelation 1 – 5

57:17 - 58:05 - Reading: Revelation 5 (NIVUK) read by David and Valerie
11 Then I looked and heard the voice of many angels, numbering
thousands upon thousands, and ten thousand times ten thousand. They
encircled the throne and the living creatures and the elders. 12 In a loud
voice they were saying:
‘Worthy is the Lamb, who was slain,
to receive power and wealth and wisdom and strength
and honour and glory and praise!’
13 Then I heard every creature in heaven and on earth and under the
earth and on the sea, and all that is in them, saying:
‘To him who sits on the throne and to the Lamb
be praise and honour and glory and power,
for ever and ever!’ AMEN.

58:10 - Music from Handel’s Messiah ‘Worthy is the Lamb’

01:02:13 - 01:09:13 - Prayers for the church today – 7 lights – with response
Lord of life shine your light.
Lord’s Prayer (Modern version)

01:10:02 - 01:12:28 - Hymn R&amp;S 666 Sing we the song

01:12:29 - 01:13:10 - Final prayer and Blessing

01:13:25 - 01:16:30 - Music, notices and photos after the service

#RevelationRevealed #RevelationExplained

#Church #Worship #Sing #Organ #Faithful #Jesus #URC #UnitedReformedChurch  #Blessings #GoodNews #NIV #NIVUK #Bible #Lessons #GoodNews #Hymns #AllAreWelcome #JoinIn #Christian

#Revelation #AlphaAndOmega #BookOfRevelation #WhatDoesItAllMean

#Revelation #HeavenlyWorship #PraiseGod #ChurchService #SundayService #BibleStudy #Sermon #BookOfRevelation #JesusLambOfGod #SacrificedLamb #EternalWorship #CosmicPraise #FourCreatures #24Elders #SymbolicImagery #HeavenlyRealm #GodsMajesty #GodsGlory #JoinInPraise #ContinualWorship</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="17"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:3-zSoCRNxHM</id>
  <yt:videoId>3-zSoCRNxHM</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 9th July 2023</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3-zSoCRNxHM"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2023-07-09T22:56:26+00:00</published>
  <updated>2023-07-18T22:27:05+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 9th July 2023</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/3-zSoCRNxHM?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/3-zSoCRNxHM/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00 - Opening music, photos, and notices - 

05:26 - Entry of the Bible

05:27 - Welcome and lighting of the peace candle

08:33 - Call to worship

09:29 - 13:33 - Hymn -  RS 195 I danced in the morning [Tune: Shaker tune]

13:42 - 16:23 - Opening Prayers
Lord’s Prayer

16:51 - 24:10 - Talk for all ages
Rebekah in the bible
Rebekah was the wife of Isaac in the Bible.
Isaac was the son of Abraham, one of the patriarchs of the Hebrew nation.
Abraham wanted Isaac to marry someone who worshipped the one true God, not the pagan gods of Canaan.
Abraham sent his servant to find a wife for Isaac from his relatives in Haran.
The servant met Rebekah at a well and she offered him water.
The servant told Rebekah she was chosen to marry Isaac. She agreed to go with him.
Rebekah left her family and traveled to Canaan to marry Isaac.
At the time, Abraham's family still worshipped pagan idols.
Abraham wanted to protect Isaac from pagan influence with his marriage.
Rebekah bravely and faithfully left her home to marry Isaac, revealing her trust in God's plan.
Even though Abraham's own family were still worshipping idols, Rebekah had such strong faith that she left her home and family behind. She set off on a long journey to the foreign land of Canaan to marry a man she had never met. Rebekah’s story shows remarkable trust in God and willingness to follow His plan, even when it required great courage and sacrifice on her part. She truly inspires us to have faith and follow God’s calling in our own lives today.

24:57 - 26:15 - Hymn R&amp;S 197 Jesus’ hands were kind hands
[Tune: Au clair de la lune]

26:40 - Offering Prayer (a collection is not taken up, but there are
bowls for any donations and many give by standing order – we
offer all our gifts – time, talents and money – to God).

Shared blessing with Junior Church
Adults: May the Lord be with you
Junior Church: And also with you. AMEN.

27:18 - 35:32 - Bible Readings:
28:06 - Genesis 24:34-38, 42-49, 58-67 NIVUK read by Rosemary Taylor
33:34 - 35:32 - Matthew 11:16-19, 25-30 NIVUK read by Larry Ogbewe

35:50 - 38:08 - HYMN RS 558 Will you come and follow me?
[Tune: Kelvingrove]

38:18 - 52:44 - Sermon
Finding out about God
The Old Testament shows gradual revelation of God over time.
The New Testament revelation through Jesus was fuller.
We don't know for certain if Jesus said the words in Matthew about no one knowing the Father except the Son.
The Gospels were written long after Jesus' life.
Matthew, as a disciple, likely remembered Jesus' important teachings.
Jesus reveals God to the marginalized, not the arrogant.
Matthew passage shows Jesus' frustration at people missing his message.
Genesis shows early stages of understanding God.
We must be humble and open to ongoing revelation, not arrogant about our knowledge.
In today’s sermon, we explore the theme of “Finding Out About God.” 
How the Old Testament shows a gradual revelation of God unfolding over many years. Contrast this to the time of Jesus, when we see fuller revelation of God’s nature and purpose. 
Now the Gospels were written decades after Jesus lived, so we can’t be certain he actually spoke the words in Matthew about no one knowing the Father except the Son. But as a disciple, Matthew likely remembered Jesus’ most important teachings. The passage shows Jesus’ frustration that people were missing his message about God’s love and salvation. Jesus reveals God to the poor and marginalized, not the arrogant. Going back to Genesis, we see the early stages of humanity just beginning to understand who God is. For us today, the lesson is that we must remain humble and open to ongoing revelation of God through Christ. We must not become arrogant or think we have perfect knowledge already. May we keep seeking God with childlike faith, wonder and curiosity.

53:11 - 56:45 - HYMN RS 579 Lord, thy Church on earth is seeking
[Tune: Abbots Leigh]

56:54 - 01:01:09 - Prayers of intercession

01:01:35 - 01:04:41 - HYMN RS 349 I heard the voice of Jesus say
[Tune: Kingsfold]

01:04:47 - 01:05:27 - Final prayer and Blessing

01:05:48 - 01:14:30 - Music, notices and photos after the service

#Church #Worship #Sing #Organ #Faithful #Jesus #URC #UnitedReformedChurch  #Blessings #GoodNews #NIV #NIVUK #Bible #Lessons #GoodNews #Hymns #AllAreWelcome #JoinIn #Christian

#Revelation #AlphaAndOmega #BookOfRevelation</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="15"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:-B9w2IkYxg4</id>
  <yt:videoId>-B9w2IkYxg4</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 2nd July 2023</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-B9w2IkYxg4"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2023-07-02T22:55:48+00:00</published>
  <updated>2023-07-05T09:09:54+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 2nd July 2023</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/-B9w2IkYxg4?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/-B9w2IkYxg4/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00 - Opening music, photos, and notices - 

04:25 - Entry of the Bible

04:38 - Welcome and lighting of the peace candle

06:55 - Call to worship  (Psalm 117)
All of you nations, come praise the Lord!
Let everyone praise our Gracious God.
God's love is wonderful; God’s faithfulness never ends.
Shout praises to the Lord!

07:30 -Hymn - R&amp;S 261  At the name of Jesus (Tune Camberwell)

10:34 - 12:47 - Opening Prayers 

12:50 - 25:00 - All age Talk: ‘Beginning and ending, alpha and omega’ 
The theme of beginnings and endings, both in life and in literature.
Examples of beginnings and endings including new jobs, the start of the Premier League season, the flow of the Thames River, the story of Peter Rabbit, and the start of school holidays.
The Book of Revelation as a strange and often misunderstood book, but encourages exploration and finding the treasures within it.
The Book of Revelation is described as a record of events revealed by Jesus Christ to the servant John.
God is much bigger than our comprehension and is eternal.
Jesus Christ is described as the faithful Witness, the ruler of kings, and the one who loves and freed us from sin.
Don't misuse the Book of Revelation but engage in individual exploration rather than relying on external interpretations. In particular, don't just Google the book of revelation
Approach the book with bravery and listen to the Spirit speaking to them.

&quot;God is always bigger than our comprehension.&quot; 
&quot;The Book of Revelation: Find the treasures within.&quot;
&quot;Be brave enough to explore the Book of Revelation and hear the Spirit speaking to you.&quot; 

21:46 - Reading: Revelation 1. 1 – 8 (Good News)

25:41 - 28:04 - Song - MP 673  There is a redeemer

28:46 - 34:11 - Introduction to today’s readings
John as the #Spielberg of the Bible

29:55 - Reading: Revelation 1. 9 – 16 NIVUK read by Tony

31:39 - Reading: Revelation 3. 14 – 22 NIVUK read by Elsje

34:35 - 37:02 - Hymn - R&amp;S 405 Angel voices

37:10 - 49:54 - Short Address
The Book of Revelation can be challenging and bewildering, causing discomfort and fear for some readers.
There were debates in the early church about whether to include the Book of Revelation in the New Testament, but it ultimately became part of the Bible.
The book was written by John, who was exiled to the island of Patmos due to his witness, and it emerged from a context of persecution under the Roman Empire.
Revelation belongs to the apocalyptic genre, which contrasts earthly and heavenly life and speaks of a struggle between good and evil.
Violent imagery in Revelation should not be taken literally; at its core is Jesus, who sacrificed himself for humanity.
The book begins with letters to seven churches, including the church of Laodicea, which is criticized for its complacency and lukewarm faith.
Jesus is portrayed as knocking on the door of the Laodicean church, urging them to open their hearts and let him in.
The invitation to open the door symbolizes a personal and intimate relationship with Jesus.
The book invites readers to open their hearts, minds, spirits, and lives to the loving Lord, who offers forgiveness, purpose, and love.

&quot;Do not panic. If you don't warm to the Book of Revelation, you're in good company.&quot;
&quot;Be patient with the book; it's full of imagery. It isn't a description of reality as such; it was a vision that came to John in the context of worship.&quot;
&quot;Here I am, I stand at the door and knock. If anyone hears my voice and opens the door, I will come in and eat with them and they with me.&quot;



50:31 - 51:34 - Hymn - R&amp;S 308  Spirit of the Living God

51:38 - 57:22 - Welcome of Valerie and Stephen into church membership by reaffirmation:

57:43 - 58:48 - Hymn - R&amp;S 309  Spirit of the Living God

58:59 - 01:09:10 - Communion: we invite you to share in the bread and wine at church (or at home) united in the name of Christ.

A Prayer of thanksgiving and Lord’s Prayer

Distribution of bread and wine (in church non-alcoholic grape juice)

01:09:17 - 01:11:36 - Closing Prayer

01:12:09 - 01:15:23 - Hymn - R&amp;S 262  Crown him with many crowns

01:15:24 - 01:15:58 - Blessing (based on Revelation 1.5,6 and 22.21)
Jesus Christ loves us, and by his sacrificial death he has freed us from our sins 6 and made us a kingdom of priests to serve his God and Father. To Jesus Christ be the glory and power forever and ever!  And the grace of the Lord Jesus be with us and all people today and for evermore.  Amen.

01:16:21 - 01:18:38 - Music, notices and photos after the service

#Church #Worship #Sing #Organ #Faithful #Jesus #URC #UnitedReformedChurch  #Blessings #GoodNews #NIV #NIVUK #Bible #Lessons #GoodNews #Hymns #AllAreWelcome #JoinIn #Christian

#Revelation #AlphaAndOmega #BookOfRevelation</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="10"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:5Nk3v0j0FnQ</id>
  <yt:videoId>5Nk3v0j0FnQ</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 25th June 2023</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5Nk3v0j0FnQ"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2023-06-25T22:59:51+00:00</published>
  <updated>2023-06-30T13:06:08+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 25th June 2023</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/5Nk3v0j0FnQ?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/5Nk3v0j0FnQ/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00 - Opening music, photos, and notices - 

07:47 - Entry of the bible

08:31 - Welcome and lighting of peace candle (an elder)

09:56 - Call to worship

11:43 - 13:20 - Hymn: O breath of life come sweeping through us (R&amp;amp;S 302) Tune: Spiritus Vitae

13:30 - Opening Prayers and the Lord’s Prayer

17:00 - 21:24 - Hymn: I the Lord of sea and sky

21:37 - Blessing as Junior Church go to their activities:
Adults: May the Lord be with you
Junior Church: And also with you.
All: Amen.

22:20 - Prayer before the readings

22:42 - 35:06 - Bible Readings

22:42 - Introduction to Bible readings

24:53 - Reading: Genesis 18: 1-15, and 21: 1-7
read by Sue Thorne

32:06 - 35:06 - Reading: Matthew 9: 35-38 and 10: 1-8
read by John Hillson

35:24 - 37:42 - Hymn: To Abraham and Sarah the call of God was clear (R&amp;S 553) Tune: Mountain Christians

37:55 - 51:37 - Sermon: followed by time of quiet reflection
3 key words: visitors, hospitality, compassion
The scriptures highlight the theme of visitors and hospitality, starting with Abraham and Sarah encountering three visitors in Genesis.
People in the Bible are constantly on the move, encountering new situations and meeting strangers, emphasizing the theme of journeys and travel.
Change and unexpected circumstances can disrupt and transform our lives, whether by our own choices, actions of others, sickness, suffering, or blessings.
God is found amidst our wanderings and encounters, often visiting us in surprising and unrecognized ways, delivering blessings beyond our imagination.
Jesus is the ultimate visitor, entering fully into human life, teaching, healing, and showing compassion to those in need, revealing God's new way of being with us.
Jesus' presence transcends time and space through his death, resurrection, and Ascension, making his home forever with us.
Suffering and need are prevalent in the world, and amidst these realities, the stories of Abraham, Sarah, and Jesus offer hope, compassion, and love.
God invites people to join in the work of compassion and salvation, as seen in Abraham and Sarah being part of God's unfolding story and the disciples being commissioned and sent out.
The disciples' names and our own names are part of the ongoing story of God's saving and renewing all of creation, with unique callings and opportunities for each individual.
As we respond to God's call, we can be answers to prayer, revealing God's heart of compassion, seeking justice, and taking action, even if the laborers may seem few.
Welcoming people in need


52:00 - 54:14 - Hymn: Will you come and follow me? (R&amp;amp;S 558)
Tune: Kelvingrove

54:24 - 56:32 - Prayers for others and ourselves

56:39 - Prayer of thanksgiving for the offertory

57:13 - 01:00:38 - Hymn: Love divine, all loves excelling (R&amp;amp;S 663)
Tune Blaenwern

01:00:43 - 01:01:00 - Closing blessing

01:01:35 - 01:05:12 - Music, notices and photos after the service

#Church #Worship #Sing #Organ #Faithful #Jesus #URC #UnitedReformedChurch  #Blessings #GoodNews #NIV #NIVUK #Bible #Lessons #GoodNews #Hymns #AllAreWelcome #JoinIn #Christian #WarmSpace #WednesdayCafe #RejoiceandSing

 #compassion  #hospitality #refugees

#Rainbow #RainbowUmbrella #Umbrella #UmbrellaSky

#SummarisedWithChatGPT #ChatGPT #GoogleBARD #BARD #LLM</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="29"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:wde1MsJnXUk</id>
  <yt:videoId>wde1MsJnXUk</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 18th June 2023</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wde1MsJnXUk"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2023-06-19T00:04:58+00:00</published>
  <updated>2023-06-22T07:40:10+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 18th June 2023</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/wde1MsJnXUk?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/wde1MsJnXUk/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00 - Opening music, photos, and notices - 

08:08 - Entry of the bible

08:15 - Welcome and lighting of peace candle (an elder)

11:07 - Call to worship – Psalm 51 vs 1 - 3 &amp;amp; 10 - 12

12:12 - 15:44 - Hymn R&amp;S 47 O worship the King all glorious above

15:46 - Opening Prayers and the Lord’s Prayer

17:35 - Reading: 1 John Ch 3 vs 1 – 3

17:35 - 22:40 - Talk for all ages “What are you worth?”
God values you, you have worth, even if you have made mistakes.
God loves you so much that he gave his son for you.
Don't ever think that you have no value.
God sees you the way that Jesus sees you.
You are perfect in Christ.
You may be going through a tough time, but God still loves you.
God will exchange his son for you.
You are worth as much as God originally made you to be.
God is our heavenly father, and he is the shepherd who leads us.
Comparing a 10-pound note to a person's worth. Even if the note is wrinkled or damaged, it is still worth 10 pounds.

22:54 - Worship Song - The Lord’s my Shepherd I’ll not want
(Stuart Townend)

25:54 - Blessing as Junior Church go to their activities:
Adults: May the Lord be with you
Junior Church: And also with you.
All: Amen.

26:19 - 29:42 - Readings

26:19 - Introduction to Bible readings

26:56 - Readings: Psalm 116 vs 1, &amp;amp; 10 – 17
read by Arthur Winning

28:08 - Romans Ch 5 vs 1 – 8 read by Jeany Bien

30:52 - Hymn - How deep the Father’s love for us

34:31 - 56:18 - Address “God demonstrates His Love”
followed by time of quiet reflection
The sermon emphasizes that being a Christian is about what God has done through Jesus Christ, not our own actions or words.
Jesus was credited as righteous by God for paying the penalty of sin, even though he was without sin himself.
We cannot pay the debt of our sin ourselves; it requires a perfect sacrifice, which Jesus provided as the Lamb of God.
By putting our sins on Jesus and accepting him through faith, we are considered righteous in God's sight.
Through Jesus' death and resurrection, our sins have been paid for, and we are set free from the penalty of sin.
Faith is crucial in accepting this freedom and trusting in what Jesus and God have promised.
Our trust in God should not waver, even in the face of suffering, as it produces endurance, character, and hope.
God's love for us is demonstrated by Christ's death for sinners, even when we were still ungodly.
We are justified and have peace with God through faith, becoming his children and sharing in his glory.
Reading God's word helps us grow spiritually and deepen our faith, as it reveals the character and love of God.
Suffering should not discourage or deter believers from their faith, but rather it should be seen as an opportunity for spiritual growth and an occasion to deepen our trust in God


56:45 - 01:00:32 - Hymn - I know not why God’s wondrous grace

01:00:59 - 01:03:32 - Prayers for others and ourselves

01:03:52 - 01:05:50 - Hymn R&amp;S - 495 Father hear the prayer we offer

01:06:06 - 01:06:34 - Closing blessing

01:07:33 - 01:09:38 - Music and notices after the service

#Church #Worship #Sing #Organ #Faithful #Jesus #URC #UnitedReformedChurch  #Blessings #GoodNews #NIV #NIVUK #Bible #Lessons #GoodNews #Hymns #AllAreWelcome #JoinIn #Christian #WarmSpace #WednesdayCafe #RejoiceandSing #Compassion 

#Ashes #HowToWatchCricket #LeatherOnWillow 

#RIPJohnStandfield

#SummarisedWithChatGPT #ChatGPT #GoogleBARD #BARD #LLM</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="26"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:4COPBAjLCB4</id>
  <yt:videoId>4COPBAjLCB4</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 11th June 2023</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4COPBAjLCB4"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2023-06-11T23:01:29+00:00</published>
  <updated>2023-06-16T02:38:23+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 11th June 2023</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/4COPBAjLCB4?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/4COPBAjLCB4/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00 - Opening music, photos, and notices - 

08:39 - Entry of the bible

08:59 - Welcome and lighting of peace candle (an elder)

11:16 - Call to worship (based on words from Psalm 103)
Praise the Lord my soul;
with our inmost being we praise God’s holy name
Do not forget all God’s blessings,
the God who forgives our sins
heals our diseases, redeems our life;
and crowns us with love and compassion.

12:12 - Hymn - MP 1259 Bless the Lord O my soul

16:19 - Opening Prayers and the Lord’s Prayer
18:49 - 21:38 - Introduction for all ages by Joe Parton

21:53 - Hymn - TP 98 When I needed a neighbour?

Blessing as Junior Church go to their activities:
Adults: May the Lord be with you
Junior Church: And also with you.
All: Amen.

24:20 - Introduction to the readings

25:03 - 27:59 - Readings: Luke 10. 25 – 37 NIVUK read by Connie Bolfrey

28:27 - 29:40 - Matthew 21. 12 – 17 NIVUK
read by Rosemary Taylor

29:58 - Hymn R&amp;S 648 Jesu, Jesu, fill us with your love

32:39 - 01:01:58 - Talk by Joe Parton followed by time of quiet reflection
The two children sponsored by our church, Christian and Mary, and mentions that other individuals in the congregation also sponsor children.
Compassion is a child-focused, church-based charity with projects in 29 countries, providing resources to alleviate poverty for sponsored children and their families.
The charity is Christ-centered, providing scripture in the children's own language and introducing them to Jesus as their savior.
The sponsored children have the opportunity to attend a project at a local church, where they receive education, socialize with other children, and are protected from unnecessary child labor.
The impact of sponsorships including over 4,300 hours spent in projects, nearly 1,500 nutritious meals provided, 24 medical checkups, and eight scriptures given to the children.
The countries where the sponsored children reside are Africa, Central and South America.
Additional financial support and gifts given by the church with examples of how these gifts have made a significant difference in the lives of the sponsored children and their families.
The personal connection between sponsors and children key, as is the exchange of letters and the profound impact it has on both the children and sponsors. 
#CompassionUK

01:02:28 - 01:06:59 - Hymn - MP 806 Beauty for brokenness

01:07:16 - 01:11:09 - Prayers for others and ourselves
led by Rosemary Taylor
Lord in your great compassion
hear our prayer.

01:11:30 - 01:13:47 - Hymn R&amp;S 620 For the healing of the nations

01:14:18 - 01:14:36 - Closing blessing

01:15:30 - 01:16:55 - Music and notices after the service

#Church #Worship #Sing #Organ #Faithful #Jesus #URC #UnitedReformedChurch  #Blessings #GoodNews #NIV #NIVUK #Bible #Lessons #GoodNews #Hymns #AllAreWelcome #JoinIn #Christian #WarmSpace #WednesdayCafe #RejoiceandSing #Compassion 



#SummarisedWithChatGPT #ChatGPT #GoogleBARD #BARD #LLM</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="27"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:wUlqrumtCpw</id>
  <yt:videoId>wUlqrumtCpw</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 4th June 2023</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wUlqrumtCpw"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2023-06-04T23:45:04+00:00</published>
  <updated>2023-06-08T21:32:56+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 4th June 2023</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/wUlqrumtCpw?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/wUlqrumtCpw/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00 - Opening music, photos, and notices - 

08:17 - Entry of the Bible
08:34 - Welcome and lighting of peace candle (an elder)

10:30 - Call to worship
On this Trinity Sunday,
we come to worship our Eternal Glorious God:
Father, Son and Holy Spirit 
So the amazing grace of our Lord Jesus Christ,
the overwhelming love of God
and the friendship of the Holy Spirit
be with us now, as we offer our thanks and praise

11:33 - 13:46 - Hymn R&amp;S 30  Father we love you 

14:03 - Opening Prayers

17:05 - Song R&amp;S 8 - Glory to God (unaccompanied)

18:42 - 28:00 - Introduction and reading
18:42 - 25:26 - Introduction for all ages: ‘tired?’
Tiredness is a common experience for everyone, including children and adults.
Tiredness can be caused by various factors, such as physical exertion, work, boredom, or lack of sleep.
Rest and renewal are necessary for maintaining energy and motivation.
Isaiah describes God as the Everlasting One who never grows tired or weary.
Trusting in God can lead to renewed strength and spiritual vitality.
Those who rely on God for help will find their weaknesses uplifted and their strength restored.
The imagery of rising on wings like eagles symbolizes gaining a new perspective and transcending daily struggles.
Even though eagles may not be present in the local area, the concept of being lifted by a powerful bird can be inspiring.
God's ability to lift and carry us signifies the potential for divine support and guidance.
Reflecting on the image of a red kite soaring in the sky can remind us of God's capacity to uplift and renew us.

25:46 - 28:00 - Reading Isaiah 40:12-17,27-31 (Good News) read by Ian

28:08 - Prayer 

28:50 - 31:45 - Hymn TP 13  Be still for the presence
Shared blessing with Junior Church
Adults:  May the Lord be with you
Junior Church: And also with you. AMEN.
Introduction to reading – what a way to finish!

32:50 - Our 2023 Gospel focus 

35:16 - 36:20 - Reading: Matthew 28.16-20 (Good News) read by Norma

36:44 - 39:14 - Hymn TP 81- Spirit of God

39:24 - 51:04 - Short Address
Trinity Sunday marks the culmination of the Christian year, reflecting on the journey from Advent to Easter and beyond.
Our church is named Trinity Church, emphasizing the unity and diversity of God's nature.
The disciples worshiped Jesus, recognizing him as both truly human and divine.
Doubts and questions are allowed in the journey of faith, and there is room for sceptics within the church.
Jesus declares his authority over heaven and earth, bridging the divide between the divine and human realms.
The commission is given to spread the universal message of God's love to all people.
The message is for everyone - all backgrounds, all sexualities, all races, and all religions.
Baptism is a way to immerse people in the love of God and introduce them to the lifestyle of following Jesus.
Learning and obedience are essential in deepening our understanding of what it means to follow Jesus.
Jesus promises to be with us always, even though unseen, and provides tangible signs of his presence in the sacraments.
The worship concludes with gratitude and assurance that Jesus is with us until the end of the age.

51:14 - Prayer for the world, the church and for ourselves

53:02 - 56:36 - Hymn TP 48  Jesus calls us

56:34 - Communion: we invite you to share in the bread and wine at church (or at home) united in the name of Christ.

A Prayer of thanksgiving
Lift up your hearts. 
We lift them to the Lord. 
Let us give thanks to the Lord our God. 
It is right to give our thanks and praise.
(Minister continues the prayer)
…For all these gifts we thank you, and we join with all your people on earth and in heaven, in joyful praise:

Holy, holy, holy Lord, God of power and might, heaven and earth are full of your glory. Hosanna in the highest. Blessed is he who comes in the name of the Lord. Hosanna in the highest.
(minister completes the prayer)

01:01:30 - Lord’s Prayer (traditional version)

01:07:41 - 01:12:10 - Closing Prayer and prayers for the world with response
Lord in your mercy
hear our prayer

01:12:32 - 01:15:03 - Hymn R&amp;S 38  Thou whose almighty word

01:15:04 - 01:15:30 - Blessing

01:16:20 - 01:19:40 - Music and notices after the service

#Church #Worship #Sing #Organ #Faithful #Jesus #URC #UnitedReformedChurch  #Blessings #GoodNews #NIV #NIVUK #Bible #Lessons #GoodNews #Hymns #AllAreWelcome #JoinIn #Christian #WarmSpace #WednesdayCafe #RejoiceandSing #Compassion 

#TrinitySunday #Communion #RedKite #Eagles #GreatCommission

#SummarisedWithChatGPT #ChatGPT #GoogleBARD #BARD #LLM</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="18"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:n-IudW5yYNk</id>
  <yt:videoId>n-IudW5yYNk</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 28th May 2023</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=n-IudW5yYNk"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2023-05-28T23:04:48+00:00</published>
  <updated>2023-06-13T00:59:23+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 28th May 2023</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/n-IudW5yYNk?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/n-IudW5yYNk/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00 - Opening music, photos, and notices - 

08:39 - Welcome and lighting of peace candle (an elder)

11:40 - Call to worship

12:18 - 14:17 - Hymn - R&amp;S 302 – O breath of life

14:39 - 16:09 - Reading: Psalm 104:24-34, 35b NIVUK
read by Lesley Bogart

24 How many are your works, LORD!
    In wisdom you made them all;
    the earth is full of your creatures.
25  There is the sea, vast and spacious,
    teeming with creatures beyond number –
    living things both large and small.
26  There the ships go to and fro,
    and Leviathan, which you formed to frolic there.
27  All creatures look to you
    to give them their food at the proper time.
28  When you give it to them,
    they gather it up;
when you open your hand,
    they are satisfied with good things.
29  When you hide your face,

    they are terrified;
when you take away their breath,
    they die and return to the dust.
30  When you send your Spirit,
    they are created,
    and you renew the face of the ground.
31  May the glory of the LORD endure for ever;
    may the LORD rejoice in his works –
32  he who looks at the earth, and it trembles,
    who touches the mountains, and they smoke.
33  I will sing to the LORD all my life;
    I will sing praise to my God as long as I live.
34  May my meditation be pleasing to him,
    as I rejoice in the LORD.
35b  Praise the LORD, my soul.
Praise the LORD.

16:21 - Opening Prayers and the Lord’s Prayer

20:27 - 23:18 - Hymn R&amp;S 310 – Gracious Spirit

23:23 - 30:12 - Talk for all ages - Looking forward to Pentecost?
Pentecost or Whit Sunday was a highly anticipated and cherished event 
The whole city of Sheffield, regardless of religious affiliation, looked forward to this occasion. 
The churches in different areas would come together, accompanied by uniformed groups and bands, to march in a procession towards the park for celebrations. 
The event included singing, pageantry, and the crowning of a queen. 
It was a significant and joyful gathering that brought people together to celebrate something meaningful to everyone involved. 
Reflecting on the nostalgia and the sense of community and togetherness that characterized the event


30:25 - Blessing as Junior Church go to their activities:
Adults: May the Lord be with you
Junior Church: And also with you
All: Amen

31:00 - 34:20 - Reading: Acts 2: 1-21 NIVUK read by Ian Bogart

35:04 - 38:21 - Hymn R&amp;S 489 – Be Thou my vision

38:29 - 56:57 - Sermon followed by time of quiet reflection
&quot;Welcoming Each Wonder&quot; by Tom Gordon.
A boy named Nathan and his questions about God.
Nathan asks his grandmother about what God is like and how he can be present even though he can't be seen.
His grandmother uses the analogy of soap slipping out of one's hands to explain the presence of God.
Nathan realizes that God, like the soap, can disappear but always comes back.
The story highlights the idea that God is always there, even if we can't see Him, and we just know when He is present.
The work of Wycliffe Bible translators and the importance of translating the Bible into native languages.
The story encourages sharing our experience of God in a language that others can understand.
A reminder that the spirit of God is always speaking to us, even if we may not always be listening.

57:36 - 01:00:47 - Hymn - R&amp;S 373 – Lord Jesus Christ

01:00:52 - 01:08:31 - Prayers for others and ourselves

01:08:51 - 01:12:48 - Hymn - R&amp;S 576 – God’s Spirit is in my heart

01:12:49 - 01:13:13 - Closing blessing

01:13:41 - 01:16:32 - Organ music after the service 

01:16:46 - RIP Martin Drake 1950-2023

#Church #Worship #Sing #Organ #Faithful #Jesus #URC #UnitedReformedChurch  #Blessings #GoodNews #NIV #NIVUK #Bible #Lessons #GoodNews #Hymns #AllAreWelcome #JoinIn #Christian #WarmSpace #WednesdayCafe #RejoiceandSing #Compassion 

#PrayForTurkey #PrayForUkraine #PrayForPeace

#Pentecost #Sheffield #ChurchesTogether #Frogfest 

#RIPMartinDrake

#SummarisedWithChatGPT #ChatGPT #GoogleBARD #BARD #LLM</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="25"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:4A9SZdqnBbk</id>
  <yt:videoId>4A9SZdqnBbk</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 21st May 2023</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4A9SZdqnBbk"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2023-05-21T22:49:45+00:00</published>
  <updated>2023-06-14T17:39:14+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 21st May 2023</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/4A9SZdqnBbk?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/4A9SZdqnBbk/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00 - Opening music, photos, and notices - 

05:32 - Welcome and lighting of peace candle (an elder)

07:03 - Call to worship 
Clap your hands, all you peoples. 
Shout to God with songs of joy.
God has gone up with a shout. 
Sing praises to the most high.
God is ruler over all the Earth. 
We worship God with all our heart.

07:52 - 10:46 - Hymn MP 77  Christ triumphant ever reigning 
(Tune Guiting Power)

10:53 - 13:31 - Opening Prayer 

13:38 - 25:30 - Introduction for all ages: ‘Watch the world!’
Christian Aid week officially ended yesterday.
Some information about Christian Aid's current work.
There will be a film about Esther and an introduction to pigeon peas.
Pigeon peas biscuits are being offered at a local shop.
Christian Aid connects with people across the world through their work and the products consumed.
Television and YouTube provide opportunities to connect with other nations.
The speaker asks if anyone watches TV programs from abroad or foreign language programs.
Some people enjoy watching skiing and the Grand Prix.
&quot;Professor T&quot; and &quot;The Big Bang Theory&quot; as examples of foreign shows.
A film from Malawi is coming up, highlighting the friendly people and the country's reputation as the heart of Africa.

18:59 - Video: ‘Esther’s story’ https://youtu.be/A8hDdi37DLg 

26:01 - 26:38 - Reading: Matthew 13.31-34 read by Samuel Evans
31 Jesus told them another parable: “The Kingdom of heaven is like this. A man takes a mustard seed and sows it in his field. 32 It is the smallest of all seeds, but when it grows up, it is the biggest of all plants. It becomes a tree, so that birds come and make their nests in its branches.”
33 Jesus told them still another parable: “The Kingdom of heaven is 
like this. A woman takes some yeast and mixes it with a bushel of flour until the whole batch of dough rises.”

26:45 - A Recipe prayer 

31:18 - 33:40 - Hymn TP 98  When I needed a neighbour

34:04 - 43:32 - Reading and seated hymn
34:04 - Introduction to the reading

35:43 - Hymn R&amp;S 595i Sometimes a light (verse 1 only) seated
Reading: Joel 1:10-12 read by Tony Hatton
Pause for reflection – sing R&amp;S 595i verse 2
Reading: Joel 2.18-23 read by Tony Hatton
Pause for reflection – sing R&amp;S 595i verse 3
Reading: Joel 2.24-29 read by Hatton
Pause for reflection sing R&amp;S 595i verse 4

43:38 - 46:58 - Short Talk – when things are hard, don’t despair 
The reading starts with a sense of doom and uncertainty but shifts to a hopeful and merciful atmosphere.
Gardening and growing things can be challenging, with pests and diseases causing frustration.
The reaction of destroying pests has had a negative impact on the climate and land.
The reading emphasizes the need for balance in personal lives and in the world.
God is portrayed as being present and assuring that everything will be well.
Joelle encourages the fields and animals to rejoice and not be afraid.
The reading concludes with the promise of God pouring out His spirit on His people.
The anticipation of Pentecost and the words of Joel being spoken by Peter
The promise of God's spirit leading through difficult times and towards a new world
The text calls for openness to the spirit and the renewal of the Earth.

47:13 - 50:10 - Hymn - R &amp;S 264  He is Lord, he is Lord 

50:13 - 51:24 - Reading: Matthew 13.1-9 read by Elsje Hatton

51:29 - Talk and Activity: what do you want to see grow?  
    • In your garden / terrace / living room
    • Among your family 
    • In your local community (Wycombe and beyond)
    • Across the world

01:01:30 - 01:04:10 - Hymn - Jesus Christ is waiting 
(Tune R&amp;S 243 Noel Nouvelet)

01:04:24 - 01:07:07 - Prayer for the world and for ourselves
Lord’s Prayer (modern version)

01:07:43 - 01:09:13 - Hymn - R&amp;S 415  You shall go out with joy (sung twice)

01:09:14 - Silent thanksgiving followed by a prayer for Martin Drake, sadly missed

01:10:05 - 01:10:57 - Blessing
Go into the world working together for change so that everyone can thrive and share life in its fullness.
And in all we do let us show the love of Jesus.
Let us treat everyone with dignity. 
We will show the love of Jesus.
Let us stand up for equality. 
We will show the love of Jesus.
Let us work and pray for justice. 
We will show the love of Jesus.
May the God of hope bless you, 
and fill you with all joy and peace in believing, 
so that you may overflow with hope 
by the power of the Holy Spirit.
Amen.

01:11:24 - 01:13:06 - Organ music after the service 

#Church #Worship #Sing #Organ #Faithful #Jesus #URC #UnitedReformedChurch  #Blessings #GoodNews #NIV #NIVUK #Bible #Lessons #GoodNews #Hymns #AllAreWelcome #JoinIn #Christian #WarmSpace #WednesdayCafe #RejoiceandSing #Compassion 

#PrayForTurkey #PrayForUkraine #PrayForPeace

#PigeonPeas #ChristianAid #ChristianAidWeek #WhatsOnTV #WhatHaveYouWatched #BigBangTheory #ProfessorT #GiroDItalia


#SummarisedWithChatGPT #ChatGPT #GoogleBARD #BARD #LLM</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="27"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:EiHYzt5PtZI</id>
  <yt:videoId>EiHYzt5PtZI</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 14th May 2023</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EiHYzt5PtZI"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2023-05-14T23:07:12+00:00</published>
  <updated>2023-06-09T07:03:12+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 14th May 2023</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/EiHYzt5PtZI?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/EiHYzt5PtZI/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00 - Opening music, photos, and notices - 

00:11 - 06:25 - All age Talk:  Forgiveness
The theme of the service is forgiveness and renewal.
Sharing their thoughts on forgiveness.
Forgiveness is explained as apologizing to someone after being rude and them forgiving you.
Examples of situations that require forgiveness are discussed, such as being hurt or having something damaged.
Forgiveness is acknowledged as a difficult process, both for individuals and for God.
The reading from Zechariah in the Old Testament illustrates God's forgiveness towards the Israelite people after their exile in Babylon.
The Lord's Prayer emphasises the importance of forgiving others as we ask for God's forgiveness.
Humans are not deserving of God's forgiveness, but God's mercy allows for forgiveness when we recognize our mistakes and are truly sorry.
The challenge of genuinely being sorry when seeking forgiveness.
The significance of forgiveness in the service's theme of forgiveness and renewal.

06:51 - 09:02 - Hymn - Praise and thanksgiving    
[Tune: Bunessan (Morning has broken)]

09:11 - Dedication of the offertory

10:40 - Introduction to today’s readings
11:15 - 13:51 - Reading:   Zechariah 8 v1-13 
14:35 - 16:34 - Reading:   Revelation 21 &amp; 22 vv1-5 

17:00 - 18:51 - Hymn - In Christ there is no east or west
[Tune: St Bernard] 

18:57 - 33:44 - Sermon
The prophet Zechariah, along with Ezra and Nehemiah, facilitated the rebuilding of the Jerusalem Temple after the Jews' return from Exile in Babylon.
The temple rebuilding was delayed due to local politics and opposition from the Northern Kingdom of Israel and the Persian king Atasurpses.
After 20 years, the people were reminded of their identity as God's chosen people and were motivated to rebuild the temple.
The prophet Zechariah announces God's word and emphasizes the urgency for action and restoration.
God promises to restore safety and good fortune to the people of Jerusalem, bringing peace and blessings.
Despite ongoing challenges and injustices in the world, God remains present and offers salvation through Jesus Christ.
The Book of Revelation, written by John, provides encouragement to the persecuted Christians and reassurance of God's ultimate purpose.
Accepting the Water of Life offered by Jesus symbolizes spiritual sustenance and eternal life.
The teachings from these ancient texts remind us of the unchanging nature of human beings, God's faithfulness, and the opportunity for personal restoration and renewal through forgiveness and faith.
The world is characterized by difficulties, inequalities, injustices, and the actions of bossy, greedy individuals who cause harm to others.
Through embracing the teachings and life of Jesus Christ, individuals can experience personal restoration, renewal, and have their names written in the book of the Lamb.

34:07 - 37:34 - Hymn - Lord, thy Church on earth is seeking
[Tune: Abbots Leigh]

37:58 - 42:05 - Prayers of intercession

42:31 - 45:17 - Hymn - There’s wideness in God’s mercy
[Tune: Sussex]

45:27 - 46:10 - Final prayer and Benediction

46:52 - 49:11 - Organ music after the service 

#Church #Worship #Sing #Organ #Faithful #Jesus #URC #UnitedReformedChurch  #Blessings #GoodNews #NIV #NIVUK #Bible #Lessons #GoodNews #Hymns #AllAreWelcome #JoinIn #Christian #WarmSpace #WednesdayCafe #RejoiceandSing #Compassion #Lent 

#PrayForTurkey #PrayForUkraine #PrayForPeace

#Forgiveness


#SummarisedWithChatGPT #ChatGPT #GoogleBARD #BARD #LLM</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="15"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:F7l-Hq-J4Y0</id>
  <yt:videoId>F7l-Hq-J4Y0</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 7th May 2023</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=F7l-Hq-J4Y0"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2023-05-07T22:40:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2023-06-10T23:20:45+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 7th May 2023</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/F7l-Hq-J4Y0?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/F7l-Hq-J4Y0/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00 - Opening music, photos, and notices - 

09:47 - Entry of Bible (please stand if you are able)

10:01 - Welcome and lighting of peace candle (Duty Elder)

12:03 - Call to worship (inspired by Psalm 31)
Christ is our rock, our fortress,
who leads us and guides us.
Therefore let us be strong;
let our hearts take courage,
for the Lord has rescued and saved us.
Thanks be to God.

12:32 - 14:38 - HYMN R&amp;S 469 - As we are gathered, Jesus is here (x2)

14:40 - Opening Prayers 

16:45 - 27:10 - All age Talk: ‘The day after the Coronation’ 
Did anyone watch or attend the coronation.
Past coronations, including that of King George and Queen Mary in 1911.
There are two women alive who were born around the time of the 1911 coronation.
My granddaughter slept through the recent coronation.
Many people watched the coronation of King George VI in 1937 and Queen Elizabeth II in 1953.
The history of the monarchy and the republic in England.
Memories of the recent coronation and what was special about it.
The horses, lifeguards, and mounties in the coronation procession.
Christian Aid week and the importance of ordinary people in making a difference.
Everyone is important to God, not just VIPs.

27:46 - 29:05 - NATIONAL ANTHEM God save the gracious King R&amp;S 762
God save our gracious King!
Long live our noble King!
God save the King!
Send him victorious,
Happy and glorious,
Long to reign over us,
God save the King!
Thy choicest gifts in store
On him be pleased to pour,
Long may he reign.
May he defend our laws,
And ever give us cause,
To sing with heart and voice,
God save the King!

Shared blessing with Junior Church
Adults:  May the Lord be with you
Junior Church: And also with you. AMEN.

29:10 - 30:32 - Introduction to today’s readings

30:38 - 32:46 - Reading: 1 Peter 2.2 – 10 NIVUK read by Abigail Lokko 

33:10 - 34:31 - HYMN R&amp;S 264 He is Lord he is Lord (vs 1 and 2) sung seated

34:49 - 36:18 - Reading John 14. 1 – 10 (The Message) Linda Curley

36:26 - HYMN R&amp;S 264 He is Life (vs 3 and 4) sung seated

37:54 - 46:53 - Short Address
Different people in the church have varying reactions to the coronation ceremony.
Some appreciate the colorful uniforms, vestments, and rituals, while others prefer something simpler.
There is a mix of emotions, including discomfort when the ritual becomes disconnected from Jesus on the cross.
King Charles, like any human being, experienced nervousness and anxiety during the anointing.
The greater truth of the ceremony is that Jesus is exalted above all, and every knee should bow to him.
The readings draw us into the wonder of who Jesus is and how he brings us to the Divine reality.
&quot;God Save the King&quot; reminds us that we all need saving, and God has a part to play in our nation.
King Charles has a representative role that goes beyond politics and arguments.
The speaker hopes that King Charles will preserve the nation's laws and diversity.
The letter of Peter reminds us to draw spiritual sustenance from God's love.
The sharing of the Lord's Supper reminds us that we all need sustenance and to draw close to God.
We carry burdens on our shoulders, but we can come to God's table to be sustained.
The Lord is good, and we can taste that goodness and carry it with us.
All the time, God is good, and we can draw close to Jesus to experience his goodness.

46:57 - 51:51 - Prayers for the world, our nation and each other
Lord in your mercy  hear our prayer.

52:19 - 54:50 - HYMN R&amp;S 474  Brother, sister

54:53 - Communion: we invite you to share in the bread and wine at church (or at home) united in the name of Christ.
A Prayer of thanksgiving and Lord’s Prayer

58:23 - Distribution of bread and wine (non-alcoholic grape juice)

01:03:59 - Closing Prayer
ALL  Lord Jesus, we thank you for the gifts 
we have shared at your table;
and the love you have poured into our hearts.
We thank you for the nation, of which we are 
Part, and the peace and freedom we enjoy.
We thank for the promise of your kingdom,
where justice, truth and compassion 
will flow like a mighty river.
Use our praying and living, this and everyday
for the work of Jesus, here and now,
caring, healing and restoring our world.  Amen.

01:04:53 - 01:08:31 - HYMN R&amp;S 603  Lord for the years

01:08:31 - 01:09:07 - Blessing

01:09:35 - 01:12:07 - Organ music after the service 


#Church #Worship #Sing #Organ #Faithful #Jesus #URC #UnitedReformedChurch  #Blessings #GoodNews #NIV #NIVUK #Bible #Lessons #King #GoodNews #Hymns #AllAreWelcome #JoinIn #Christian #WarmSpace #WednesdayCafe #RejoiceandSing #Compassion #Lent 

#PrayForTurkey #PrayForUkraine #PrayForPeace

#Coronation #KingCharles #KCIII #TheMall #BuckinghamPalace #StateCoach #EveryoneIsAVIPToGod


#SummarisedWithChatGPT #ChatGPT #GoogleBARD #BARD #LLM</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="1" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="40"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:9Rse1hT7pkA</id>
  <yt:videoId>9Rse1hT7pkA</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 30th April 2023</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9Rse1hT7pkA"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2023-04-30T23:22:49+00:00</published>
  <updated>2023-06-16T15:14:52+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 30th April 2023</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/9Rse1hT7pkA?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/9Rse1hT7pkA/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00 - Opening music, photos, and notices - 

09:13 - Entry of the Bible  

09:17 - Welcome and lighting of peace candle

10:45 - Call to worship
Shout for joy to the LORD, all the earth.
Worship the LORD with gladness;
Come before God with joyful songs.
Know that the LORD is God.
It is God who made us, and we are his; ;
we are God’s people, the sheep of his pasture.
Enter God’s gates with thanksgiving
and his courts with praise;
Give thanks to God and praise his name.
God’s love endures forever.

11:31 - 13:15 - Hymn - I will enter his gates (sung twice)

13:23 - Opening Prayers and the Lord’s Prayer

15:46 - 24:54 - Introduction for all ages: ‘Recognise that voice?’
Missing Easter at Trinity due to scheduling conflicts.
During Good Friday, the church had stations of prayer, including one titled &quot;The Buried Grain,&quot; where people were invited to plant a pinch of seed into a tray of soil.
This links to the Bible verse where Jesus compares his death to a buried grain that produces new life.
The speaker sees the growth of the planted seeds as a symbol of Jesus' love within us, reverberating down the centuries and producing fruit in the lives of billions of people.
The Bee Squared program (https://zeroch.org/bee-squared/) that encourages people to plant wildflowers to support bees and other insects crucial to life.
Jesus is referred to as the Good Shepherd and the gateway to God's loving presence.
Jesus' sheep recognize and trust his voice, and the speaker asks the audience to think of a voice they trust, like Mary Berry's recipe or Winston Churchill's wartime speeches.
There are many voices out there today, and the speaker urges the audience to choose which voices they trust.


Reading: John 10.1 – 10 NIVUK read by Kitty 

27:49 - Prayer
Lord you are the Way – help us to follow.
You are the truth – help us to listen.
You are the Life – refresh our lives today. Amen.

28:24 - 30:23 - Hymn - Jesus stand among us

30:44 - 31:33 - Reading: Psalm 23 NIVUK read by Kate 

31:41 - 39:44 - Meditation on the 23 rd Psalm – ‘being a follower of the Good
Shepherd’ (using Stuart Townend sung version MP 1008)
Sing verse 1
Leader: Let us think about how Jesus leads us in times past
and in the present time. (pause) Let us think about the life
Jesus offers us, life in abundance.
(pause, then sing the chorus)
Sing verse 2
Leader: Let us think about and receive again the inner peace
offered by Jesus. (pause) Let us think about and receive again
the contentment Jesus offers.
(pause, then sing the chorus)
Sing verse 3
Leader: Let us think about Jesus’ presence in difficult times
holding before him our troubles and concerns. (pause) Let us
think about drawing closer to Jesus and receiving his love and
protection from harm.
(pause, then sing the chorus)

40:21 - 41:26 - Reading: John 10.11 – 16 NIVUK read by Kitty

42:06 - 43:17 - Hymn The King of love vs 1 and 6 only -sung seated

43:54 - 56:30 - Address
The Great &quot;I ams&quot;
Jesus describes himself as &quot;I am&quot; seven times in John's Gospel.
Each description (&quot;I am the Good Shepherd,&quot; &quot;I am the bread of life,&quot; etc.) takes us into the heart of who Jesus is.
&quot;I am&quot; is not just a personal description but echoes God's words to Moses in the desert.
In John's Gospel, &quot;I am&quot; is linked to the fundamentals of life.
The Shepherd lies down in front of the entrance and protects the sheep through the night.
This intimate picture of the Shepherd is full of trust and care.
Jesus is the Good Shepherd who knows us through and through and wants to protect and keep us safe.
The Gate is the cross, where Jesus protects, leads, and opens up heaven and God's love to us.
Jesus is both the king of kings and the outcast, the one who is poor and rejected.


56:44 - 58:33 - Hymn- All heaven declares

58:41 - 01:05:55 - Prayers for the world with the response
God of truth and love,
bring them abundant life.

01:06:14 - 01:09:32 - Hymn - Christ is the King! O friends rejoice

01:09:33 - 01:09:58 - Closing blessing

01:10:25 - 01:14:32 - Organ music after the service 


#Church #Worship #Sing #Organ #Faithful #Jesus #URC #UnitedReformedChurch  #Blessings #GoodNews #NIV #NIVUK #Bible #Lessons #King #GoodNews #Hymns #AllAreWelcome #JoinIn #Christian #WarmSpace #WednesdayCafe #RejoiceandSing #Compassion #Lent 

#PrayForTurkey #PrayForUkraine #PrayForPeace

#Coronation #KingCharles #MissPiggy #KermitTheFrog #Eisenhower #MaryBerry


#SummarisedWithChatGPT #ChatGPT #GoogleBARD #BARD #LLM</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="26"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:iO26xjfuXTc</id>
  <yt:videoId>iO26xjfuXTc</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 23rd April 2023</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iO26xjfuXTc"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2023-04-23T22:32:26+00:00</published>
  <updated>2023-07-23T10:42:54+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 23rd April 2023</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/iO26xjfuXTc?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/iO26xjfuXTc/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>Opening music, photos, and notices - Missing in this stream

Entry of the Bible  - Missing in this stream

Welcome and lighting of peace candle (Duty Elder) - Missing in this stream

Call to worship Psalm 116:8-9 - Missing in this stream

Hymn: R&amp;amp;S 260 – Christ is alive! Let Christians sing (Tune: Truro) - Missing in this stream

Opening Prayers of Approach, Thanksgiving, Confession &amp; Praise, and the Lord’s Prayer - Missing in this stream

Introduction to the Bible reading - Missing in this stream

00:00:00 - Reading: Luke 24: 13-35 (CEV) 

02:05 - 04:00 - Talk for all ages
How long ago did you last play hide and seek?
Jesus walking with the disciples, hidden in plain sight.
Jesus was not noticed by the disciples when he was walking with them.
We can sometimes be so focused on our own problems that we don't see the miracles or the ordinary everyday things that are right in front of us.
We should pray that God will open our eyes and our hearts to see him in ways that we don't expect.

04:05 - 07:08 - Hymn: R&amp;S 234 Alleluia, alleluia, give thanks to the risen Lord (tune: Alleluia)

07:23 - Dedication of gifts

08:12 - Blessing as Junior Church go to their activities:
Adults: May the Lord be with you
Junior Church: And also with you
All: Amen

08:28 - Introduction to the Bible reading

09:20 - Reading: Acts 2:14-24, 37-42 (CEV) 

12:34 - 15:25 - Hymn: R&amp;S 354 Come Living God, when least expected (tune: Sunset)

15:35 - 22:13 - Talk: Expect the unexpected
followed by a time of quiet reflection
We all make plans
Sometimes plans don't go as expected.
It can be difficult to deal with unexpected events.
Faith in God can help us deal with unexpected events.
The story of the Road to Emmaus shows how Jesus can come alongside us in unexpected ways.
We should be open to expecting the unexpected.
We should pray for those who are struggling.
We should have faith in God, even when things don't go our way. The story of the Road to Emmaus shows how Jesus can come alongside us in unexpected ways, and give us hope when we are struggling. We should be grateful for God's presence in our lives, and pray for those who are struggling. We should renew our commitment to discipleship, and live our lives in a way that honors God.
Have faith in God, even when things don't go your way.

22:29 - 25:08 - Hymn: R&amp;S 590 – In heavenly love abiding (tune: Penlan)

25:25 - 27:29 - Prayers for others and ourselves led by Sue Thorne

27:53 - 30:19 - Hymn: R&amp;S 558 – Will you come and follow me (Tune: Kelvingrove)

30:25 - Time of silent prayer

33:32 - 33:49 - Closing blessing

34:18 - 38:07 - Music, notices, and photographs

#Church #Worship #Sing #Organ #Faithful #Jesus #URC #UnitedReformedChurch  #Blessings #GoodNews #NIV #NIVUK #Bible #Lessons #King #GoodNews #Hymns #AllAreWelcome #JoinIn #Christian #WarmSpace #WednesdayCafe #RejoiceandSing #Compassion #Lent 

#PrayForTurkey #PrayForUkraine #PrayForPeace

#Coronation #KingCharles #Daffodil #Quiche #ExpectTheUnexpected #BikeRide #A404 #Discipleship #Emmaus #RoadToEmmaus #MakePlans #HideAndSeek #HiddenInPlainSight


#SummarisedWithChatGPT #ChatGPT #GoogleBARD #BARD #LLM</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="35"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:8qNUKIsTAi4</id>
  <yt:videoId>8qNUKIsTAi4</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship - 16th April 2023</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8qNUKIsTAi4"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2023-04-16T22:21:33+00:00</published>
  <updated>2023-07-16T09:49:28+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship - 16th April 2023</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/8qNUKIsTAi4?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/8qNUKIsTAi4/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00:00 - Opening music, photos, and notices

06:32 - Entry of Bible 
06:44 - Welcome and lighting of peace candle (an elder)

08:13 - Call to worship 
This service will be like the TV program #ILiterallyJustToldYou

10:12 - 13:15 - Hymn - R&amp;S 74 - Praise to the Lord

13:20 - Opening Prayers
(prompt) Unlock our hearts to you, Lord.
(Response)  May we stop doubting and believe.

Lord’s Prayer

Introduction to the service

17:40 - 21:58 - Hymn - R&amp;S 258 - Saviour who exalted high

22:04 - Talk (part 1)
Who can remember the first word of the hymn we have just sung - #WeLiterallyJustSangIt

22:46 - 26:41 - Hymn - R&amp;S 499 - Have faith in God my heart


Introduction to Bible readings

28:20 - 29:55 - Reading: 1 Peter 1. v3-9 (Read by Sue )

30:36 - 33:02 - Hymn - R&amp;S 588 - Blest be the everlasting God)   

33:13 - 36:23 - Reading: John 20. v19-31 (Read by John)

36:36 - 41:04 - Talk (part 2)
The words &quot;faith&quot;, &quot;family&quot;, and &quot;staff&quot; to illustrate the importance of support.
A stick can help people get through muddy fields.
Workers support their bosses.
Music supports Charles so he knows what to play in what order.
In India, wooden sticks are used as scaffolding.
People need support in different ways.
We should all be there to support each other.

41:46 - 44:34 - Hymn - My Faith it is an oaken staff

45:00 - 46:19 - Prayers for others and ourselves

47:05 - 50:25 - Hymn - R&amp;S 244  - O sons &amp; daughters let us sing  -  v6 - 11   
(Tune - Victory - 250)    

50:26 - 51:01 - Closing blessing

#Church #Worship #Sing #Organ #Faithful #Jesus #URC #UnitedReformedChurch  #Blessings #GoodNews #NIV #NIVUK #Bible #Lessons #King #GoodNews #Hymns #AllAreWelcome #JoinIn #Christian #WarmSpace #WednesdayCafe #RejoiceandSing #Compassion #Lent 

#PrayForTurkey #PrayForUkraine #PrayForPeace

#PalmCrosses #PalmCross #Jerusalem #Donkey #PalmSunday #Hosanna #HolyWeek
#Easter #Faith #Salvation #Redemption #Savior #Blessings #Resurrection


#SummarisedWithChatGPT #ChatGPT #GoogleBARD #BARD #LLM</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="33"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
</feed>
