<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns:yt="http://www.youtube.com/xml/schemas/2015" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 <link rel="self" href="http://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=PLrggWHcy3azrunmSfTCSlS5JRuB4zTgCY"/>
 <id>yt:playlist:PLrggWHcy3azrunmSfTCSlS5JRuB4zTgCY</id>
 <yt:playlistId>PLrggWHcy3azrunmSfTCSlS5JRuB4zTgCY</yt:playlistId>
 <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
 <title>Worship services - Trinity and Cores End URCs</title>
 <author>
  <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
  <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
 </author>
 <published>2020-04-04T11:11:34+00:00</published>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:lCsGIi5eqSY</id>
  <yt:videoId>lCsGIi5eqSY</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship - 18th September Harvest 2022</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lCsGIi5eqSY"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-09-18T10:46:06+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-09-18T11:03:01+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship - 18th September Harvest 2022</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/lCsGIi5eqSY?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/lCsGIi5eqSY/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00:00 - Music before the service

Welcome, introduction and call to worship
HYMN  Praise and thanksgiving (R&amp;S 48)
Opening Prayer of thanksgiving 
For farms and fishing; carrots and combine harvesters:
We thank you, Lord of our lives.
For high street and superstore; checkout and debit card:
We thank you, Lord of our lives.
For commerce and industry; factory and workshop:
We thank you, Lord of our lives.
For college and school; teacher and pupil:
We thank you, Lord of our lives.
For police and firefighter; doctor and nurse:
We thank you, Lord of our lives.
For leisure and fun; recreation and sport:
We thank you, Lord of our lives.
For food and clothes; friendship and family:
We thank you, Lord of our lives.
For our nation and the people that inspire us
We thank you, Lord of our lives.
For this planet, this earth; all its life and creatures
We thank you, Lord of our lives.
For spiritual food; and the gift of your son:
We thank you, Lord of our lives.
For your kindness and love; and your plan for our lives:
We thank you, Lord of our lives.
in the name of Jesus.  Amen.
Introduction: ‘harvest links’
One Can Update 
Reading: Psalm 65. 1, 5-13 (CEV) read by Samuel Evans
SONG Our God is a great big God
Short Christian Aid Film: the Crisis in East Africa
Prayer for East Africa
Loving and compassionate God, 
When Famine stalks the land, nothing grows. 
Plants cannot, people cannot, ideas and dreams cannot  
everything withers and dies. 
It is a violent aberration of your will for the world 
and it is multiplied now by conflict, climate change and covid. 
God of the flourishing field, there is enough to feed us all. 
Call us to that sacred sharing, neighbour to global neighbour,  
your gifts of food, water, a chance to live the life 
so delicately crafted by your divine spirit. 
We will not turn away but turn towards each other 
with generosity and a justice-driven compassion 
that searches for solutions. 
Famine stalks the land, so may our outrage grow, 
may our determination steel itself, 
may our solidarity spur us into action. 
God of the flourishing field, help us feed each other.  Amen.
SONG Come all you people, come and praise your maker (video)
Uyai mose, tinamate mwari. (x3)
Uyai mose zvino.
Activity for children at back of church
Reading: Luke 12 8.1 – 9 read by Sarah Evans
13 Someone in the crowd said to him, ‘Teacher, tell my brother to divide the inheritance with me.’
14 Jesus replied, ‘Man, who appointed me a judge or an arbiter between you?’ 15 Then he said to them, ‘Watch out! Be on your guard against all kinds of greed; life does not consist in an abundance of possessions.’
16 And he told them this parable: ‘The ground of a certain rich man yielded an abundant harvest. 17 He thought to himself, “What shall I do? I have no place to store my crops.”
18 ‘Then he said, “This is what I’ll do. I will tear down my barns and build bigger ones, and there I will store my surplus grain. 19 And I’ll say to myself, ‘You have plenty of grain laid up for many years. Take life easy; eat, drink and be merry.’”
20 ‘But God said to him, “You fool! This very night your life will be demanded from you. Then who will get what you have prepared for yourself?”
21 ‘This is how it will be with whoever stores up things for themselves but is not rich towards God.’
SONG Give thanks with a grateful heart (MP 170)
Short Talk
HYMN   God whose farm is all creation (R&amp;S 612)
Offering of our gifts (symbolic gifts)
Prayers of intercession for the world 
Lord of all the harvest
Hear our prayer.
The Lord’s Prayer 
HYMN Fill your hearts with joy (MP 147)
Blessing</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="4"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:ItoLy-7NlBE</id>
  <yt:videoId>ItoLy-7NlBE</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship - 11th September 2022</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ItoLy-7NlBE"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-09-11T11:26:24+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-09-16T19:14:39+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship - 11th September 2022</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/ItoLy-7NlBE?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/ItoLy-7NlBE/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00:00 - Music before the service

00:12:40 Welcome and lighting of peace candle (an elder)

16:48 - Call to worship:

18:18 - Hymn - Our God our help in ages past R&amp;S 705

21:51 - Opening Prayer

24:07 - The Lord’s Prayer

25:20 - 27:17 - Reading: Luke 15 vv 1-10  read by Norma
Now the tax collectors and sinners were all gathering round to hear Jesus. 2 But the Pharisees and the teachers of the law muttered, ‘This man welcomes sinners, and eats with them.’
3 Then Jesus told them this parable: 4 ‘Suppose one of you has a hundred sheep and loses one of them. Doesn’t he leave the ninety-nine in the open country and go after the lost sheep until he finds it? 5 And when he finds it, he joyfully puts it on his shoulders 6 and goes home. Then he calls his friends and neighbours together and says, “Rejoice with me; I have found my lost sheep.” 7 I tell you that in the same way there will be more rejoicing in heaven over one sinner who repents than over ninety-nine righteous people who do not need to repent.
The parable of the lost coin
8 ‘Or suppose a woman has ten silver coins[a] and loses one. Doesn’t she light a lamp, sweep the house and search carefully until she finds it? 9 And when she finds it, she calls her friends and neighbours together and says, “Rejoice with me; I have found my lost coin.” 10 In the same way, I tell you, there is rejoicing in the presence of the angels of God over one sinner who repents.’

27:30 - Talk for All ages
I remember the chaplain coming to my last place of work
Misunderstanding the chaplain referring to us as a flock of sheep
Driving home from Wales one night and a sheep ran out into the side of the road.

Hymn: Brother sister let me serve you R&amp;S 474 


Reading: 1 Timothy 1  vv 12-17 read  by Alan
2 I thank Christ Jesus our Lord, who has given me strength, that he considered me trustworthy, appointing me to his service. 13 Even though I was once a blasphemer and a persecutor and a violent man, I was shown mercy because I acted in ignorance and unbelief. 14 The grace of our Lord was poured out on me abundantly, along with the faith and love that are in Christ Jesus.
15 Here is a trustworthy saying that deserves full acceptance: Christ Jesus came into the world to save sinners – of whom I am the worst. 16 But for that very reason I was shown mercy so that in me, the worst of sinners, Christ Jesus might display his immense patience as an example for those who would believe in him and receive eternal life. 17 Now to the King eternal, immortal, invisible, the only God, be honour and glory for ever and ever. Amen.


HYMN: The King of love my shepherd is  R&amp;S 552 

Sermon followed by time of quite reflection

HYMN: Eternal Father of the ceaseless round R&amp;S 623

Prayers of Intercession

Hymn: God is love let heaven adore Him R&amp;S 95</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="44"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:_6Fe9s_knLI</id>
  <yt:videoId>_6Fe9s_knLI</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 4th September 2022</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_6Fe9s_knLI"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-09-04T14:34:42+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-09-16T07:59:41+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 4th September 2022</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/_6Fe9s_knLI?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/_6Fe9s_knLI/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00 - Music and notices before the service

08:16 - Welcome and lighting of peace candle (an elder)

09:35 - Call to worship: from Psalm 33
The world belongs to the Lord,
the earth and all its creatures.
Let everything that has breath praise the Lord;
how good it is, to sing praises to our God.

10:24 - Hymn - R&amp;S 45  Morning has broken

12:20 - Opening Prayer 

13:34 - Introduction to Season of Creation for all ages: ‘Listen up!’
September sees the beginning of the season of creation
Celebrated across the world by people from all kinds of backgrounds
Christians in Pakistan suffering from floods 
Christians in East Africa suffering the worst drought in years
Christians in Germany meeting at the council of World Churches
Christians in Ukraine suffering from the invasion by Russia
The season begins on the 1st September and continues to the 4th October, St Francis's Day
This sense of relationship to the whole natural order goes back to the bible, one of the great Psalms speaks of creation which we will use now

15:53 - 17:35 - Reading: Psalm 19 
The heavens declare the glory of God; the skies proclaim the work of God’s hands. Day after day they pour forth speech; night after night they reveal knowledge. 
Listen to creation tell of God, listen to God’s Word today 
They have no speech, they use no words; no sound is heard from them. Yet their voice goes out into all the earth, their words to the ends of the world. 
Listen to creation tell of God, listen to God’s Word today
 The law of the LORD is perfect, refreshing the soul. The statutes of the LORD are trustworthy, making wise the simple. The precepts of the LORD are right, giving joy to the heart. 
Listen to creation tell of God, listen to God’s Word today 
The commands of the LORD are radiant, giving light to the eyes. The fear of the LORD is pure, enduring forever. The decrees of the LORD are firm, and all of them are righteous. 
Listen to creation tell of God, listen to God’s Word today

17:35 - 18:04 - Listening is the theme of this year's season of Creation

18:28 - Creation video #seasonofcreation 

23:30 - Prayer of lament with the response 
Lord in your mercy hear our prayer. 

26:01 - Song MP 545
Open our eyes Lord,
to see your creation,
to care for this planet,
the earth and its creatures.
Open our ears Lord
and help us to listen.
O open our eyes, Lord;
we want to love your world.

28:40 - Song Who put the colours in the rainbow? (JP 288)

31:14 - Introducing the readings

32:27 -35:01 - Reading: Exodus 3.1 – 12 (NIVUK) read by Ian Bogart

35:33 - Hymn -  R&amp;S 547  Moses I know you’re the man

39:50 - 41:15 - Reading: Mark 4:1-9 (Good News) read by Lesley Bogart

41:31 - 53:02 - Short Address: ‘Listen’
Geese flying over the house honking
Energy and the cost of living crisis leading to lots of honking from politicians at the moment
A call to listen is at the heart of our worship today
To listen to the world around us and to God's voice
Wordplay from Jesus in the parable &quot;If you have ears, listen&quot;
The natural world is sending strong messages to us as the human race - wake up, protect from damage, turn back from the climate crisis
Climate change first shown to be happening in 1939 but the message was delayed due to other events that year
We have to listen to each other, the world, and God
We have to protect His creation and liberating his people
May we listen and may we act in Jesus' name


53:04 - Profession of Faith 
We believe in God, the Source of all life, who creates all things, who embraces all things, who celebrates all things, who is present in every part of the fabric of creation, who is and baptises this planet with living water. 
We believe in Jesus Christ, the Seed of new life, who loves and cares for this world and who suffers with it and for it and came to reconcile and renew this world and everything in it. 
We believe in the Holy Spirit, the Breath of God, who moves among and with us today. 
We believe in everlasting life in God, the living hope that one day God will put an end to death and all destructive forces.
To the Living God, Trinity of Love, be all praise and glory, now and for evermore.  Amen.
(Gurukul Theological college, India - adapted)

54:22 - A Prayer for all creation

55:21 - Hymn - R&amp;S 327  O God, who’s love’s undying flame

58:02 - Communion: we invite you to share in the bread and wine at church (or at home) united in the name of Jesus Christ

A Prayer of thanksgiving and Lord’s Prayer 

01:01:25 - Distribution of Communion 

01:07:11 - Closing Prayer

01:10:54 - Hymn - R&amp;S 60  God who spoke at the beginning (Tune 344)

01:13:00 - 01:13:23 - Blessing 

01:13:58 - 01:16:51 - Music and notices after the service</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="9"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:z2NpOX_eWfc</id>
  <yt:videoId>z2NpOX_eWfc</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship - 21st August 2022</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=z2NpOX_eWfc"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-08-29T19:53:55+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-09-08T08:01:04+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship - 21st August 2022</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/z2NpOX_eWfc?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/z2NpOX_eWfc/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00:00 - Music before the service

11:50 - Welcome and lighting of peace candle (an elder)

13:43 - Call to worship (based on Isaiah 58.9)
Let us call out to God, and the LORD will answer;
Let us will cry for help, and God will say: ‘here I am.’

14:06 - Hymn R&amp;S 30 - Father we love you

16:42 - Opening Prayers with the response
We rejoice in your presence:
We give you thanks and praise.

Lord’s Prayer

20:55 - 27:33 - Introduction for all ages; ‘Awesome!’
What comes into your mind when you hear the word &quot;awesome&quot;? Teenagers maybe?
It's a word for us all
What do you find awesome? Or is the world so jaded we have lost our sense of awe?
Sunsets, nature, God, Tour de France riders
Awesome people: Skydivers, wheelchair racers at the Commonwealth Games, Malala Yousafzai
Awesome nature: Sunrise, sunset, mountains and lakes, giant redwoods, murmurations of starlings
Awesome universe: pictures from the James Webb telescope
Behind our awesome creation is the awesome reality we call God
God created all things, worthy of our worship

27:35 - Songs:
MP 1005 Our God is an awesome God
MP 242 Hosanna, hosanna

32:21 - Introducing the readings

33:45 - 34:30 - Reading: Psalm 103.1-8 NIVUK 
1  Praise the LORD, my soul;
    all my inmost being, praise his holy name.
2  Praise the LORD, my soul,
    and forget not all his benefits –
3  who forgives all your sins
    and heals all your diseases,
4  who redeems your life from the pit
    and crowns you with love and compassion,
5  who satisfies your desires with good things
    so that your youth is renewed like the eagle’s.
6  The LORD works righteousness
    and justice for all the oppressed.
7  He made known his ways to Moses,
    his deeds to the people of Israel:
8  the LORD is compassionate and gracious,
    slow to anger, abounding in love.

34:38 - 36:47 - Reading: Hebrews 12. 49 – 56
18  You have not come to a mountain that can be touched and that
is burning with fire; to darkness, gloom and storm;  19  to a trumpet
blast or to such a voice speaking words that those who heard it
begged that no further word be spoken to them,  20  because they
could not bear what was commanded: ‘If even an animal touches
the mountain, it must be stoned to death.’  21  The sight was so
terrifying that Moses said, ‘I am trembling with fear.’
22  But you have come to Mount Zion, to the city of the living God,
the heavenly Jerusalem. You have come to thousands upon
thousands of angels in joyful assembly,  23  to the church of the
firstborn, whose names are written in heaven. You have come to
God, the Judge of all, to the spirits of the righteous made
perfect,  24  to Jesus the mediator of a new covenant, and to the
sprinkled blood that speaks a better word than the blood of Abel.
25  See to it that you do not refuse him who speaks. If they did not
escape when they refused him who warned them on earth, how
much less will we, if we turn away from him who warns us from
heaven?  26  At that time his voice shook the earth, but now he has
promised, ‘Once more I will shake not only the earth but also the
heavens.’  27  The words ‘once more’ indicate the removing of what
can be shaken – that is, created things – so that what cannot be
shaken may remain.

28  Therefore, since we are receiving a kingdom that cannot be
shaken, let us be thankful, and so worship God acceptably with
reverence and awe,  29  for our ‘God is a consuming fire.’

37:05 - Hymn MP 50 - Be still for the presence of the Lord

41:03 - 53:28 - Address
What have we come to as we sit here or watch from home?
A building where people have gathered Sunday by Sunday for 122 years - almost 9000 Sundays!
A place where the service is uplifting, the music empowering, the preacher engaging?
A group of people yes, but also this awesome God
Political leaders come and go, wealth fades, athletic prowess diminishes, the world changes but at the heart of life, the one, unchanging God
The one revealed to Moses - &quot;I am who I am&quot;, the great &quot;I am&quot;
The giving of the law on Mount Sinai was an awesome moment
The writer to the Hebrews talks of Moses trembling in fear
The Old Testament speaks again and again of fear of God being the beginning of all wisdom
This God alone is worthy of worship
The consuming fire of love, the light that blazes and drives away corruption, wipes away hatred &amp; selfishness
This is the worship God accepts today. Worship that flows into action, driving how we live day to day
Let us take a moment to offer wonder, love, and praise to our awesome God.

53:30 - Silent reflection

53:57 - Offering Prayer for all our giving

54:28 - Hymn R&amp;S 583 The Church is wherever

56:25 - Prayers for others and ourselves

01:02:49 - Hymn R&amp;S 663 Love divine (1st tune Hyfrydol)

01:06:50 - 01:07:17 - Blessing

01:07:43 - 01:13:10 - Music and notices after the service</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="12"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:3hRL9cTjbXk</id>
  <yt:videoId>3hRL9cTjbXk</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship - 14th August 2022</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3hRL9cTjbXk"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-08-14T13:32:33+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-09-02T07:55:05+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship - 14th August 2022</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/3hRL9cTjbXk?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/3hRL9cTjbXk/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00:00 - Music before the service

09:46 - Welcome and lighting of peace candle (an elder)

12:56 - Call to worship

13:33 - HYMN - R&amp;S 117 O Lord, my God, when I in awesome wonder

19:00 - Opening Prayers and Lord’s Prayer

23:31 - 27:07 - Introduction for all ages
How many of you have one of these - an Apostle Spoon?
Whenever we visited an Aunt in childhood, a set of these would come out to look at
I bought a set of 6 many years ago, all but one disappeared now
They were originally given as gifts at the time of baptism as a symbol the person was a follower of Jesus or the hope that the child would become one
Made of solid silver but likely not any more
It reminds us that God is always close to hand if we follow Jesus

27:09 - Song MP 225 He’s got the whole wide world in His hands

29:12 - Introducing the readings

30:17 - Reading: Jeremiah 23. 23 – 29 NIVUK 
‘Am I only a God nearby,’ declares the LORD,
‘and not a God far away?
24  Who can hide in secret places
so that I cannot see them?’ declares the LORD.
 ‘Do not I fill heaven and earth?’ declares the LORD.
25  ‘I have heard what the prophets say who prophesy lies in my
name. They say, “I had a dream! I had a dream!”  26  How long will
this continue in the hearts of these lying prophets, who prophesy
the delusions of their own minds?  27  They think the dreams they
tell one another will make my people forget my name, just as their
ancestors forgot my name through Baal worship.  28  Let the prophet
who has a dream recount the dream, but let the one who has my

word speak it faithfully. For what has straw to do with grain?’
declares the LORD.  29  ‘Is not my word like fire,’ declares the LORD,
‘and like a hammer that breaks a rock in pieces?

31:40 - 32:55 - Reading: Luke 12. 49 – 56 
49  ‘I have come to bring fire on the earth, and how I wish it were
already kindled!  50  But I have a baptism to undergo, and what
constraint I am under until it is completed!  51  Do you think I came
to bring peace on earth? No, I tell you, but division.  52  From now on
there will be five in one family divided against each other, three
against two and two against three.  53  They will be divided, father
against son and son against father, mother against daughter and
daughter against mother, mother-in-law against daughter-in-law
and daughter-in-law against mother-in-law.’
54  He said to the crowd: ‘When you see a cloud rising in the west,
immediately you say, “It’s going to rain,” and it does.  55  And when
the south wind blows, you say, “It’s going to be hot,” and it
is.  56  Hypocrites! You know how to interpret the appearance of the
earth and the sky. How is it that you don’t know how to interpret
this present time?

33:09 - Hymn R&amp;S 317 Lord thy word, abideth

36:25 - 52:28 - Address
When have you had to face something you didn't like but knew was going to happen
Not knowing when or why, what were your emotions
This is what Jesus was feeling in the gospel reading from Luke 12
He doesn't welcome the idea of what will happen in Jerusalem but accepts it
Jeremiah says many people claim to speak from God but are false prophets
He says the community is awash with false information about God
Nowadays we hear a lot about fake news
Today in our lifetimes, the truth about God is often hidden 
God's word is a word of judgement that Jesus brings
Jeremiah says God's word is like a fire
What is God really like?
When our emotions are stirred, are they stirred by God or those around us?

Silent reflection

52:47 - Offering Prayer for all our giving

53:43 - Hymn R&amp;S 567 Thy hand, O God, has guided

57:05 - Prayers for others and ourselves

01:03:22 - Hymn - R&amp;S 373 Lord Jesus Christ, you have come to us

01:07:01 - 01:07:20 - Blessing

01:07:50 - 01:11:20 - Music and notices after the service</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="22"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:zlWz1gtDmPY</id>
  <yt:videoId>zlWz1gtDmPY</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 31st July led by Terry Hinks</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zlWz1gtDmPY"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-07-31T14:00:21+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-08-19T15:50:08+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 31st July led by Terry Hinks</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/zlWz1gtDmPY?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/zlWz1gtDmPY/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00:00 - Music and notices before the service 

09:24 - Welcome and lighting of peace candle (by an elder)

11:01 - Call to worship (based on Hebrews 10)
Let us come near to God with open hearts,
for Jesus has opened for us a new and living way.
Let us hold on firmly to the hope we profess,
because we can trust God to keep his promise. 
Let us be concerned for one another,
helping one another to show love and do good.
Let us come together and encourage each other,
more and more, as we follow Jesus here and now.


12:30 - Hymn - R&amp;S 102 Praise the Lord, his glories show

15:42 - Opening Prayers with responses
Lord have mercy: Lord have mercy.
Christ have mercy: Christ have mercy.
Lord have mercy: Lord have mercy.

19:08 - 27:30 - Introduction: a word from Lighthouse
What is Lighthouse?
When is it?
Where is it held?
Who is involved?
What do we do?
How can you help?

28:00 - Lighthouse Song (video)

32:43 - 34:18 - Reading: Psalm 98 NIVUK 

Sing to the LORD a new song,
    for he has done marvelous things;
his right hand and his holy arm have worked salvation for him.
2  The LORD has made his salvation known and revealed his righteousness to the nations.
3  He has remembered his love and his faithfulness to Israel;
all the ends of the earth have seen the salvation of our God.
4  Shout for joy to the LORD, all the earth, burst into jubilant song with music;
5  make music to the LORD with the harp, with the harp and the sound of singing,
6  with trumpets and the blast of the ram’s horn – shout for joy before the LORD, the King.
7  Let the sea resound, and everything in it, the world, and all who live in it.
8  Let the rivers clap their hands, let the mountains sing together for joy;
9  let them sing before the LORD, for he comes to judge the earth.
He will judge the world in righteousness and the peoples with equity.

36:31 - 38:24 - Reading: Hebrews 1. 1 – 8 NIVUK 
1 In the past God spoke to our ancestors through the prophets at many
times and in various ways,  2  but in these last days he has spoken to us by
his Son, whom he appointed heir of all things, and through whom also
he made the universe.  3  The Son is the radiance of God’s glory and the
exact representation of his being, sustaining all things by his powerful
word. After he had provided purification for sins, he sat down at the
right hand of the Majesty in heaven.  4  So he became as much superior to
the angels as the name he has inherited is superior to theirs.
5  For to which of the angels did God ever say,
‘You are my Son; today I have become your Father’?
Or again, ‘I will be his Father,  and he will be my Son’?
6  And again, when God brings his firstborn into the world, he says,
‘Let all God’s angels worship him.’
7  In speaking of the angels he says,

38:50 - 47:00 - Introducing the letter to the Hebrews (video)
47:04 - 47:57 - Summary of the reading and letter to the Hebrews

47:59 - Song: R&amp;S 271 You are the king of glory

50:42 - Prayer

51:10 - 52:07 - Reading Hebrews 4.14 – 16 NIVUK
14  Therefore, since we have a great high priest who has ascended into
heaven, Jesus the Son of God, let us hold firmly to the faith we
profess.  15  For we do not have a high priest who is unable to feel
sympathy for our weaknesses, but we have one who has been tempted
in every way, just as we are – yet he did not sin.  16  Let us then approach
God’s throne of grace with confidence, so that we may receive mercy
and find grace to help us in our time of need.

52:10 - 01:00:39 - Talk: ‘Hold on!’
&quot;Grace to help us in our time of need&quot;
As we look at the world right now, we see a time of great need
The Ukraine, China, Taiwan, The Other Western Nations, The Climate Emergency, Environmental Need, Displacement due to conflict, the refugee crisis, doubt in the democratic process as our government attempts to regain trust and integrity, the cost of living crisis: surely this is a time of need
But centuries ago these Jewish Christians, different to us in language, understandings, lifestyles. Think of their lives burdened by absolute poverty, unsure what persecution would arise in the brutal Roman Empire.  They were in a time of need.
Some questioned whether their faith was enough, some were slipping away
The writer challenges them to hold on to the precious gift of Jesus given to them
He was tempted but held on to his god even when all had deserted him
Draw close the writer says, don't turn back, hold fast and come with confidence to your saviour
Let the radiance of God's glory shine bright in your dark place and in the dark places of our world 

01:00:50 - Offering Prayer (of all our gifts – no collection is taken up)

01:01:41 - Song R&amp;S 375 In my life, Lord, be glorified

01:03:41 - Prayers for the church and the world with the response:
Great God, in your mercy
hear our prayer.

01:09:19 - Lord’s Prayer

01:10:08 - Hymn R&amp;S 598 Will your anchor hold?

01:15:10 - 01:15:35 - Blessing

01:16:17 - 01:20:58 - Music and Notices after the service</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="1" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="41"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:sgTLPqCTYcA</id>
  <yt:videoId>sgTLPqCTYcA</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 17th July led by Rev Terry Hinks</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sgTLPqCTYcA"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-07-17T13:15:55+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-09-08T07:47:32+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 17th July led by Rev Terry Hinks</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/sgTLPqCTYcA?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/sgTLPqCTYcA/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00:00 - Music and notices

07:21 - Welcome and lighting of peace candle (an elder)

08:57 - Call to worship (from Hebrews 13)

God has said, ‘Never will I leave you; never will I forsake you.’  
So we say with confidence,
‘The Lord is my helper; I will not be afraid. 
What can mere mortals do to me?
Jesus Christ is the same yesterday and today and for ever.
Therefore, through Jesus, let us continually offer to God 
a sacrifice of praise and not forget to do good 
and to share with others.

09:48 - Hymn: R&amp;S 377  This is the day!

12:32 - Opening Prayers with the response
It is good to give thanks to you, our God:
 your love endures for ever.

15:10 - 24:12 - Introduction: ‘Time!’
We make it or waste it
Where has the year gone?
Coming in 2 minutes early
Time to stay for refreshments afterwards
Watching the clock too much?
Images from the James Webb telescope, seeing images from things that happened thousands of years ago in the Southern Ring Nebula
8 minute for light from the sun to reach us
Do you have time?
Special thanks in this jubilee year for the URC, 50 years since the formation?
Lighthouse starting in 1987
Our sanctuary refurbished in 2009

24:52 - 26:41 - Reading: Psalm 145. 1 – 13 

26:54 - Song: Thank you Lord for this fine day! (Junior Praise 232)

30:45 - 35:55 - Introducing activity : 50 years of the United Reformed Church
I hope 1972 is in your minds at the moment
The union of Presbyterian and Congregationalist Christians that started the URC
Congregational Union of Scotland joining in 2000 
Activity: ‘50 year Time line’ 1972 – 2022 and beyond
Think about 3 events to put on the timeline: a personal one, a special moment in the church, and an event in the community, nation or world

41:30 - Worship song: MP 1259  Bless the Lord o my soul

45:44 - Introduction to reading

46:16 - 47:35 - Reading: Luke 4.14 – 21 (The Message) 

47:47 - 52:42 - All age talk: ‘The Time is now!’
What a moment that must have been - that synagogue where Jesus read the words from Isaiah saying what he was about
For the United Reformed Church, this is seen as a jubilee year, when we want God's time to shine
Anniversary socks from the URC Ministers' gathering
What else can you buy that's URC branded - soap!
Jesus gives his agenda in the moment in Galilee - a very particular place and moment
The Spirit of the Lord is upon me - to bring good news to the poor
God's time is now
Good news can't just be words, it has to be actions
The story ends with Jesus being turned out and a crowd attempting to stone him
Moments of jubilation and despair on our timeline
Is God shining through Jesus and hist followers
We need to open our eyes to find where that light is shining in unexpected places


54:58 - Song: MP 545  Open my eyes Lord

55:55 - Short talk: Vision for Trinity 
Key themes from the planning group - worship and Christian discipleship
Outward looking, communicating the good news of Jesus
Focusing on the resources we have - buildings, finance and people
Working in partnership
Start small - crawl, walk, then run
Doing something, not remaining paralysed

Offering Prayer (of all our gifts – no collection is taken up)

59:08 - 01:00:11 - Song Open my hands Lord
Open our hands, Lord,
we want to serve Jesus,
to reach out in his name,
and show his love for all.
Open our hearts, Lord,
and help us to follow.
Open our hands, Lord,
we want to serve Jesus.

01:00:16 - Prayers for the church and the world with the response
Your kingdom come
  Your will be done.
Lord’s Prayer (modern version)

01:06:48 - Hymn R&amp;S 489  Be thou my vision

01:10:10 - 01:10:39 - Blessing

01:11:03 - 01:14:55 - Music and notices after the service</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="19"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:lwUFNtBK7AE</id>
  <yt:videoId>lwUFNtBK7AE</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 24th July led by John Shaw</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lwUFNtBK7AE"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-07-24T11:50:02+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-08-19T15:49:36+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 24th July led by John Shaw</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/lwUFNtBK7AE?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/lwUFNtBK7AE/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00:00 - Music and notices before the service 

15:18 - Welcome and lighting of peace candle (by an elder)

17:29 - Call to Worship from Colossians 2. 6 – 7

19:09 - Hymn When morning gilds the sky (R&amp;S 292)

22:40 - Opening Prayers and the Lord’s Prayer

25:15 - 34:07 - Talk for all ages: “Teach us to pray”
We are glad it's not as hot as last Monday and Tuesday
When it's that hot, it's hard to even think, one just wants to be still and get through it
Think about a time when you had to learn a skill
Sometimes the learning is successful, sometimes not
Learning to tie shoelaces?
Learning to play the piano?
Learning to drive?
In the reading from Luke's gospel, the disciples want Jesus to teach them how to pray.
In Luke more than others, we hear of when Jesus is praying
We have already used the prayer he taught them all two thousand years ago
There is so much in the Lord's Prayer
What he taught them was not what they were expecting which was something long and wordy
What Jesus taught was a simple prayer, the short version of this can be said just in one breath
If ever you are uncertain of how to pray, the Lord's Prayer is a great place to start

34:22 - Hymn - Father I place into your hands (R&amp;S 518)

34:50 - Blessing as Junior Church go to their activities:
Adults: May the Lord be with you
Junior Church: And also with you
All: Amen.

37:53 - Introduction to Bible readings

38:23 - Reading: Luke 11. 1 – 13 NIVUK
11 One day Jesus was praying in a certain place. When he finished, one
of his disciples said to him, ‘Lord, teach us to pray, just as John taught his
disciples.’
2  He said to them, ‘When you pray, say:
‘“Father,
hallowed be your name,
your kingdom come.
3  Give us each day our daily bread.
4  Forgive us our sins, for we also forgive everyone who sins against us.
And lead us not into temptation.”’
5  Then Jesus said to them, ‘Suppose you have a friend, and you go to him
at midnight and say, “Friend, lend me three loaves of bread;  6  a friend of
mine on a journey has come to me, and I have no food to offer
him.”  7  And suppose the one inside answers, “Don’t bother me. The door
is already locked, and my children and I are in bed. I can’t get up and
give you anything.”  8  I tell you, even though he will not get up and give
you the bread because of friendship, yet because of your shameless
audacity ]  he will surely get up and give you as much as you need.
9  ‘So I say to you: ask and it will be given to you; seek and you will find;
knock and the door will be opened to you.  10  For everyone who asks
receives; the one who seeks finds; and to the one who knocks, the door
will be opened.
11  ‘Which of you fathers, if your son asks for a fish, will give him a snake
instead?  12  Or if he asks for an egg, will give him a scorpion?  13  If you then,
though you are evil, know how to give good gifts to your children, how
much more will your Father in heaven give the Holy Spirit to those who
ask him!’

40:35 - 42:43 - Reading: Colossians 2. 6 – 15 NIVUK 


43:03 - Hymn - I will sing the wondrous story (CMP 315)

46:52 - Prayer
47:46 - 01:05:06 - Sermon: “Ask and you will receive”
These familiar words are used just after the Disciples ask Jesus to teach them how to pray 
They highlight how important it is for us to ask, seek, knock and pray
Why do some people say prayer is irrelevant
Looking at prayer in the context of our relationship with God
Finally thinking about the nature of God that sets the words in context
Distinguishing between gifts from God as creator and father - creation and redemption

A time of quiet reflection

01:06:00 - Hymn - What a friend we have in Jesus (R&amp;S 413)

01:08:56 - Prayers for others and ourselves
Offering Prayer of all our gifts – no collection is taken up

01:15:18 - Hymn - At the name of Jesus (R&amp;S 261)

01:18:34 - 01:18:54 - Closing blessing / the Grace

01:19:22 - 01:23:08 - Organ voluntary and notices</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="21"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:STm5_E8OToo</id>
  <yt:videoId>STm5_E8OToo</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 10th July led by Dr J Prior</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=STm5_E8OToo"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-07-10T22:19:40+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-08-19T15:34:54+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 10th July led by Dr J Prior</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/STm5_E8OToo?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/STm5_E8OToo/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00 - Music and notices before the service

10:50 - Welcome and lighting of peace candle (an elder)
12:18 - Call to worship

13:47 - Hymn: R&amp;S 45 Morning has broken [Tune: Bunessan]

15:59 - Opening Prayers 
Lord’s Prayer 

18:54 - 23:40 - Talk with all ages - Prophets
Our first reading will be from one of the Old Testament Prophets
Do any of our young people understand what prophets
One that prophesies, something where you spend money to make more money
Homophones and prophets/profits
We all profit from the wisdom of the prophets
Prophets weren't actually telling the future, their job was to tell it like it is
Speaking truth to power and telling those in power that things were not going as they should be
Thinking of modern day prophets
Greta Thunberg - a schoolgirl but understands the world as it is today is not going to be able to sustain itself unless we change.

23:55 - Song TP 13  Be still, for the presence of the Lord   

27:05 - Offering Prayer (of all our gifts – no collection is taken up)

Blessing as Junior Church go to their activities:
Adults:   The Lord be with you
Junior Church:  And also with you
All:      Amen.

29:10 - Introduction to the readings
  
30:21 - Reading: Amos 7:7-17 NIVUK 


33:32 - 35:35 - Reading: Colossians 1: 1 – 14 NIVUK 

35:45 - Song: TP 13   God forgave my sin

38:31 - 50:48 - Address: How to live a good life which honors God
The two bible readings could hardly be more different
Separated in time by about 800 years, the tone of the two is markedly different
Amos wrote his prophecy in around 760BC some 20 years before the better known Isiah
Amos didn't see himself as a prophet, not employed by anyone important, he worked the land.
He traveled widely and knew the northern kingdom well.
He saw lots of inequality and divisions in society
Merchants were paying lip service only to their religion
The Altar at Bethel was being used to worship false Gods
When he challenged the High Priest, Amos was told to go back to Judah
Amos warned that Israel's exile to Assyria was at had but was ignored
There are sad parallels with our society today
Our Prime Minister Boris Johnson wriggling out of one scandal after another. Now irretrievably rejected by his MPs he has accepted he needs to go but is still clinging to power. Brought down by his own dishonest.
Think of Putin's invasion of Ukraine and the war crimes committed there.
Think of the riots in Sri Lanka
Think of the earthquake in Afghanistan and all of the other issues there
Paul's letter to the Colossians is in contrast to this.
Written from house arrest in Rome whilst waiting for false accusations to be dealt with.
It is full of hope, written to stem the influence of teaching aimed at trapping the people in superstition
We are still Paul's congregation
We have been rescued by God through Christ Jesus, forgiving our sins.
Paul's message helps us to bear in mind that God in Christ Jesus is all in all, first and last, head of the Church, all powerful and generous in return for our faith and obedience to God's law - loving him with all our strength, soul, and mind and to love our neighbour as we love ourself


51:04 - Hymn R&amp;S 613 Lord, speak to me [Tune: RS 50; Galilee]

54:41 - Prayers of intercession with the response
Leader: The Lord hears our prayer:
All:  Thanks be to God.

59:47 - Hymn R&amp;S 260 Christ is alive!   [Tune: Truro]

01:03:12 - 01:03:45 - Final Prayer and Blessing

01:04:45 - 01:07:45  - Organ voluntary and notices</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="22"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:X9PZZLxF1SQ</id>
  <yt:videoId>X9PZZLxF1SQ</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 3rd July led by Rev Terry Hinks</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=X9PZZLxF1SQ"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-07-03T21:37:41+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-08-19T15:31:51+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 3rd July led by Rev Terry Hinks</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/X9PZZLxF1SQ?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/X9PZZLxF1SQ/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00:00 - Music and notices before the service
05:05 - Welcome and lighting of peace candle (an elder)

06:28 - Call to worship: from Psalm 66

07:27 - Hymn: TP 48  Jesus calls us here to meet him

10:40 - Opening Prayers with the response 

13:30 - 22:33 - Introduction: ‘receiving and sharing the gift’
Good to be back home
Think for a moment about a house - a childhood home, where you live today, a holiday home, a tent, a famous place
Buckingham Palace, the Queen welcoming a refugee from Peru at her recent Diamond Jubilee celebrations
Jesus sending out 72 disciples out to visit villages and homes taking a great gift - Peace
Peace doesn't just appear, it has to be made



23:35 - Worship songs: R&amp;S 594  Peace perfect peace (vs 1 only)
 and MP 1227 The splendour of the King – led by Music Group 

28:50 - Introduction to the readings

29:25 - 30:37 - Reading: Luke 10:1 – 11 NIVUK

31:20 - Hymn R&amp;S 512 Seek ye first the kingdom sung seated as a round

35:04 - 35:48 - Reading: Luke 10: 17 – 21 NIVUK 

36:52 - Hymn R&amp;S 286 Rejoice in the Lord sung standing as a round

38:53 - 47:45 - Short Address
Take a deep breath, relax, be conscious of the in-breath, hold and then release
Slowly breathe in and out feeling the air moving
Difficulty living with asthma
The breathing of the church
The church as Institutions and people of God
Inviting others to come and breathe in the love of God
Living our christian and human lives day by day
Keeping in balance
Jesus trusting the disciples with his work
Using the words &quot;Peace to this house&quot;

47:47 - Hymn R&amp;S 398 O Lord hear my prayer 
sung seated to begin our prayers

50:16 - 52:28 - Prayers for others and ourselves
Please pray for: 
• Those on your hearts who need God’s peace
• Trinity Prayer Day – as we seek God’s guidance for our Church Vision – our work and witness in our community.
• Lighthouse Holiday Club (25 – 29 July)
• URC General Assembly meeting at Swanwick (8 to 11 July)
• Peace in homes, nations and globally

52:37 - Hymn R&amp;S 635  Put peace into each other’s hands 

56:20 - Communion: we invite you to share in the bread and wine at church (or at home) united in the name of Christ, empowered by the Spirit.

A Prayer of thanksgiving and Lord’s Prayer 

Distribution of Communion and Closing Prayer

01:06:14 - Hymn R&amp;S 21 Praise God from all blessings flow

01:07:18 - 01:07:50 - Blessing

01:08:27 - 01:13:06 - Music, photos and notices after the service</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="20"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:u05IqZoi3us</id>
  <yt:videoId>u05IqZoi3us</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 26th June 2022  led by Daisy Mansfield  The Leprosy Mission</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=u05IqZoi3us"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-06-26T10:44:50+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-08-19T15:36:03+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 26th June 2022  led by Daisy Mansfield  The Leprosy Mission</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/u05IqZoi3us?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/u05IqZoi3us/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00  Music and notices before worship.

09:39 - Welcome and lighting of peace candle (an elder)

11:55 - Call to worship: Psalm 118

13:24 - Hymn: TP 12  Be still and know that I am God 

15:17 - Opening Prayers and the Lord’s Prayer

16:55 - 21:12 - Talk for all ages: Introduction to the Leprosy Mission
Difficulties with leprosy
Leprosy a bacterial disease affecting hands and feet
  
21:18 - Worship songs
MP 1079 Jesus Hope of the nations
MP 1008 The Lord’s my Shepherd I’ll not want
 
Blessing as Junior Church go to their activities:

29:13 - Introduction to Bible readings

29:35 - Reading 1 : Isaiah 43:14-21

31:07 - 32:53 - Reading 2: John 10: 1-10 r

33:06 - Hymn TP 100 When we walk with the Lord

36:52 - Sermon – Springs of Hope
Bringing a message of hope in 3 parts:
An unexpected hope, a living hope, and partnered in hope
Poppies as a sign of hope 
Niger and the issues with poverty and leprosy
How education is changing lives
Donations helping transform communities
£6 provides a child with a place at school for a year

01:00:02 - A time of quiet reflection

01:01:30 - Hymn TP29  For I’m building a people of power

01:04:11 - Prayers for others and ourselves

Offering – please stand for the Prayer of Dedication

01:10:41 - Hymn TP 31 Give thanks with a grateful heart

01:13:43 - 01:14:06 - Closing blessing 

01:14:28 - 01:17:58 - Music and notices after the service

Organist: Charles Brewster</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="1" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="19"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:KOWmE4cBlVA</id>
  <yt:videoId>KOWmE4cBlVA</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 19th June 2022</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KOWmE4cBlVA"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-06-19T10:41:10+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-06-24T07:41:14+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 19th June 2022</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/KOWmE4cBlVA?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/KOWmE4cBlVA/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00  Music and notices before worship.

10:31 - Welcome and lighting of peace candle (an elder)

12:17 - Call to worship 

12:42 - Hymn - Jesus calls us here

15:45 - 22:03 - Opening Prayers and the Lord’s Prayer
Nice to be back after COVID, seeing everyone getting back into more normal activities

22:05 - Song -  Be still for the presence of the Lord
 
25:23 - Introduction to Bible readings
The readings have a theme today

26:40 - 28:34 - Reading: 1 Kings 17 vv7-14  

28:41 - 30:50 - Reading: John 5 vv 1-15 
 
30:56 - 32:28 - Reading Luke 5  vv17-36

32:35 - Hymn - Christ’s is the world in which we live 

36:51 - 56:18 - Talk  followed by time of quiet reflection 
The story of the paralysed man was the first that came to mind to speak about
The &quot;para&quot; part has become common in conversation in our family in the past 18 months since our daughter Nina was diagnosed with MS and subsequently gained a place in the GB para-snowboard squad.
Nina is the opposite to the paralysed man in the story.  He had been sitting by the pool for 38 years.  We don't know how he got there every day.  He told himself when the pool stirred, one of these days he would be first in and would be able to walk.
After 38 years, did he feel it was too much to hope to walk in the way others did?  Why had no-one helped him in those 38 years
Elijah traveled as he was told to and met a widow. He wanted a drink and something to eat.  There was only enough flour and oil to make bread for her and her son but she shared it with him and there was more
In the third story, the man had good friends who were determined he should have a chance to be healed lowering him through a roof to get him in front of Jesus
Finding friends who help for no benefit to themselves
Feeling part of a new group and belonging
Remembering who you are and where you come from
Making a difference to people, one individual at a time
Finding someone we can each help

57:05 - Hymn - O let the Son of God enfold you 

01:00:30 - Prayers for others and ourselves

01:05:33 - Offering Prayer of Dedication

01:06:13 - Hymn - All over the world                       

01:08:54 - 01:09:17 - Closing blessing 

01:09:40 - 01:14:20 - Music and notices after the service

Worship led by Barbara Sparks
Organist: Charles Brewster</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="1" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="20"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:iv4H7C67oP4</id>
  <yt:videoId>iv4H7C67oP4</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 5th June 2022</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iv4H7C67oP4"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-06-05T10:55:08+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-09-08T14:50:17+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 5th June 2022</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/iv4H7C67oP4?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/iv4H7C67oP4/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00:00 - Music and notices before worship

06:39 - Welcome, lighting of peace candle
08:34 - Call to worship:
Whoever you are, come together and come to God.
Wherever you’re from, come together and come to God.
Whatever you bring, come together and come to God.
However you feel, come together and come to God.
God is here, and God is good!

09:10 - Hymn R&amp;S 329 There’s a spirit in the air

12:15 - Opening Prayers

14:55 - 21:19 -  Introduction: the Queen’s Jubilee – ‘held in prayer’
One of those mornings, I couldn't find my flag to wave
We come this amazing weekend for our nation to remember the work of our Queen over those 70 years
What a life of service
How many of you have seen the Queen in person
Over 1/3 of the population feel they have had a connection with Her Majesty
Paddington and James Bond, Bond with his courage and brokenness, Paddington an immigrant from Darkest Peru
Junior Church prayer tree now featuring a squirrel, a blue tit and a caterpillar
The Church Of England is obliged to pray for the Queen
The corronation speech from Her Majesty - &quot;Throughout this memorable day I have been uplifted and sustained by the knowledge that your thoughts and prayers were with me&quot; - https://www.royal.uk/coronation-day-speech-2-june-1953
The church sustaining us
Let's hold each other in prayer day by day, week by week

21:20 - Jubilee Song - Rise Up and Serve
Rise Up and Serve song (video to watch) with the chorus:
‘Rise up and serve’ is the call we hear
With hope in our hearts, joining as one, making history.
Let fanfares sound through this Jubilee
Rise up and serve, thanking God for Her Majesty.

27:55 - National Anthem
God save our gracious Queen
Long live our noble Queen
God save the Queen
Send her victorious
Happy and glorious
Long to reign over us
God save the Queen

Not in this land alone,
But be God's mercies known,
From shore to shore!
Lord make the nations see,
That all should kindred be,
And form one family,
The wide world o'er.

29:27 - Prayer for Her Majesty

31:22 - Introducing reading: the Universal Spirit

32:16 - 35:03 - Reading: Acts 2.1 – 13 (Good News) 

35:13 - Hymn R&amp;S 308 Spirit of the Living God 

36:08 - Reading: Acts 2.14 – 21 (Good News)

37:33 - 38:30 - Hymn R&amp;S 309 Spirit of the Living God 

38:31 - 49:05 - Short Talk
I hope you have been enjoying this 4 day weekend
Escaping the pettiness of politics, #partygate mentioned in the comedy links at the party
A bit of fun, pomp and ceremony, and some history
Celebrating this stateswoman in our midst
Her contribution to this nation was recognised and thanks given for it
Was the Queen watching from home as so many of us have done over the past 2 years
Impressed by the involvement of young people across the Commonwealth
Soggy street parties as the culmination of a great weekend?
Today is also Pentecost
In Jewish tradition a time to celebrate the giving of the Torah
Moving from the incredible events of the cross and resurrection of Jesus, sending out the disciples with all their joy to tell people the good news
As small group of disciples and a large crows from all known nations
We need individuals that inspire us - The Queen, David Attenborough , Michelle #Obama
Peter stood up when the disciples were being mocked for being drunk to turn hearts and bring thousands to God
More than that we need communities that are transformed by the joy and peace of the coming of the spirit
The Pentecost story is about being filled with the Holy Spirit, not just being given it, telling people how all could be saved
We need individuals but we need the Spirit of God to inspire his followers today
The Spirit is God's gift to us all

49:06 - 52:36 Prayers for the church and the world with the response
Come Holy Spirit, give new strength and hope.

52:52 - Hymn - MP 673 There is a Redeemer

55:33 - Communion: we invite you to share in the bread and wine at
church (or at home) united in the name of Christ, empowered by
the Spirit.
A Prayer of thanksgiving and Lord’s Prayer

58:54 - Distribution of Communion and Closing Prayer

01:04:52 - Hymn We sing a love that sets all people free TUNE R&amp;S 740
We sing a love that sets all people free,
that blows like wind, that burns like scorching flame,
enfolds the earth, springs up like water clear:
come, living love, live in our hearts today.

We sing a love that seeks another’s good,
that longs to serve and not to count the cost,
a love that, yielding, finds itself made new:
come, caring love, live in our hearts today.

We sing the Holy Spirit, full of love,
who seeks out scars of ancient bitterness,
brings to our wounds the healing grace of Christ:
come, radiant love, live in our hearts today.
© June Boyce-Tillman

01:08:17 - 01:08:35 - Blessing

01:09:06 - 01:12:53 - Organ, Notices and Photos from our congregation around out community this week

#jubilee #platinumjubilee #thequeen #pentecost</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="129"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:XOgqzS9cvww</id>
  <yt:videoId>XOgqzS9cvww</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 29th May 2022 - led by Rev Terry Hinks</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XOgqzS9cvww"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-05-29T10:47:56+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-08-19T15:50:03+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 29th May 2022 - led by Rev Terry Hinks</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/XOgqzS9cvww?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/XOgqzS9cvww/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00:00 - Music and notices before worship

16:45 - Welcome, lighting of peace candle
18:42 - We come in hope, - to hear the Good News of Jesus.
We come in wonder, - to share the Good News of Jesus.
We come in joy, - to proclaim the Good News of Jesus.
We come to worship God,  - to praise Jesus as Lord and Saviour of world,
in the power of God’s Spirit of love and truth.  
Amen.

19:27 - Hymn R&amp;S 262  Crown him with many crowns

23:38 - Opening Prayers
25:18 - Lord’s Prayer

25:57 - 34:39 - Introduction: ‘Love Wycombe?’ 
I hope you have all heard of Love Wycombe by now
Part of the life of churches in Wycombe for over a decade now
This year by the Guildhall on 12th June
As we pray for the Wycombe area, work for its good and prepare to celebrate God’s love for all, let’s ask two questions:
    What do you three things like about your community?
   What three improvements would you like to see happen?


34:46 - 34:38 -  Reading: Psalm 122 read by Kate Yates
36:16 - Peace be with you

36:18 - Song MP 1079  Jesus hope of the nations 
Brian Doerkensen - https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MsFIGSOTsVM

40:55  - Introduction to reading

41:09 - 42:22 - Reading: Luke 24. 44 – 53 read by Kate Yates

42:53 - Song R&amp;S 264 He is Lord (sung seated as a prayer)

45:42 - 57:45 - Talk:  ‘Mountain top and city streets’
This Sunday is fascinating - is it Easter or something else
It's called different things depending on which lectionary you use
Jesus has died and risen but the holy spirit has not yet arrived. 10 days of waiting.
Is Jesus still with them or has he gone?
Luke describes the ascension in the most literal terms of the 4 gospels
Jesus ascending to heaven wasn't an Apollo/Elon Musk trip to space
There was a transition as Jesus left the physical space and became the greater reality no longer restricted by flesh and blood, opening the disciples' minds
Opening minds - the most important thing for us as Christians today?
Getting caught up in all of our transitions, turning back again and again to the living Jesus who opens our minds to understand the scriptures anew


57:48 - Hymn R&amp;S 579 Lord thy church on earth

01:01:28 - ‘Thy Kingdom come’: Global Wave of Prayer
 LOVE THE WORLD 
God so loved the world that he gave his one and only Son, that whoever believes in him shall not perish but have eternal life…God sent him not to condemn the world …but to save the world.
John 3.16, 17

Prayers for the church and the world with the response:
Your kingdom come,
Your will be done.

 LOVE WYCOMBE TODAY 
Today as we pick up litter in the neighbourhood.
Today as we pray for our neighbours (street by street in ‘Prayer walking’).
Today as we pray for the central event planned for Sunday 12 June

01:10:09 - Hymn -  R&amp;S 603  Lord for the years

01:13:54 -1:14:24 - Blessing.

01:14:56 - 01:17:41 - Organ, Notices and Photos from our congregation around out community this week</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="1" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="26"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
</feed>
