<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns:yt="http://www.youtube.com/xml/schemas/2015" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 <link rel="self" href="http://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=PLrggWHcy3azrunmSfTCSlS5JRuB4zTgCY"/>
 <id>yt:playlist:PLrggWHcy3azrunmSfTCSlS5JRuB4zTgCY</id>
 <yt:playlistId>PLrggWHcy3azrunmSfTCSlS5JRuB4zTgCY</yt:playlistId>
 <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
 <title>Worship services - Trinity and Cores End URCs</title>
 <author>
  <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
  <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
 </author>
 <published>2020-04-04T11:11:34+00:00</published>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:kCoReUha7SE</id>
  <yt:videoId>kCoReUha7SE</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 17th September 2023 - Harvest Celebration</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kCoReUha7SE"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2023-09-16T17:06:33+00:00</published>
  <updated>2023-09-17T12:45:26+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 17th September 2023 - Harvest Celebration</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/kCoReUha7SE?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/kCoReUha7SE/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00 - Welcome to Harvest Thanksgiving Service, focusing on our need for physical and spiritual food.  A special welcome to Helen Foster from One Can Foodbank who will be updating us on its work and receiving our harvest gifts.  Do stay of you can for refreshments after the service.  Leaflets about the church and its activities are on the side tables.

Entry of Bible (please stand if you are able), welcome 
and lighting of peace candle (by Duty Elder)

Call to worship
God cares for the earth and makes its fruitful
Our God crowns the year with good gifts.   

HYMN R&amp;S 124  We plough the fields and scatter

Opening Prayers

Reading: Deuteronomy 12. 1 – 12 Good News
read by Valerie and David Bishop

Bringing our gifts

A word of thanks from Helen Foster of One Can
SONG TP 98  When I needed a neighbour

Activities for children at back of church

Talk: An update on the wider work of One Can

HYMN All across the world (Tune R&amp;S 495)

1. All across the world there’s harvests 
gath’ring food we’re glad to eat; 
though we’ll never meet the farmers, 
keep us thankful for their feat. 

2. Foodstuffs gathered, packed and processed,
shipped and trucked and sold and bought; 
for all people who supply us, 
may we show the thanks we ought. 

3. Where rewards divide unjustly,
workers struggle to survive,
may we act to make trade fairer,
play our part, keep hope alive. 

4. God who cares for all who harvest,
God who cares for all who eat, 
keep us thankful, keep us acting 
’til your justice is complete. 

© 2016 Kevin Mayhew John Campbell 

Reading: 2 Corinthians 9:6-15  NIVUK 
read by Valerie and David 

Short Talk; ‘sow generously’
Prayers for ourselves and the world 
using the verses of HYMN R&amp;S 512 Seek ye first

Let us seek first the kingdom of God – that life of the Spirit, full of peace and justice and compassion.
1. Seek ye first the kingdom of God….
(Prayer)
Let us ask God for the help we need and seek our Creator’s will for the world around us:
2. Ask, and it shall be given unto you…
(prayer)
Let us remember the need of all people for spiritual as well as physical food and give thanks for all our Saviour provides:
3. We shall not live by bread alone… 
(prayer)
May the Lord of the harvest, Creator, Saviour and Spirit hear our prayers as we seek the kingdom of God.
4. Seek ye first the kingdom of God….
(ending with the chorus Alleluia, Alleluia…)

The Lord’s Prayer 

HYMN R&amp;S 48  Praise and thanksgiving

Blessing

Music after the service

#Church #Worship #Sing #Organ #Faithful #Jesus #URC #UnitedReformedChurch  #Blessings #GoodNews #NIV #NIVUK #Bible #Lessons #GoodNews #Hymns #AllAreWelcome #JoinIn #Christian

#worship #spiritualstruggle #goodvsevil #christcrucified #communion #heavenlypraise #almightygod #ChurchLife #FaithMatters #YourChurch #OneCan

#Harvest #HarvestFestival #Produce #Deuteronomy #Offering #FoodBank</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="6"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:tCg9XvNXW8g</id>
  <yt:videoId>tCg9XvNXW8g</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 10th September 2023 - Led by the members</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tCg9XvNXW8g"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2023-09-10T22:30:55+00:00</published>
  <updated>2023-09-11T17:26:21+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 10th September 2023 - Led by the members</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/tCg9XvNXW8g?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/tCg9XvNXW8g/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00 - Opening music, photos, and notices

08:01 - Entry of Bible (please stand if you are able)

08:12 - Welcome and lighting of the peace candle

10:34 - Call to worship
  Where can I go from your spirit?
  Or where can I flee from your presence?
  If I ascend to heaven, you are there;
  If I make my bed in Sheol, you are there.
  If I take the wings of the morning and settle at the farthest limits of the sea,
  even there your hand shall lead me,
  and your right hand shall hold me fast  

11:18 - 14:16 - Hymn - MP 59 - Blessed assurance Jesus is mine

14:31 - 16:26 - Opening prayers &amp; Lord's Prayer

16:48 - 19:14 - Harvest Talk

19:45 - 22:18 - Song - R&amp;S 523 - Give me Joy in my heart

Blessing with Junior Church

22:29 - Prayer for illumination before the reading

22:49 - 24:29 - Reading: Genesis 28: 10-19a NIVUK read by Kate Yates

24:50 - 27:22 - Hymn - MP 1343 - O God you search me (Psalm 139)

28:03 - 41:52 - Sermon
Jacob was a lonely, guilty figure fleeing his past when he had the dream.
God had to speak to Jacob in a dream when he was passive to get through to him.
In the dream, Jacob saw a ladder between heaven and earth with angels going up and down.
The passage points to Jesus as the ladder between heaven and earth.
Jesus referred to himself as the ladder between heaven and earth.
The passage also tells us something about the church as a &quot;trusting&quot; place where heaven and earth meet.
The church is a special meeting place between God and people.
The passage addresses us individually in our own lonely, guilty, or dark places.
Even when we don't know it, God can be present with us in those painful places.
Those painful places can later become &quot;Bethel&quot; - the house of God.

42:11 - 45:00 - Hymn - R&amp;S 71 - O God of Bethel, by whose hand

45:17 - 4743 - Prayers of Intercessions

47:44 - Offertory prayer

48:19 - 53:08 - HYMN - R&amp;S 121 - The God of Abraham praise

53:09 - 53:49 - Blessing

54:15 - 58:16 - Music after the service

#Church #Worship #Sing #Organ #Faithful #Jesus #URC #UnitedReformedChurch  #Blessings #GoodNews #NIV #NIVUK #Bible #Lessons #GoodNews #Hymns #AllAreWelcome #JoinIn #Christian

#worship #spiritualstruggle #goodvsevil #christcrucified #communion #heavenlypraise #almightygod #ChurchLife #FaithMatters #YourChurch #OneCan

#HarvestNextWeek #RIPYourMajesty #QueenElizabethII #RNLI 
#JacobsLadder #Bethel #HouseOfGod #Jacob</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="32"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:Vq0aVCpO0g0</id>
  <yt:videoId>Vq0aVCpO0g0</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 3rd September 2023</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Vq0aVCpO0g0"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2023-09-03T22:55:40+00:00</published>
  <updated>2023-09-06T08:11:22+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 3rd September 2023</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/Vq0aVCpO0g0?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/Vq0aVCpO0g0/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00 - Opening music, photos, and notices

08:00 - Entry of Bible (please stand if you are able)

08:10 - Welcome and lighting of the peace candle

10:25 - Call to worship

11:06 - 15:00 - Hymn R&amp;S 39 All creatures of our God and King (vs 1-4)

16:07 - 18:39 - Opening Four Directional Prayer

18:45 - 29:53 - All age Talk: ‘Season of Creation – rivers of justice and peace’
The river of Life from Revelation, bringing healing.
Rivers start small but grow large, which fascinates the speaker.
The local River Wye is a precious chalk stream needing protection.
The Wye has been polluted and neglected over the years.
Local groups like Revive the Wye aim to restore and protect the river.
Rivers worldwide are being damaged through pollution.
Rivers are sacred places in scripture that we must protect.

30:25 - A Prayer of new beginning
(by Revd James Shri Bhagwan, General Secretary of the Pacific Conference of Churches)
God of hope and healing may your Rivers of Righteousness
wash away our apathy, our greed and selfishness and reveal
the deep relationships You created for us with all creation.
Nourish us with the water of life that restores, turning
deserts of despair into oases of hope.
May the waves of Your embrace transform us back into
guardians of Your creation.
May the currents of Your justice carry us to Your lagoon of
peace where all creation may enjoy Life in abundance
We pray in the name of the one who came, so that the whole
cosmos may have everlasting life, Jesus the Christ. Amen.

31:52 - 34:47 - SONG TP 75 Peace I give to you

34:50 - A Word from Greenbelt Festival

42:55 - 45:02 - Readings: Psalm 85 with the response
May love and truth meet together:
Let justice and mercy join hands.

45:31 - 49:02 - Hymn R&amp;S 639 This we can do for justice

49:52 - 50:54 - Amos 5: 21-24 (NIVUK) read by Elsje Hatton
51:03 - 52:00 - John 7:37-39 (NIVUK) read by Tony Hatton

52:35 - 57:57 - Short Address
Rivers are powerful parts of creation and nature.
Local rivers like the Wye provided power for industry and development.
But rivers have been neglected, polluted, and abused over the years.
Rivers are sacred places in scripture and tradition.
Rivers symbolize life and renewal.
Rivers need protection and care as precious resources.
Rivers can symbolize justice and righteousness flowing through society.
And rivers can symbolize the Spirit flowing in our hearts to cleanse and renew.
We're called to care for physical rivers, work for societal justice, and seek inner spiritual renewal.

Rivers have physical power in creation and enabled industrial development locally. But sadly, rivers have been neglected and polluted over time. Biblically, rivers are sacred places representing life. But our treatment of rivers like the Thames shows need for protection of these precious resources. Second, rivers can symbolize justice and righteousness flowing through society to bring renewal. Third, rivers remind us of the Spirit flowing within, cleansing our hearts. In conclusion, we're called to care for physical rivers, work for justice in society, and seek spiritual renewal from God's Spirit within. Rivers connect us to God's creation, God's justice, and God's Spirit.

58:57 - 01:02:42 - Prayers of concern
Lord of all life teach us; and show us your way.
Lord’s Prayer (version by Jim Cotter)
Eternal Spirit, Earth-maker, Pain-bearer, Life-giver,
Source of all that is and that shall be,
Father and Mother of us all, Loving God, in whom is heaven:
The hallowing of your name echoes through the universe! The
way of your justice be followed by the peoples of the world!
Your heavenly will be done by all created beings! Your
communion of peace and freedom sustain our hope and come
on Earth. With the bread we need for today, feed us. In the
hurts we absorb from one another, forgive us. In times of
temptation and test, strengthen us. From trials too great to
endure, spare us. From the grip of all that is evil, free us. For
you reign in the glory of the power that is love, now and
forever. Amen.

01:03:25 - 01:06:45 - Hymn R&amp;S 635 Put peace into each others’ hands

01:06:59 - Communion: we invite you to share in the bread and wine at
church (or at home) united in the name of Christ.
A Prayer of thanksgiving

Distribution of bread and wine (non-alcoholic grape juice)

01:16:07 -  Closing Prayer

01:17:31 - 01:20:08 - Hymn R&amp;S 38 Thou whose almighty word

01:20:09 - 01:20:35 - Blessing

01:21:04 - 01:25:06 - Music after the service

#Church #Worship #Sing #Organ #Faithful #Jesus #URC #UnitedReformedChurch  #Blessings #GoodNews #NIV #NIVUK #Bible #Lessons #GoodNews #Hymns #AllAreWelcome #JoinIn #Christian

#worship #spiritualstruggle #goodvsevil #christcrucified #communion #heavenlypraise #almightygod #ChurchLife #FaithMatters 

#Rivers #Pollution #Sewage #Festival #BurningMan #ThamesWater #Amos #GiveThanks #CurrentOfRenewal #StreamsOfLivingWater #SeasonOfCreation #RiverWye #RiverThames

#Greenbelt @greenbeltfestival #SomewhereToBelieveIn #YourChurch</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="36"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:Sp1D0LJITNI</id>
  <yt:videoId>Sp1D0LJITNI</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 27th August 2023</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Sp1D0LJITNI"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2023-08-27T22:27:13+00:00</published>
  <updated>2023-09-01T08:08:22+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 27th August 2023</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/Sp1D0LJITNI?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/Sp1D0LJITNI/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00 - Opening music, photos, and notices

06:07 - Entry of Bible (please stand if you are able)

06:22 - Welcome and lighting of peace candle

10:03 - Call to worship Psalm 138.1 – 5 
       
10:57 - 13:38 -  Hymn - Father, we praise you now

13:39 - 16:00 - Opening Prayer and Lord’s Prayer

16:22 - 17:37 - Reading: Matthew 16. 13 – 20 read by Sarah 

17:44 - 21:36 - Talk for all ages introducing the theme
A new job at G Smith The Undertakers in Wooburn Green.
The speaker was puzzled by the fact that the cost of a funeral plan did not always match the cost of the funeral itself.
This is because the plan is taken out at one point in time, but the funeral may take place at a later date, when prices may have changed.
Compares this to the Gospel story, where Jesus's disciples were trying to figure out who he was.
Jesus knew that they had different ideas about him, but he wanted them to make the discovery for themselves.
We should also try to make our own discoveries about God.
When we discover something for ourselves, we are more likely to remember it and understand it better.
The speaker gives the example of learning that fire is hot or that cement hardens.
The speaker says that Jesus sensed that his disciples were almost ready to discover that he was the Messiah.
The speaker says that Simon Peter was the first disciple to make this discovery.
Jesus's disciples were trying to figure out who he was. Jesus knew that they had different ideas about him, but he wanted them to make the discovery for themselves. We should also try to make our own discoveries about God. When we discover something for ourselves, we are more likely to remember it and understand it better.

22:00 - 24:14 - Hymn - In the cross of Christ, I glory

24:46 - 26:48 - Reading: Romans 12. 1 – 8 read by Norma

27:15 - Hymn - Just as I am

31:24 - 41:32 - Address, followed by a time of quiet reflection 
Reflecting on the previous sermon series on Revelation.
Why the lectionary is used for most services rather than exploring other parts of the Bible.
Doing the daily office with readings and psalms from the lectionary.
Fewer churches have evening services now, and we are poorer for it
Certain Bible passages and hymns conjure up thoughts about God.
Recalling a confirmation class discussion about hymns portraying God.
One student said a hymn portrayed God like an almighty corset.
Today's Romans passage reminds us of a previous sermon on not thinking too highly of yourself.
Relating this to the unattractive character of Uriah Heep from David Copperfield.
Does emphasizing humility makes some people think even less of themselves.
Does stressing humility leads some people to think even less of themselves when they already face challenges to their self-esteem from lack of education, employment, or respect from others.


42:02 - 44:40 - Hymn Thy kingdom come O God

44:49 - 48:29 - Prayers for the church and the world 

48:50 - 53:50 - Hymn - Living God your Joyful Spirit

53:54 - 54:12 - Blessing 

54:44 - 58:39 - Music after the service

#Church #Worship #Sing #Organ #Faithful #Jesus #URC #UnitedReformedChurch  #Blessings #GoodNews #NIV #NIVUK #Bible #Lessons #GoodNews #Hymns #AllAreWelcome #JoinIn #Christian

#revelation #ANewHope #ANewHeaven #ANewJerusalem #AccidentalStarWars
#revelationexplained 
#worship #spiritualstruggle #goodvsevil #christcrucified #communion #heavenlypraise #almightygod #ChurchLife #FaithMatters #DavidCopperfield #TellYourStory

#Greenbelt @greenbeltfestival #SomewhereToBelieveIn #YourChurch</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="50"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:UXLW6P48NJY</id>
  <yt:videoId>UXLW6P48NJY</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 20th August 2023</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UXLW6P48NJY"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2023-08-20T22:58:46+00:00</published>
  <updated>2023-09-15T14:05:22+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 20th August 2023</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/UXLW6P48NJY?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/UXLW6P48NJY/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00 - Opening music, photos, and notices

Entry of Bible (please stand if you are able)

07:00 - Welcome and lighting of peace candle (Duty Elder)

08:10 - Call to worship (from Psalm 100)
Make a joyful noise to the Lord all the earth;
Let us worship the Lord with gladness.
Come into God’s presence with singing,
For we know the Lord is God.
God made us and we belong to God.

09:15 - HYMN R&amp;S 660 Hark what a sound

12:26 - 14:18 - Opening Prayer

14:19 - 21:33 - Introduction to reading – ‘all made new’
We're nearing the end of our series on Revelation 
Revelation is an amazing, strange, difficult book
It was debated if Revelation should be included in the Bible
But it was included and challenges, puzzles, and inspires us 
Our series has led us to the final chapters 21-22
These give a vision of new things, a new beginning 
A new heaven, new earth, and New Jerusalem 
It's not that heaven and earth don't exist anymore, but they are renewed 
Then I saw a new heaven and a new earth
Try something new

We are nearing the end of their sermon series on Revelation, which she describes as an amazing but difficult book that was debated for inclusion in the Bible but ultimately included. The series has led them to the final chapters 21-22, which give a vision of new things and a new beginning, including a new heaven, new earth, and New Jerusalem. This doesn't mean heaven and earth don't exist anymore, but they are renewed.

21:34 - 24:27 - A new heaven and new earth - Reading: Revelation 21. 1 – 7 (Good News)
read by John Hillson

24:57 - 27:06 - SONG R&amp;S 271 You are the king of glory

27:10 - 32:07 - A new Jerusalem - Reading: Revelation 21. 10 – 11, 21 – 26 read by John Hillson

32:17 - 38:11 - Talk: Light of our lives
The new Jerusalem needs no sun or moon to shine on it
The glory of God shines on it and the Lamb is its lamp 
Ancient people worshiped the sun for its life-giving light and warmth
The moon was seen as a lesser god, creating seasons and rhythms 
Cities produced their own light with oil lamps in John's day
But today's light pollution would astonish ancients
John knows the importance of light
But the true light is God's spiritual light - the glory of God
This has been seen in Jesus, the Lamb on the cross 
If we learn one thing from John, it is to worship the living God 
The theme of light, referring to the passage just read about how the New Jerusalem needs no sun or moon because God is its light. Ancient people worshiped the sun and moon but that John sees the true light as the spiritual light of God's glory, revealed in Jesus Christ. The main message from John is to worship the living God, not lesser things.

38:27 - 42:31 - SONG TP 62 Shine Jesus, shine

43:16 - 45:14 - A new hope for all the nations -Reading Revelation 22. 1 – 9 (Good News) read by Sue Thorne

45:23 - 51:23 - Talk: John’s Do’s and don'ts
John tries to take in all he's seen and heard in the vision 
He is overwhelmed and kneels to worship the angel
But the angel says &quot;Don't do it&quot; 
Don't worship me, worship God
Don't worship lesser things, only God 
Not the Bible, ministers, rulers, wealth, technology or military might 
The emperor demanded worship as God's son
But the angels say these words can be trusted - worship God
Jesus says happy are those who obey the prophetic words 
The message is simple - worship the living God

John is overwhelmed by the vision and kneels to worship the angel, but is told not to worship lesser things, only God. Rulers like the emperor demanded worship but angels tell John the words are true - worship God. The message is not to worship human rulers and powers but only the living God. This is the simple message to obey from Revelation.


51:48 - 53:30 - HYMN R&amp;S 265 I cannot tell (vs 4 only) sung seated

53:40 - Activity: healing leaves

01:14:25 - 01:18:55 - Prayers for the healing of the nations with response
Lord of life, bring healing; bring peace.

Lord’s Prayer (Modern version)

01:19:03 - 01:22:43 - HYMN R&amp;S 90 O Lord all the world belongs to you

01:22:43 - 01:23:12 - Final prayer and Blessing
The grace of the Lord Jesus Christ be with us all.
Amen. Come, Lord Jesus.

01:23:37 - 01:28:07 - Music after the service

#Church #Worship #Sing #Organ #Faithful #Jesus #URC #UnitedReformedChurch  #Blessings #GoodNews #NIV #NIVUK #Bible #Lessons #GoodNews #Hymns #AllAreWelcome #JoinIn #Christian

#revelation #ANewHope #ANewHeaven #ANewJerusalem #AccidentalStarWars
#revelationexplained 
#worship #spiritualstruggle #goodvsevil #christcrucified #communion #heavenlypraise #almightygod #SPAENG #ENGSPA #Lionesses #FIFWWC</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="35"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:UjS76QYpibI</id>
  <yt:videoId>UjS76QYpibI</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 6th August 2023</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UjS76QYpibI"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2023-08-06T22:57:21+00:00</published>
  <updated>2023-08-23T21:44:28+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 6th August 2023</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/UjS76QYpibI?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/UjS76QYpibI/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00 - Opening music, photos, and notices

09:28 - Entry of the bible and welcome

09:35 - Welcome and lighting of peace candle (Duty Elder)

11:43 - Call to worship (from Psalm 46)
God is our refuge and strength,
Always ready to help in trouble.
Therefore we will not fear, though the earth should change,
though the mountains shake in the heart of the sea;
God is in our midst of the city, we shall not be moved;
God will help us when the morning dawns.
The nations are in an uproar, the kingdoms totter;
God utters his voice, the earth melts.
The LORD of hosts is with us;
the God of Jacob is our refuge.

12:43 - 16:04 - Hymn -  Meekness and majesty

16:09 - 17:49 - Opening Prayers

17:54 - Introduction to the reading

18:58 - Reading: Revelation 7.9 – 12 (minister and congregation)
 
20:06 - 30:48 - All age Talk: ‘After Alpha’ 
The book of Revelation has many oddities and strangeness but its main theme is worshiping God.
It calls us to put aside other things that demand worship and focus on glorifying God.
Revelation gives glimpses of heavenly worship with people and angels praising God.
We began looking at Revelation and its vision of God as Alpha and Omega - the beginning and end.
Our purpose is to glorify God who encompasses all eternity.
After Alpha comes Beta - we are covering chapters 6-19 today.
These chapters describe the spiritual battle between good and evil.
But there are also beautiful encouraging words like blessings and the bridegroom.
We must hold onto all that is good, truthful and beautiful.
Remember verses calling us to worship and honor God, the one who created heaven and earth.
The Book of Revelation, despite its strangeness, calls us to worship God above all else. We get glimpses of heavenly praise, and are reminded that God is the beginning and end - our purpose is to glorify Him. Though the middle chapters describe spiritual struggle, they also have beautiful words about God's blessings and love. We must hold onto the good and continue worshiping the Creator.

31:11 - 33:00 - Song -  All heaven declares

33:10 - 44:38 - Introduction, readings and silent prayer
33:10 - Introduction to today’s readings: ‘among the dragons, horsemen and beasts, plagues and trumpets’

38:41 - Reading: Revelation 8. 1 - 5 NIVUK read by Arthur

Silent Prayer

40:10 - Reading: Revelation 11. 15 – 19 NIVUK read by Ian

Silent Prayer

42:00 - Reading: Revelation 18. 20 – 19.5 read by Arthur

45:20 - 48:24 - Hymn -  Blessed assurance

48:34 - 01:00:16 - Short Address
Revelation repeatedly calls us to simple heartfelt worship of God.
It invites us to put aside earthly idols that demand our worship.
John wrote Revelation when Christians faced persecution from the Roman empire.
The churches he wrote to were frightened by the empire's military might.
But John reminds them that Rome is not the ultimate power - God is.
There is a spiritual battle between good and evil described in these chapters.
Though it talks of destructive forces, God can destroy destruction without being destructive.
Heaven falls silent so God can hear the cries of his people on earth.
At the communion table, we proclaim the lamb sacrificed on the cross as the ultimate power, not political or military forces.
We must continue to worship God amidst life's struggles, holding onto all that is good.
We explore Revelation's call to worship God above all earthly powers. Though the middle chapters describe spiritual battles, John reminds us that God, not the mighty Roman empire, is the ultimate power. God destroys evil without being destructive himself. Overall we are to worship God amidst life's struggles, proclaiming Christ's sacrifice as the greatest power.

59:19 - Reading: Revelation 19.6 – 9a read by Ian 

01:00:59 - 01:04:14 - Hymn - Jesus calls us here to meet him

01:04:17 - Communion: we invite you to share in the bread and wine at church (or at home) united in the name of Christ.

01:04:57 - A Prayer of thanksgiving (based on words from Revelation)
Lord’s Prayer
 
01:08:45 - Distribution of bread and wine (non-alcoholic grape juice)

01:13:55 - 01:16:58 - Closing Prayer

01:17:35 - 01:20:31 - Hymn - R&amp;S 584 The day thou gavest Lord is ended

01:20:33 - 01:20:56 - Blessing

01:21:27 - 01:24:30 - Music after the service

#revelation 
#revelationexplained 
#worship #spiritualstruggle #goodvsevil #christcrucified #communion #heavenlypraise #almightygod
#Hiroshima #Nagasaki

#Church #Worship #Sing #Organ #Faithful #Jesus #URC #UnitedReformedChurch  #Blessings #GoodNews #NIV #NIVUK #Bible #Lessons #GoodNews #Hymns #AllAreWelcome #JoinIn #Christian</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="34"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:-_E3yl-0498</id>
  <yt:videoId>-_E3yl-0498</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 30th July 2023</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-_E3yl-0498"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2023-07-30T22:53:12+00:00</published>
  <updated>2023-09-05T14:48:17+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 30th July 2023</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/-_E3yl-0498?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/-_E3yl-0498/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00 - Opening music, photos, and notices

00:52 - Entry of the bible and welcome

03:19 - Call to worship: Psalm 103.1, 11, 17-19

05:19 - 08:37 - Hymn – Praise my soul the king of heaven 

08:43 - 11:44 - Opening Prayers and the Lo53:30 - rd’s Prayer

11:54 - 16:04 - Talk for all ages: ‘The king and the kingdom’
Jesus often taught people using parables - stories that related to everyday life
Parables helped people understand Jesus' message through familiar examples
Many parables were about farming, baking bread, family relationships
If Jesus was here today, parables might use modern examples like technology, business, shopping
The word &quot;parable&quot; means to place beside as a comparison or illustration
There are about 40 parables total in the Bible, with the most in Matthew and Luke
Matthew 13 has 7 parables in a row, mostly about the Kingdom of Heaven
The Kingdom of Heaven refers not just to heaven, but God's kingdom on earth too
Jesus came as our King to show God's love and wants us to be part of God's kingdom
Reflecting on parables helps us understand more about God's love and kingdom

16:24 - Hymn – The kingdom of God is justice and Joy

19:04 - Blessing as Junior Church go to their activities (if the children
stay in there will be activities in back corner for them):
Adults: May the Lord be with you
Junior Church: And also with you
All: Amen

19:31 - 25:19 - Bible Readings
19:31 -  Introduction to Bible readings

20:33 - Reading: 1 Kings 3. 5-15 read by Linda

22:46 - Reading: Matthew 13. 31-33, 44-52 read by Harri

25:45 - 28:50 - Hymn – Be thou my vision

29:00 - Prayer

30:01 - 53:30 - Sermon: “The kingdom of heaven …”
The parable of the mustard seed shows the kingdom started small but grew greatly.
The parable of the yeast shows how the kingdom expands and multiplies.
The treasure and pearl show the great value of the kingdom.
The net parable refers to final judgment and separation of good/wicked.
Solomon exemplifies using discernment to govern justly as part of God's kingdom.
God blessed Solomon with wisdom when he sought to discern God's will as king.
We are not fully living in God's kingdom now with all the world's problems.
But we can see signs of God's kingdom through people helping others.
Our role is to help grow God's kingdom by discerning and doing God's will.
Reflecting on parables helps us understand our part in advancing God's kingdom.
Examining the parables reminds us to discern God's will so we can help grow His righteous kingdom.

53:40 - 55:58 - Hymn – Give to me, Lord, a thankful heart

56:11 - 01:01:54 - Prayers for others and ourselves

01:02:03 - Review of Lighthouse High Wycombe

01:06:37 - Hymn – Love Divine all loves excelling 

01:10:13 - 01:10:33 - Closing blessing
01:10:58 - 01:14:45 - Music after the service

#KingdomOfGod
#Parables
#SeekingDiscernment
#AdvancingKingdom
#GodsLove

#Church #Worship #Sing #Organ #Faithful #Jesus #URC #UnitedReformedChurch  #Blessings #GoodNews #NIV #NIVUK #Bible #Lessons #GoodNews #Hymns #AllAreWelcome #JoinIn #Christian</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="1" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="29"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:RtiFdvJ1hBU</id>
  <yt:videoId>RtiFdvJ1hBU</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 23rd July 2023</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RtiFdvJ1hBU"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2023-07-23T22:48:41+00:00</published>
  <updated>2023-07-26T21:52:00+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 23rd July 2023</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/RtiFdvJ1hBU?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/RtiFdvJ1hBU/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00 - Opening music, photos, and notices - 

03:56 - Entry of the Bible

00:04:18 - Welcome and lighting of peace candle (Duty Elder)

00:06:16 - Call to worship - Matthew 6: 31&amp;33

00:06:52 - 00:10:22 - HYMN - R&amp;S 104 – Praise, my soul, the King of heaven

10:30 - 17:21 - Opening Prayer and Lord's Prayer

17:29 - 20:34 - Reading: Matthew 13:31-33, 44-50

20:42 - 29:58 - Talk for all ages – The kingdom of God
The kingdom of God is not a place, club or building.
It is a personal encounter with God through prayer, listening and obedience.
We experience the kingdom when we are in communion with God.
When we listen and obey God, we experience more of the kingdom.
The kingdom is defined by God's perfect love.
The kingdom seems beyond limits of time.
We can feel far from God and the kingdom when life is hard.
But God's love remains through good and bad times.
The Lord's Prayer says the kingdom comes when God's will is done on earth.
As we follow God's will, we experience more of the kingdom.

The kingdom of God is not a physical place, but rather a personal encounter with God through prayer, diligent listening and obedience. We experience the kingdom when we are in full communion with the Lord, truly listening and following His will. The more we listen and obey, the more we live in the kingdom. God's perfect love defines the kingdom, which seems beyond earthly limits of time. Though we can feel far from God when life gets hard, His love remains constant. The kingdom comes when God's will is done on earth, as the Lord's Prayer says. As we seek and follow the will of God in our lives, we come to know the kingdom in a real and personal way.


00:30:27 - 00:33:09 - HYMN - R&amp;S 141 – Make way, make way

00:33:11 - 37:07 - Reading: Romans 8: 31-39

00:37:54 - 40:24 - HYMN: R&amp;S 200 – The kingdom of God is justice and joy

00:40:28 - 00:53:39 - Address: The Kingdom of God. followed by a time of quiet reflection
Why do people come to church?  The promise of eternal life is not a motivating factor.
The kingdom of God is exciting but hard to grasp
Jesus told parables to describe the kingdom
The kingdom starts small but grows large
It changes us with just a small presence
The kingdom is of greatest value
We must seek the kingdom like hidden treasure
It is for everyone, no one is excluded
God's perfect love defines the kingdom
The kingdom is beyond limits of time
We live the kingdom by following God's will
Jesus used parables to convey the kingdom of God, which begins humbly but grows to greatness. Though elusive, we must seek the kingdom like a treasure.  It holds supreme value and is defined by God's perfect love, extending to all people without limits of time. We live the kingdom by seeking and following God's will in our lives.

00:54:21 - 00:58:10 - HYMN - R&amp;S 107 – The love of God comes close

00:58:54 - 01:03:53 - Prayers for the church and the world

01:04:11 - 01:06:39 - HYMN - R&amp;S 293 – Ye servants of God

01:06:40 - 01:07:03 - Closing blessing

01:07:24 - 01:12:21 - Music, notices and photos after the service

01:12:39 - RIP John Standfield

#KingdomOfGod
#GodsLove
#SeekTheKingdom
#JesusParables
#AllAreWelcome

#Church #Worship #Sing #Organ #Faithful #Jesus #URC #UnitedReformedChurch  #Blessings #GoodNews #NIV #NIVUK #Bible #Lessons #GoodNews #Hymns #AllAreWelcome #JoinIn #Christian

#Revelation #AlphaAndOmega #BookOfRevelation #WhatDoesItAllMean</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="26"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:XE4V8KXvOAs</id>
  <yt:videoId>XE4V8KXvOAs</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 16th July 2023</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XE4V8KXvOAs"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2023-07-16T23:00:17+00:00</published>
  <updated>2023-08-25T20:51:42+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 16th July 2023</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/XE4V8KXvOAs?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/XE4V8KXvOAs/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00 - Opening music, photos, and notices - 

03:52 - Entry of the bible

04:04 - Welcome and lighting of peace candle (Duty Elder)

06:00 - Call to worship
This is the day that the LORD has made;
we will rejoice and be glad in it.
It is good to give thanks to the Lord
For God’s love endures for ever.

06:38 - Hymn - R&amp;S 377 This is the day, this is the day

09:09 - 10:11 - Opening Prayer

10:15 - 17:15 - Introduction and reading 

10:15 - Introduction to reading – a glimpse of heaven

14:45 - Reading: Revelation 4 (Good News)


18:15 - 21:32 - Song - MP 1040 Come now is the time to worship

21:38 - Activity: ‘flight of praise’

31:11 - WORSHIP SONGS led by Praise Group
MP 883 Lord I lift your name on high
MP454 Majesty, worship His Majesty

37:39 - 45:45 - Short Talk: ‘Numbers and symbols’
The sermon reflects on the imagery in Revelation, especially the four &quot;heavenly creatures&quot; repr esenting all creation worshiping God, and the image of Jesus as a sacrificed lamb. The preacher discusses how Revelation reveals the glory and majesty of God.
Revelation is a visionary book filled with symbolic imagery and numbers.
It reveals God's heavenly perspective on history and current events.
The four &quot;heavenly creatures&quot; may represent the heights of creation - lion, ox, eagle, human.
They are also linked to the four Gospel writers - lion for Mark, human for Matthew, ox for Luke, eagle for John.
Numbers like 4, 7, and 12 have symbolic meaning coming from the Old Testament.
Revelation portrays heaven as a place of continuous worship with God at the center.
Jesus is portrayed as a sacrificed lamb, showing he conquered through self-sacrifice.
The slain lamb is worthy to open the scroll of God's plans.
The creatures and elders in heaven continually worship God and the lamb.
Revelation invites Christians on earth to join in the heavenly worship and praise of God.
The Book of Revelation uses vivid symbolic imagery and numbers, like the number 7 representing completeness, to reveal God's majestic heavenly realm, where the four wondrous creatures representing all of creation along with the twenty-four elders continually worship the Lord Almighty. At the center of this glorious worship stands the sacrificed Lamb, Jesus Christ, who is worthy to fulfill God's eternal plans. By portraying this awe-inspiring scene of ongoing praise in heaven, Revelation invites Christians on earth to envision ourselves participating in this eternal worship, caught up in wonder and awe of our magnificent, loving Creator and Redeemer. As we join in praise of God and the Lamb, we align our lives to their purposes and participate here and now in the cosmic worship that continues forever around God's throne.

46:27 - 49:43 - Hymn - R&amp;S 34 Holy, holy, holy

49:52 - Recap: Bible Project Video on Revelation 1 – 5

57:17 - 58:05 - Reading: Revelation 5 (NIVUK) read by David and Valerie
11 Then I looked and heard the voice of many angels, numbering
thousands upon thousands, and ten thousand times ten thousand. They
encircled the throne and the living creatures and the elders. 12 In a loud
voice they were saying:
‘Worthy is the Lamb, who was slain,
to receive power and wealth and wisdom and strength
and honour and glory and praise!’
13 Then I heard every creature in heaven and on earth and under the
earth and on the sea, and all that is in them, saying:
‘To him who sits on the throne and to the Lamb
be praise and honour and glory and power,
for ever and ever!’ AMEN.

58:10 - Music from Handel’s Messiah ‘Worthy is the Lamb’

01:02:13 - 01:09:13 - Prayers for the church today – 7 lights – with response
Lord of life shine your light.
Lord’s Prayer (Modern version)

01:10:02 - 01:12:28 - Hymn R&amp;S 666 Sing we the song

01:12:29 - 01:13:10 - Final prayer and Blessing

01:13:25 - 01:16:30 - Music, notices and photos after the service

#RevelationRevealed #RevelationExplained

#Church #Worship #Sing #Organ #Faithful #Jesus #URC #UnitedReformedChurch  #Blessings #GoodNews #NIV #NIVUK #Bible #Lessons #GoodNews #Hymns #AllAreWelcome #JoinIn #Christian

#Revelation #AlphaAndOmega #BookOfRevelation #WhatDoesItAllMean

#Revelation #HeavenlyWorship #PraiseGod #ChurchService #SundayService #BibleStudy #Sermon #BookOfRevelation #JesusLambOfGod #SacrificedLamb #EternalWorship #CosmicPraise #FourCreatures #24Elders #SymbolicImagery #HeavenlyRealm #GodsMajesty #GodsGlory #JoinInPraise #ContinualWorship</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="18"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:3-zSoCRNxHM</id>
  <yt:videoId>3-zSoCRNxHM</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 9th July 2023</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3-zSoCRNxHM"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2023-07-09T22:56:26+00:00</published>
  <updated>2023-08-29T08:47:59+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 9th July 2023</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/3-zSoCRNxHM?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/3-zSoCRNxHM/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00 - Opening music, photos, and notices - 

05:26 - Entry of the Bible

05:27 - Welcome and lighting of the peace candle

08:33 - Call to worship

09:29 - 13:33 - Hymn -  RS 195 I danced in the morning [Tune: Shaker tune]

13:42 - 16:23 - Opening Prayers
Lord’s Prayer

16:51 - 24:10 - Talk for all ages
Rebekah in the bible
Rebekah was the wife of Isaac in the Bible.
Isaac was the son of Abraham, one of the patriarchs of the Hebrew nation.
Abraham wanted Isaac to marry someone who worshipped the one true God, not the pagan gods of Canaan.
Abraham sent his servant to find a wife for Isaac from his relatives in Haran.
The servant met Rebekah at a well and she offered him water.
The servant told Rebekah she was chosen to marry Isaac. She agreed to go with him.
Rebekah left her family and traveled to Canaan to marry Isaac.
At the time, Abraham's family still worshipped pagan idols.
Abraham wanted to protect Isaac from pagan influence with his marriage.
Rebekah bravely and faithfully left her home to marry Isaac, revealing her trust in God's plan.
Even though Abraham's own family were still worshipping idols, Rebekah had such strong faith that she left her home and family behind. She set off on a long journey to the foreign land of Canaan to marry a man she had never met. Rebekah’s story shows remarkable trust in God and willingness to follow His plan, even when it required great courage and sacrifice on her part. She truly inspires us to have faith and follow God’s calling in our own lives today.

24:57 - 26:15 - Hymn R&amp;S 197 Jesus’ hands were kind hands
[Tune: Au clair de la lune]

26:40 - Offering Prayer (a collection is not taken up, but there are
bowls for any donations and many give by standing order – we
offer all our gifts – time, talents and money – to God).

Shared blessing with Junior Church
Adults: May the Lord be with you
Junior Church: And also with you. AMEN.

27:18 - 35:32 - Bible Readings:
28:06 - Genesis 24:34-38, 42-49, 58-67 NIVUK read by Rosemary Taylor
33:34 - 35:32 - Matthew 11:16-19, 25-30 NIVUK read by Larry Ogbewe

35:50 - 38:08 - HYMN RS 558 Will you come and follow me?
[Tune: Kelvingrove]

38:18 - 52:44 - Sermon
Finding out about God
The Old Testament shows gradual revelation of God over time.
The New Testament revelation through Jesus was fuller.
We don't know for certain if Jesus said the words in Matthew about no one knowing the Father except the Son.
The Gospels were written long after Jesus' life.
Matthew, as a disciple, likely remembered Jesus' important teachings.
Jesus reveals God to the marginalized, not the arrogant.
Matthew passage shows Jesus' frustration at people missing his message.
Genesis shows early stages of understanding God.
We must be humble and open to ongoing revelation, not arrogant about our knowledge.
In today’s sermon, we explore the theme of “Finding Out About God.” 
How the Old Testament shows a gradual revelation of God unfolding over many years. Contrast this to the time of Jesus, when we see fuller revelation of God’s nature and purpose. 
Now the Gospels were written decades after Jesus lived, so we can’t be certain he actually spoke the words in Matthew about no one knowing the Father except the Son. But as a disciple, Matthew likely remembered Jesus’ most important teachings. The passage shows Jesus’ frustration that people were missing his message about God’s love and salvation. Jesus reveals God to the poor and marginalized, not the arrogant. Going back to Genesis, we see the early stages of humanity just beginning to understand who God is. For us today, the lesson is that we must remain humble and open to ongoing revelation of God through Christ. We must not become arrogant or think we have perfect knowledge already. May we keep seeking God with childlike faith, wonder and curiosity.

53:11 - 56:45 - HYMN RS 579 Lord, thy Church on earth is seeking
[Tune: Abbots Leigh]

56:54 - 01:01:09 - Prayers of intercession

01:01:35 - 01:04:41 - HYMN RS 349 I heard the voice of Jesus say
[Tune: Kingsfold]

01:04:47 - 01:05:27 - Final prayer and Blessing

01:05:48 - 01:14:30 - Music, notices and photos after the service

#Church #Worship #Sing #Organ #Faithful #Jesus #URC #UnitedReformedChurch  #Blessings #GoodNews #NIV #NIVUK #Bible #Lessons #GoodNews #Hymns #AllAreWelcome #JoinIn #Christian

#Revelation #AlphaAndOmega #BookOfRevelation</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="15"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:-B9w2IkYxg4</id>
  <yt:videoId>-B9w2IkYxg4</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 2nd July 2023</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-B9w2IkYxg4"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2023-07-02T22:55:48+00:00</published>
  <updated>2023-08-31T23:05:01+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 2nd July 2023</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/-B9w2IkYxg4?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/-B9w2IkYxg4/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00 - Opening music, photos, and notices - 

04:25 - Entry of the Bible

04:38 - Welcome and lighting of the peace candle

06:55 - Call to worship  (Psalm 117)
All of you nations, come praise the Lord!
Let everyone praise our Gracious God.
God's love is wonderful; God’s faithfulness never ends.
Shout praises to the Lord!

07:30 -Hymn - R&amp;S 261  At the name of Jesus (Tune Camberwell)

10:34 - 12:47 - Opening Prayers 

12:50 - 25:00 - All age Talk: ‘Beginning and ending, alpha and omega’ 
The theme of beginnings and endings, both in life and in literature.
Examples of beginnings and endings including new jobs, the start of the Premier League season, the flow of the Thames River, the story of Peter Rabbit, and the start of school holidays.
The Book of Revelation as a strange and often misunderstood book, but encourages exploration and finding the treasures within it.
The Book of Revelation is described as a record of events revealed by Jesus Christ to the servant John.
God is much bigger than our comprehension and is eternal.
Jesus Christ is described as the faithful Witness, the ruler of kings, and the one who loves and freed us from sin.
Don't misuse the Book of Revelation but engage in individual exploration rather than relying on external interpretations. In particular, don't just Google the book of revelation
Approach the book with bravery and listen to the Spirit speaking to them.

&quot;God is always bigger than our comprehension.&quot; 
&quot;The Book of Revelation: Find the treasures within.&quot;
&quot;Be brave enough to explore the Book of Revelation and hear the Spirit speaking to you.&quot; 

21:46 - Reading: Revelation 1. 1 – 8 (Good News)

25:41 - 28:04 - Song - MP 673  There is a redeemer

28:46 - 34:11 - Introduction to today’s readings
John as the #Spielberg of the Bible

29:55 - Reading: Revelation 1. 9 – 16 NIVUK read by Tony

31:39 - Reading: Revelation 3. 14 – 22 NIVUK read by Elsje

34:35 - 37:02 - Hymn - R&amp;S 405 Angel voices

37:10 - 49:54 - Short Address
The Book of Revelation can be challenging and bewildering, causing discomfort and fear for some readers.
There were debates in the early church about whether to include the Book of Revelation in the New Testament, but it ultimately became part of the Bible.
The book was written by John, who was exiled to the island of Patmos due to his witness, and it emerged from a context of persecution under the Roman Empire.
Revelation belongs to the apocalyptic genre, which contrasts earthly and heavenly life and speaks of a struggle between good and evil.
Violent imagery in Revelation should not be taken literally; at its core is Jesus, who sacrificed himself for humanity.
The book begins with letters to seven churches, including the church of Laodicea, which is criticized for its complacency and lukewarm faith.
Jesus is portrayed as knocking on the door of the Laodicean church, urging them to open their hearts and let him in.
The invitation to open the door symbolizes a personal and intimate relationship with Jesus.
The book invites readers to open their hearts, minds, spirits, and lives to the loving Lord, who offers forgiveness, purpose, and love.

&quot;Do not panic. If you don't warm to the Book of Revelation, you're in good company.&quot;
&quot;Be patient with the book; it's full of imagery. It isn't a description of reality as such; it was a vision that came to John in the context of worship.&quot;
&quot;Here I am, I stand at the door and knock. If anyone hears my voice and opens the door, I will come in and eat with them and they with me.&quot;



50:31 - 51:34 - Hymn - R&amp;S 308  Spirit of the Living God

51:38 - 57:22 - Welcome of Valerie and Stephen into church membership by reaffirmation:

57:43 - 58:48 - Hymn - R&amp;S 309  Spirit of the Living God

58:59 - 01:09:10 - Communion: we invite you to share in the bread and wine at church (or at home) united in the name of Christ.

A Prayer of thanksgiving and Lord’s Prayer

Distribution of bread and wine (in church non-alcoholic grape juice)

01:09:17 - 01:11:36 - Closing Prayer

01:12:09 - 01:15:23 - Hymn - R&amp;S 262  Crown him with many crowns

01:15:24 - 01:15:58 - Blessing (based on Revelation 1.5,6 and 22.21)
Jesus Christ loves us, and by his sacrificial death he has freed us from our sins 6 and made us a kingdom of priests to serve his God and Father. To Jesus Christ be the glory and power forever and ever!  And the grace of the Lord Jesus be with us and all people today and for evermore.  Amen.

01:16:21 - 01:18:38 - Music, notices and photos after the service

#Church #Worship #Sing #Organ #Faithful #Jesus #URC #UnitedReformedChurch  #Blessings #GoodNews #NIV #NIVUK #Bible #Lessons #GoodNews #Hymns #AllAreWelcome #JoinIn #Christian

#Revelation #AlphaAndOmega #BookOfRevelation</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="11"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:5Nk3v0j0FnQ</id>
  <yt:videoId>5Nk3v0j0FnQ</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 25th June 2023</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5Nk3v0j0FnQ"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2023-06-25T22:59:51+00:00</published>
  <updated>2023-08-28T06:23:06+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 25th June 2023</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/5Nk3v0j0FnQ?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/5Nk3v0j0FnQ/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00 - Opening music, photos, and notices - 

07:47 - Entry of the bible

08:31 - Welcome and lighting of peace candle (an elder)

09:56 - Call to worship

11:43 - 13:20 - Hymn: O breath of life come sweeping through us (R&amp;amp;S 302) Tune: Spiritus Vitae

13:30 - Opening Prayers and the Lord’s Prayer

17:00 - 21:24 - Hymn: I the Lord of sea and sky

21:37 - Blessing as Junior Church go to their activities:
Adults: May the Lord be with you
Junior Church: And also with you.
All: Amen.

22:20 - Prayer before the readings

22:42 - 35:06 - Bible Readings

22:42 - Introduction to Bible readings

24:53 - Reading: Genesis 18: 1-15, and 21: 1-7
read by Sue Thorne

32:06 - 35:06 - Reading: Matthew 9: 35-38 and 10: 1-8
read by John Hillson

35:24 - 37:42 - Hymn: To Abraham and Sarah the call of God was clear (R&amp;S 553) Tune: Mountain Christians

37:55 - 51:37 - Sermon: followed by time of quiet reflection
3 key words: visitors, hospitality, compassion
The scriptures highlight the theme of visitors and hospitality, starting with Abraham and Sarah encountering three visitors in Genesis.
People in the Bible are constantly on the move, encountering new situations and meeting strangers, emphasizing the theme of journeys and travel.
Change and unexpected circumstances can disrupt and transform our lives, whether by our own choices, actions of others, sickness, suffering, or blessings.
God is found amidst our wanderings and encounters, often visiting us in surprising and unrecognized ways, delivering blessings beyond our imagination.
Jesus is the ultimate visitor, entering fully into human life, teaching, healing, and showing compassion to those in need, revealing God's new way of being with us.
Jesus' presence transcends time and space through his death, resurrection, and Ascension, making his home forever with us.
Suffering and need are prevalent in the world, and amidst these realities, the stories of Abraham, Sarah, and Jesus offer hope, compassion, and love.
God invites people to join in the work of compassion and salvation, as seen in Abraham and Sarah being part of God's unfolding story and the disciples being commissioned and sent out.
The disciples' names and our own names are part of the ongoing story of God's saving and renewing all of creation, with unique callings and opportunities for each individual.
As we respond to God's call, we can be answers to prayer, revealing God's heart of compassion, seeking justice, and taking action, even if the laborers may seem few.
Welcoming people in need


52:00 - 54:14 - Hymn: Will you come and follow me? (R&amp;amp;S 558)
Tune: Kelvingrove

54:24 - 56:32 - Prayers for others and ourselves

56:39 - Prayer of thanksgiving for the offertory

57:13 - 01:00:38 - Hymn: Love divine, all loves excelling (R&amp;amp;S 663)
Tune Blaenwern

01:00:43 - 01:01:00 - Closing blessing

01:01:35 - 01:05:12 - Music, notices and photos after the service

#Church #Worship #Sing #Organ #Faithful #Jesus #URC #UnitedReformedChurch  #Blessings #GoodNews #NIV #NIVUK #Bible #Lessons #GoodNews #Hymns #AllAreWelcome #JoinIn #Christian #WarmSpace #WednesdayCafe #RejoiceandSing

 #compassion  #hospitality #refugees

#Rainbow #RainbowUmbrella #Umbrella #UmbrellaSky

#SummarisedWithChatGPT #ChatGPT #GoogleBARD #BARD #LLM</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="29"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:wde1MsJnXUk</id>
  <yt:videoId>wde1MsJnXUk</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 18th June 2023</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wde1MsJnXUk"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2023-06-19T00:04:58+00:00</published>
  <updated>2023-08-30T01:08:14+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 18th June 2023</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/wde1MsJnXUk?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/wde1MsJnXUk/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00 - Opening music, photos, and notices - 

08:08 - Entry of the bible

08:15 - Welcome and lighting of peace candle (an elder)

11:07 - Call to worship – Psalm 51 vs 1 - 3 &amp;amp; 10 - 12

12:12 - 15:44 - Hymn R&amp;S 47 O worship the King all glorious above

15:46 - Opening Prayers and the Lord’s Prayer

17:35 - Reading: 1 John Ch 3 vs 1 – 3

17:35 - 22:40 - Talk for all ages “What are you worth?”
God values you, you have worth, even if you have made mistakes.
God loves you so much that he gave his son for you.
Don't ever think that you have no value.
God sees you the way that Jesus sees you.
You are perfect in Christ.
You may be going through a tough time, but God still loves you.
God will exchange his son for you.
You are worth as much as God originally made you to be.
God is our heavenly father, and he is the shepherd who leads us.
Comparing a 10-pound note to a person's worth. Even if the note is wrinkled or damaged, it is still worth 10 pounds.

22:54 - Worship Song - The Lord’s my Shepherd I’ll not want
(Stuart Townend)

25:54 - Blessing as Junior Church go to their activities:
Adults: May the Lord be with you
Junior Church: And also with you.
All: Amen.

26:19 - 29:42 - Readings

26:19 - Introduction to Bible readings

26:56 - Readings: Psalm 116 vs 1, &amp;amp; 10 – 17
read by Arthur Winning

28:08 - Romans Ch 5 vs 1 – 8 read by Jeany Bien

30:52 - Hymn - How deep the Father’s love for us

34:31 - 56:18 - Address “God demonstrates His Love”
followed by time of quiet reflection
The sermon emphasizes that being a Christian is about what God has done through Jesus Christ, not our own actions or words.
Jesus was credited as righteous by God for paying the penalty of sin, even though he was without sin himself.
We cannot pay the debt of our sin ourselves; it requires a perfect sacrifice, which Jesus provided as the Lamb of God.
By putting our sins on Jesus and accepting him through faith, we are considered righteous in God's sight.
Through Jesus' death and resurrection, our sins have been paid for, and we are set free from the penalty of sin.
Faith is crucial in accepting this freedom and trusting in what Jesus and God have promised.
Our trust in God should not waver, even in the face of suffering, as it produces endurance, character, and hope.
God's love for us is demonstrated by Christ's death for sinners, even when we were still ungodly.
We are justified and have peace with God through faith, becoming his children and sharing in his glory.
Reading God's word helps us grow spiritually and deepen our faith, as it reveals the character and love of God.
Suffering should not discourage or deter believers from their faith, but rather it should be seen as an opportunity for spiritual growth and an occasion to deepen our trust in God


56:45 - 01:00:32 - Hymn - I know not why God’s wondrous grace

01:00:59 - 01:03:32 - Prayers for others and ourselves

01:03:52 - 01:05:50 - Hymn R&amp;S - 495 Father hear the prayer we offer

01:06:06 - 01:06:34 - Closing blessing

01:07:33 - 01:09:38 - Music and notices after the service

#Church #Worship #Sing #Organ #Faithful #Jesus #URC #UnitedReformedChurch  #Blessings #GoodNews #NIV #NIVUK #Bible #Lessons #GoodNews #Hymns #AllAreWelcome #JoinIn #Christian #WarmSpace #WednesdayCafe #RejoiceandSing #Compassion 

#Ashes #HowToWatchCricket #LeatherOnWillow 

#RIPJohnStandfield

#SummarisedWithChatGPT #ChatGPT #GoogleBARD #BARD #LLM</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="26"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:4COPBAjLCB4</id>
  <yt:videoId>4COPBAjLCB4</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 11th June 2023</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4COPBAjLCB4"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2023-06-11T23:01:29+00:00</published>
  <updated>2023-08-29T13:40:36+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 11th June 2023</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/4COPBAjLCB4?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/4COPBAjLCB4/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00 - Opening music, photos, and notices - 

08:39 - Entry of the bible

08:59 - Welcome and lighting of peace candle (an elder)

11:16 - Call to worship (based on words from Psalm 103)
Praise the Lord my soul;
with our inmost being we praise God’s holy name
Do not forget all God’s blessings,
the God who forgives our sins
heals our diseases, redeems our life;
and crowns us with love and compassion.

12:12 - Hymn - MP 1259 Bless the Lord O my soul

16:19 - Opening Prayers and the Lord’s Prayer
18:49 - 21:38 - Introduction for all ages by Joe Parton

21:53 - Hymn - TP 98 When I needed a neighbour?

Blessing as Junior Church go to their activities:
Adults: May the Lord be with you
Junior Church: And also with you.
All: Amen.

24:20 - Introduction to the readings

25:03 - 27:59 - Readings: Luke 10. 25 – 37 NIVUK read by Connie Bolfrey

28:27 - 29:40 - Matthew 21. 12 – 17 NIVUK
read by Rosemary Taylor

29:58 - Hymn R&amp;S 648 Jesu, Jesu, fill us with your love

32:39 - 01:01:58 - Talk by Joe Parton followed by time of quiet reflection
The two children sponsored by our church, Christian and Mary, and mentions that other individuals in the congregation also sponsor children.
Compassion is a child-focused, church-based charity with projects in 29 countries, providing resources to alleviate poverty for sponsored children and their families.
The charity is Christ-centered, providing scripture in the children's own language and introducing them to Jesus as their savior.
The sponsored children have the opportunity to attend a project at a local church, where they receive education, socialize with other children, and are protected from unnecessary child labor.
The impact of sponsorships including over 4,300 hours spent in projects, nearly 1,500 nutritious meals provided, 24 medical checkups, and eight scriptures given to the children.
The countries where the sponsored children reside are Africa, Central and South America.
Additional financial support and gifts given by the church with examples of how these gifts have made a significant difference in the lives of the sponsored children and their families.
The personal connection between sponsors and children key, as is the exchange of letters and the profound impact it has on both the children and sponsors. 
#CompassionUK

01:02:28 - 01:06:59 - Hymn - MP 806 Beauty for brokenness

01:07:16 - 01:11:09 - Prayers for others and ourselves
led by Rosemary Taylor
Lord in your great compassion
hear our prayer.

01:11:30 - 01:13:47 - Hymn R&amp;S 620 For the healing of the nations

01:14:18 - 01:14:36 - Closing blessing

01:15:30 - 01:16:55 - Music and notices after the service

#Church #Worship #Sing #Organ #Faithful #Jesus #URC #UnitedReformedChurch  #Blessings #GoodNews #NIV #NIVUK #Bible #Lessons #GoodNews #Hymns #AllAreWelcome #JoinIn #Christian #WarmSpace #WednesdayCafe #RejoiceandSing #Compassion 



#SummarisedWithChatGPT #ChatGPT #GoogleBARD #BARD #LLM</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="27"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:wUlqrumtCpw</id>
  <yt:videoId>wUlqrumtCpw</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 4th June 2023</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wUlqrumtCpw"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2023-06-04T23:45:04+00:00</published>
  <updated>2023-09-04T12:19:02+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 4th June 2023</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/wUlqrumtCpw?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/wUlqrumtCpw/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00 - Opening music, photos, and notices - 

08:17 - Entry of the Bible
08:34 - Welcome and lighting of peace candle (an elder)

10:30 - Call to worship
On this Trinity Sunday,
we come to worship our Eternal Glorious God:
Father, Son and Holy Spirit 
So the amazing grace of our Lord Jesus Christ,
the overwhelming love of God
and the friendship of the Holy Spirit
be with us now, as we offer our thanks and praise

11:33 - 13:46 - Hymn R&amp;S 30  Father we love you 

14:03 - Opening Prayers

17:05 - Song R&amp;S 8 - Glory to God (unaccompanied)

18:42 - 28:00 - Introduction and reading
18:42 - 25:26 - Introduction for all ages: ‘tired?’
Tiredness is a common experience for everyone, including children and adults.
Tiredness can be caused by various factors, such as physical exertion, work, boredom, or lack of sleep.
Rest and renewal are necessary for maintaining energy and motivation.
Isaiah describes God as the Everlasting One who never grows tired or weary.
Trusting in God can lead to renewed strength and spiritual vitality.
Those who rely on God for help will find their weaknesses uplifted and their strength restored.
The imagery of rising on wings like eagles symbolizes gaining a new perspective and transcending daily struggles.
Even though eagles may not be present in the local area, the concept of being lifted by a powerful bird can be inspiring.
God's ability to lift and carry us signifies the potential for divine support and guidance.
Reflecting on the image of a red kite soaring in the sky can remind us of God's capacity to uplift and renew us.

25:46 - 28:00 - Reading Isaiah 40:12-17,27-31 (Good News) read by Ian

28:08 - Prayer 

28:50 - 31:45 - Hymn TP 13  Be still for the presence
Shared blessing with Junior Church
Adults:  May the Lord be with you
Junior Church: And also with you. AMEN.
Introduction to reading – what a way to finish!

32:50 - Our 2023 Gospel focus 

35:16 - 36:20 - Reading: Matthew 28.16-20 (Good News) read by Norma

36:44 - 39:14 - Hymn TP 81- Spirit of God

39:24 - 51:04 - Short Address
Trinity Sunday marks the culmination of the Christian year, reflecting on the journey from Advent to Easter and beyond.
Our church is named Trinity Church, emphasizing the unity and diversity of God's nature.
The disciples worshiped Jesus, recognizing him as both truly human and divine.
Doubts and questions are allowed in the journey of faith, and there is room for sceptics within the church.
Jesus declares his authority over heaven and earth, bridging the divide between the divine and human realms.
The commission is given to spread the universal message of God's love to all people.
The message is for everyone - all backgrounds, all sexualities, all races, and all religions.
Baptism is a way to immerse people in the love of God and introduce them to the lifestyle of following Jesus.
Learning and obedience are essential in deepening our understanding of what it means to follow Jesus.
Jesus promises to be with us always, even though unseen, and provides tangible signs of his presence in the sacraments.
The worship concludes with gratitude and assurance that Jesus is with us until the end of the age.

51:14 - Prayer for the world, the church and for ourselves

53:02 - 56:36 - Hymn TP 48  Jesus calls us

56:34 - Communion: we invite you to share in the bread and wine at church (or at home) united in the name of Christ.

A Prayer of thanksgiving
Lift up your hearts. 
We lift them to the Lord. 
Let us give thanks to the Lord our God. 
It is right to give our thanks and praise.
(Minister continues the prayer)
…For all these gifts we thank you, and we join with all your people on earth and in heaven, in joyful praise:

Holy, holy, holy Lord, God of power and might, heaven and earth are full of your glory. Hosanna in the highest. Blessed is he who comes in the name of the Lord. Hosanna in the highest.
(minister completes the prayer)

01:01:30 - Lord’s Prayer (traditional version)

01:07:41 - 01:12:10 - Closing Prayer and prayers for the world with response
Lord in your mercy
hear our prayer

01:12:32 - 01:15:03 - Hymn R&amp;S 38  Thou whose almighty word

01:15:04 - 01:15:30 - Blessing

01:16:20 - 01:19:40 - Music and notices after the service

#Church #Worship #Sing #Organ #Faithful #Jesus #URC #UnitedReformedChurch  #Blessings #GoodNews #NIV #NIVUK #Bible #Lessons #GoodNews #Hymns #AllAreWelcome #JoinIn #Christian #WarmSpace #WednesdayCafe #RejoiceandSing #Compassion 

#TrinitySunday #Communion #RedKite #Eagles #GreatCommission

#SummarisedWithChatGPT #ChatGPT #GoogleBARD #BARD #LLM</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="19"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
</feed>
