<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns:yt="http://www.youtube.com/xml/schemas/2015" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 <link rel="self" href="http://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=PLrggWHcy3azrunmSfTCSlS5JRuB4zTgCY"/>
 <id>yt:playlist:PLrggWHcy3azrunmSfTCSlS5JRuB4zTgCY</id>
 <yt:playlistId>PLrggWHcy3azrunmSfTCSlS5JRuB4zTgCY</yt:playlistId>
 <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
 <title>Worship services - Trinity and Cores End URCs</title>
 <author>
  <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
  <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
 </author>
 <published>2020-04-04T11:11:34+00:00</published>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:eFtyfvc8ap4</id>
  <yt:videoId>eFtyfvc8ap4</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship - Sunday 18th December 2022</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eFtyfvc8ap4"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-12-18T11:54:59+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-12-18T13:13:52+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship - Sunday 18th December 2022</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/eFtyfvc8ap4?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/eFtyfvc8ap4/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00:00 - Opening music, photos, and notices

10:14 - Welcome and lighting of peace candle (an elder)
Call to worship
God of creation, God of history:
God is here with us.
God of mystery, God of blessing:
God is here with us.
God in Jesus, God named Emmanuel:
God is here with us.

HYMN Joy to the world, the Lord is come (R&amp;amp;S 135)

Opening Prayers and Lord’s Prayer

Introduction: Nativity now – what part would you play?

CAROL The angel Gabriel (R&amp;amp;S 139)

Lighting the Advent candles
As we light the last candle before Christmas Day,
we give thanks for the role Mary and Joseph played in God’s
unfolding plan and pray:
God of all our lives, you call each of us to play a part in your story
and purposes for the world. As we give thanks for the courage
and the humility of Mary and Joseph, may shine your light into
the lives of others.
Draw us all to the Christmas stable, where hope is born and all
are loved, in Jesus’ name. Amen.

Reading: Isaiah 7.10 – 16 GN read by John Hillson (from chair)
10  The LORD sent another message to Ahaz:  11  “Ask the LORD your God to
give you a sign. It can be from deep in the world of the dead or from
high up in heaven.”

12  Ahaz answered, “I will not ask for a sign. I refuse to put the LORD to the
test.” 13  To that Isaiah replied, “Listen, now, descendants of King David.
It&amp;#39;s bad enough for you to wear out the patience of people—do you
have to wear out God&amp;#39;s patience too?  14  Well then, the Lord himself will
give you a sign: a young woman who is pregnant will have a son and will
name him ‘Immanuel.’  15  By the time he is old enough to make his own
decisions, people will be drinking milk and eating honey.  16  Even before
that time comes, the lands of those two kings who terrify you will be
deserted.

SONG Emmanuel, Emmanuel (MP 121) sung three times
Emmanuel, Emmanuel, His name is called Emmanuel
God with us, revealed in us – His name is called Emmanuel

Find Mary…find Joseph (carols R&amp;amp;S 144 – 181)

Matthew 1. 18 – 25 NIVUK read by Sue Thorne
18  This is how the birth of Jesus the Messiah came about: his mother
Mary was pledged to be married to Joseph, but before they came
together, she was found to be pregnant through the Holy
Spirit.  19  Because Joseph her husband was faithful to the law, and yet did
not want to expose her to public disgrace, he had in mind to divorce her
quietly. 20  But after he had considered this, an angel of the Lord
appeared to him in a dream and said, ‘Joseph son of David, do not be
afraid to take Mary home as your wife, because what is conceived in her
is from the Holy Spirit.  21  She will give birth to a son, and you are to give
him the name Jesus, because he will save his people from their sins.’
22  All this took place to fulfil what the Lord had said through the
prophet:  23  ‘The virgin will conceive and give birth to a son, and they will
call him Immanuel’ (which means ‘God with us’).
24  When Joseph woke up, he did what the angel of the Lord had
commanded him and took Mary home as his wife.  25  But he did not
consummate their marriage until she gave birth to a son. And he gave
him the name Jesus.

CAROL Joseph, son of David (Tune R&amp;amp;S 243 Noel nouvelet)
1. Joseph, son of David, son of Abraham;
regally descended, son of tent and psalm;
waited the day when, filled with joy and pride,
he would marry Mary, she would be his bride.

2. Joseph, though a poor man, with no wealth or fame,
yet possessed a treasure in his fam’ly name.
He must pass on this honour to his son,
in the line of David – then his job was done!
3. Yet, before the wedding, Mary was with child
and there was no father; ev’ryone went wild!
What could he do, to keep his name intact?
Mary must be banished! Surely he must act!
4. Calmly, at God’s prompting, Joseph held his ground,
risking, trusting, waiting; Mary still around.
Somehow he knew, though how he could not tell,
God would act through Jesus, all would then be well.
5. Showing such devotion, Joseph stood in line
with ancestral women working God’s design:
Rahab, and Tamar, Bathsheba and Ruth –
each, when others faltered, stood for hope and truth.
6. Now the gift of Joseph – ancestry and name –
graciously surrendered, nevermore the same;
offered to Jesus, ’til God’s work is done,
welcomes all the nations, seeks to make us one.
© John Campbell (based on Matthew 1)

Short Talk

SONG Born in the night, Mary’s child (R&amp;amp;S 188) sung seated

Prayers for each other and the world

CAROL See! In yonder manger low (R&amp;amp;S 157)

Blessing

Music, notices and photos

#Church #Worship #Advent  #AllAreWelcome #URC #UnitedReformedChurch #Hope #Isaiah #FourCandles #ForkHandles #Matthew</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="5"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:MBQLNs_bIYk</id>
  <yt:videoId>MBQLNs_bIYk</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship - Sunday 11th December 2022</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MBQLNs_bIYk"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-12-11T11:47:22+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-12-14T08:57:29+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship - Sunday 11th December 2022</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/MBQLNs_bIYk?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/MBQLNs_bIYk/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00:00 - Opening music, photos, and notices

07:35 - Welcome and lighting of peace candle (Linda as duty elder)

08:32 - Introduction – Linda

09:50 - 13:40 - Carol: In the Bleak Mid-Winter (R&amp;S 162)

13:46 - Story Telling – Julia
What are you looking forward to most about Christmas
Dinner
Cousins
Grandchildren
Now think back to when you were a child?
Presents
Stocking
Which do you like best - giving or receiving
Why do we give presents?
Enjoyment, showing our love for one another, reminding us of the first Christmas present wrapped in strips of cloth
Jesus was the first and best
Remembering our friends, family and God at Christmas
We need to receive, unwrap, thank, enjoy, and share our presents and God's present of Jesus

17:47 - 19:00 - Reading: Luke 2. 4-12 (NIVUK) – Samuel
4  So Joseph also went up from the town of Nazareth in Galilee to
Judea, to Bethlehem the town of David, because he belonged to
the house and line of David.  5  He went there to register with Mary,
who was pledged to be married to him and was expecting a
child.  6  While they were there, the time came for the baby to be
born,  7  and she gave birth to her firstborn, a son. She wrapped him
in cloths and placed him in a manger, because there was no guest
room available for them.
8  And there were shepherds living out in the fields near by, keeping
watch over their flocks at night.  9  An angel of the Lord appeared to
them, and the glory of the Lord shone around them, and they
were terrified.  10  But the angel said to them, ‘Do not be afraid. I
bring you good news that will cause great joy for all the
people.  11  Today in the town of David a Saviour has been born to
you; he is the Messiah, the Lord.  12  This will be a sign to you: you
will find a baby wrapped in cloths and lying in a manger.’

19:14 - 23:17 - Carol - We Three Kings of Orient Are

23:33 - 24:37 - Reading: Matthew 2. 1-2, 9-12 (NIVUK)
After Jesus was born in Bethlehem in Judea, during the time of
King Herod, Magi from the east came to Jerusalem  2  and asked,
‘Where is the one who has been born king of the Jews? We saw
his star when it rose and have come to worship him.’
9  After they had heard the king, they went on their way, and the
star they had seen when it rose went ahead of them until it
stopped over the place where the child was.  10  When they saw the
star, they were overjoyed.  11  On coming to the house, they saw the
child with his mother Mary, and they bowed down and
worshipped him. Then they opened their treasures and presented
him with gifts of gold, frankincense and myrrh.  12  And having been
warned in a dream not to go back to Herod, they returned to their
country by another route.

24:46 - Lighting of the Advent Candle – Samuel

26:18 - 29:30 - Carol - Good King Wenceslas (verses 1-3, 5)

29:37 - Introduction to Activities
- Print wrapping paper) – Sarah
- Christmas Stocking – Sarah
- Story Teller – Linda
- Edible Baby – Julia
- Themed crossword for those sitting – Ellen
- At home – Ellen

58:58 - 01:01:34 - Carol -  Come and Join the Celebration (R&amp;amp;S 166)

01:01:40 - Prayers and Lord’s Prayer – Sarah

01:06:32 - 01:19:56 - Carol - Hark the Herald Angels Sing (R&amp;amp;S 159)

01:10:03 - 01:10:40 - Messy Grace – Linda

01:10:56 - Music, notices and photos

#Church #Worship #Advent  #AllAreWelcome #URC #UnitedReformedChurch #Hope #Isaiah #Paul #Romans</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="14"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:C8h3HLFKpTk</id>
  <yt:videoId>C8h3HLFKpTk</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship - Sunday 4th December 2022</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=C8h3HLFKpTk"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-12-04T12:01:41+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-12-06T08:41:22+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship - Sunday 4th December 2022</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/C8h3HLFKpTk?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/C8h3HLFKpTk/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00:00 - Opening music, photos, and notices

08:30 - Welcome and lighting of peace candle (an elder)
#Ukraine 

10:20 - Call to worship (based on Psalm 72. 18,19)
Praise be to the Lord God, 
the God of Israel, the God of all people
the God who alone does marvellous deeds.
Praise be to God’s glorious name for ever;
may the whole earth be filled with God’s glory.
Seen in the Face of Jesus, Emmanuel, 
God with us for ever and ever.  Amen.

11:18 - 15:51 - Hymn - O come o come Emmanuel (R&amp;S 126 vs. 1 – 5)
Four candles and the great Os

16:11 - Prayer of adoration and confession

18:09 - Introduction for all ages: ‘Speaking up, speaking out’
Have any of  you joined a protest march?
Would you ever join one?
Cancel the debt?
Having a phobia of crowds, feeling uncomfortable in them but admiring those who do protest
What would you protest about?
CND, Mahsa Amini, China, Extinction Rebellion, Insulate Britain
Local protests
What would go on your banner?
Prayer as a kind of protest
&quot;It is better to light a candle than curse the darkness&quot;

27:30 - Lighting of 2nd Advent candle 
Reader: As we light the second Advent candle, 
  we remember the prophets of the past and the 
present, witnessing to the justice and peace God 
wants for this world.  And we pray that we too may 
be ready to speak out against evil and wrong and 
show God’s love today
All:  Lord Jesus, light of the world,
born to bring peace and love to a hurting world.
Help us to follow your way and to know your 
peace this Christmastide.  Amen. 

32:35 - 35:398 - Hymn -  Make way, make way (R&amp;S 141)

36:10 - Introducing the first reading: ‘a world transformed’

37:01 - 38:40 - Reading: Isaiah 11.1-10 (NIVUK) read by Eljse Hatton

39:10 - 42:10 - Hymn - Hills of the north rejoice vs 5 (CP 337)

42:18 - 43:52 - Reading: Romans 15.4-13 (NIVUK) read by Tony Hatton 

44:20 - Short Address
What does hope mean in your lives?
This is the season of hope and light
Sharing 3 pictures of hope
The great reading from Romans of hope overflowing
Take that hope home with you
Firstly from hundreds of years ago, a tiny middle eastern nation being surrounded and the invasion becoming a certainty
Isaiah delivered a message of hope to Judah
Secondly from a man who had endures much suffering in his life yet held on to the love of God and the hope of Christ
Paul writing to the Christians in Rome against the evil empire
Finally from Cambridge when studying economics
A small christian group called the ecumenical fellowship group
Meeting, discussing and planning social action, going to the local psychiatric hospital to sit with and talk to some of the patients



53:20 - 58:20 - Prayers for the church and the world 


58:40 - 01:01:10 - Hymn - Hark the glad sound (R&amp;S 137)  

01:01:18 - Thanksgiving Prayer and Lord’s Prayer
01:04:17 - Distribution of bread and wine and Closing Prayer 

01:11:02 - 01:13:54 - Hymn - Joy to the world (R&amp;S 135ii)

01:13:55 - 01:14:26 -  Blessing

01:14:51 - 01:18:44 - Music, notices and photos

#Church #Worship #Advent  #AllAreWelcome #URC #UnitedReformedChurch #Hope #Isaiah #Paul #Romans</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="1" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="35"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:Glr8tbgbwC0</id>
  <yt:videoId>Glr8tbgbwC0</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship - Sunday 27th November 2022</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Glr8tbgbwC0"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-11-27T11:56:13+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-11-28T08:59:22+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship - Sunday 27th November 2022</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/Glr8tbgbwC0?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/Glr8tbgbwC0/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00:00 - Opening music, photos, and notices

11:15 - Welcome and lighting of peace candle (an elder)

13:46 - Call to worship - Psalm 122

15:04 - 21:54 - Hymn:  O Come o come Emanuel R&amp;S126

21:58 - Prayer of adoration and confession

25:05 - Lord’s Prayer

26:05 - Reading: Matthew 24 vv 36-44 Read by Kate Yates

27:10 - 30:37 -  All age talk and intro
Boys' Brigade camp &amp; worrying about people being sick on the coach
Phobias
Working in care for so many years and being unable to deal with sick
&quot;Are we there yet?&quot;
Donkey, Shrek and Fiona in Shrek 2
The answer never comes until all of a sudden it does
We are told in our readings to prepare as we don't know the time and the hour
Penitential seasons before the two great festivals of Easter and Christmas
Thinking more about getting ready for Christ
Extending our prayer life
The start of the lectionary aligns with Advent
We have to prepare and be ready

30:51 - 34:02 - Hymn: Light of the World  MP1086

34:10 - Lighting of the Advent Candle

37:05 - 38:18 - Reading: Isaiah 2  vv 1-5  read by Kate Yates

38:36 - 40:37 - Hymn: Come thou long expected Jesus R&amp;S 138

40:42 - 52:33 - Address
Matthew 23 vv34 - Truly I tell you this generation will not pass away until all these things have happened
Reading v34, Matthew could not have thought of this generation only lasting 30-40 years after the crucifixion, but maybe before all of Jesus' had passed away
Compare to v36 - &quot;But about that day or hour no one knows, not even the angels in heaven, nor the Son, but only the Father&quot;
We know so little, constantly confounded by events
Jesus says &quot;about that day and hour no-one knows&quot;
Remembering days or hours about which I did not know - friends telling they have terminal cancer, meeting a future spouse, going to court to get justice, being asked to pray for a COVID sufferer
The day or hour about which we do not know comes to us all in thousands of different ways
We have no way of knowing whether it will be welcome or unwelcome
Jesus says &quot;Keep awake and be ready&quot; but for what?
We don't know but that is how life unfolds, it deepens the meaning of life. 
Everything matters and we should not want to miss a moment

52:50 - 55:19 - Hymn: Hark the glad sound the Saviour comes R&amp;S 137

55:23 - Offering Prayer
Prayers for the church and the world 

59:42 - 01:04:46 - Hymn: Lo He comes with clouds descending R&amp;S 656

01:04:47 - 01:05:08 - Blessing

01:05:34 - 01:09:00 - Organ voluntary, notices and photos

#Advent #Church #Jesus #Sing #Hymn  #AdventCandle #Candle</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="59"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:ae71A8eaGLI</id>
  <yt:videoId>ae71A8eaGLI</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship - Sunday 20th November 2022</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ae71A8eaGLI"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-11-20T12:25:47+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-11-29T16:26:22+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship - Sunday 20th November 2022</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/ae71A8eaGLI?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/ae71A8eaGLI/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00:00 - Opening music, photos, and notices

13:17 - Welcome and lighting of peace candle (an elder)

15:13 - Call to worship

Strength through vulnerability, peace through pain:
Jesus is the image of the unseen God.
Courage through truth, light through darkness:
Jesus is the image of the unseen God.

15:49 - Hymn - MP 465 Meekness and majesty

19:56 - Prayer of adoration and confession
Lord’s Prayer

22:48- 26:59 - Introducing of today’s theme: ‘Christ the King’

27:31 - 28:51 - Reading: Jeremiah 23.1-6 (NIVUK) read by David Bishop
23 ‘Woe to the shepherds who are destroying and scattering the sheep
of my pasture!’ declares the LORD.  2  Therefore this is what the LORD, the
God of Israel, says to the shepherds who tend my people: ‘Because you
have scattered my flock and driven them away and have not bestowed
care on them, I will bestow punishment on you for the evil you have
done,’ declares the LORD.  3  ‘I myself will gather the remnant of my flock
out of all the countries where I have driven them and will bring them
back to their pasture, where they will be fruitful and increase in
number.  4  I will place shepherds over them who will tend them, and they
will no longer be afraid or terrified, nor will any be missing,’ declares
the LORD.
5  ‘The days are coming,’ declares the LORD, ‘when I will raise up for
David a righteous Branch,
a King who will reign wisely and do what is just and right in the land.
6  In his days Judah will be saved and Israel will live in safety.
This is the name by which he will be called: The LORD Our Righteous
Saviour.

29:40 - 33:12 - Hymn MP 1008 The Lord’s my shepherd (Stuart Townend)

33:18 - Activity: ‘A king chart’
Thinking about Kings
What do you associate with the word King?
Castles
Privilege
Wealth
Heredity
Fine Clothes
Powerful
Authority
War
History
Which of these connect with Christ the King?
Powerful, crown, heritage, authority, history
That's not enough, let's add some words specific to Jesus
Faithful, loving, shepherd, servant, compassionate, humble

48:10 - Pilate's sign above the cross - Jesus King of the Jews

49:28 - Reading Luke 23.33-43 (NIVUK) read by Val Bishop
33  When they came to the place called the Skull, they crucified him there,
along with the criminals – one on his right, the other on his left.  34  Jesus
said, ‘Father, forgive them, for they do not know what they are
doing.’ [a]  And they divided up his clothes by casting lots. 35  The people
stood watching, and the rulers even sneered at him. They said, ‘He saved
others; let him save himself if he is God’s Messiah, the Chosen One.’
36  The soldiers also came up and mocked him. They offered him wine
vinegar  37  and said, ‘If you are the king of the Jews, save yourself.’
38  There was a written notice above him, which read: THIS IS THE KING OF THE
JEWS. 39  One of the criminals who hung there hurled insults at him: ‘Aren’t
you the Messiah? Save yourself and us!’ 40  But the other criminal
rebuked him. ‘Don’t you fear God,’ he said, ‘since you are under the
same sentence?  41  We are punished justly, for we are getting what our
deeds deserve. But this man has done nothing wrong.’
42  Then he said, ‘Jesus, remember me when you come into your
kingdom.’ 43  Jesus answered him, ‘Truly I tell you, today you will be with
me in paradise.’

51:04 - 53:05 - Short talk: Preparing for the King, praying for the kingdom
One of the great prayers of the New Testament - &quot;Jesus, remember me when you come into your
kingdom&quot;
This is an incredible King we are thinking of
In our system, the monarchy recognises its dependence on God, a King of love
He is the King of Kings
Next Sunday at the beginning of Advent we begin to prepare for the arrival of our King

53:06 - Craft Activity: Crown of love

01:03:50 - 01:08:00 - Hymn R&amp;S 522 From heaven you came

01:08:34 - Offering Prayer
Lord, show us where and how we can serve you,
the king who serves and gives yourself for us.
In our words and in our lives, we will worship you,
The King of love, the Prince of Peace.

01:09:30 - Taize Song - Jesus remember me (sung three times)
Jesus remember me, when you come into your kingdom…

01:11:11 - Prayers for the world with the response
Jesus, King of love,
remember them today.

01:15:39 - 01:19:01 - Hymn R&amp;S 262 Crown him the Lord of life

01:19:02 - 01:19:37 - Blessing
Let us hold fast to that which is good
In the strength of Jesus we are powerful
Let us never give in to evil.
In the peace of Jesus we are forgiven
Let follow his way of compassion
In the love of Jesus we are encircled
Blessed today and always
Amen.

01:19:54 - 01:22:45 - Music and notices after the service

#StirUpSunday #Church #Worship #Jeremiah #Luke #Bible #Crowns #JuniorChurch #TheLordsMyShepherd #Shepherd #Lord #God #Jesus</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="1" average="5.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="30"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:8HUynkMXiWc</id>
  <yt:videoId>8HUynkMXiWc</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship - Sunday 13th November 2022 - Remembrance Sunday</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8HUynkMXiWc"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-11-13T13:28:50+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-11-14T08:54:40+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship - Sunday 13th November 2022 - Remembrance Sunday</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/8HUynkMXiWc?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/8HUynkMXiWc/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00:00 - Opening music, photos, and notices

10:43 - Welcome and notices (an elder)

Call to worship
Lighting of Peace candle
Minister: On this Remembrance Sunday, we affirm that God is with us now, source of true peace.
All:  Be present with us, Lord, bring life and hope.
Minister: We remember the victory of Jesus Christ over death 
and hatred and his greeting ‘Peace be with you’:
All:  Be present with us, Lord, bring grace and peace.
Minister: Christ’s light shines in our world and in our hearts 
and the world’s darkness will never overcome it:
All:  Be present with us, Lord: 
lead us by the light of your love and truth.

13:16 - 15:57 - Hymn MP 1201  Longing for light (vs 1,2 and 5)

15:58 - 18:11 - Prayer of adoration and confession

18:17 - 25:04 - Introduction for all ages: ‘peace begins here and now’
Today is the day we remember
The different colours of poppies now available
White for peace, red for suffering and sacrifice
What other colours will be made available in the future as we recognise the impact of war
Imagine a pebble, holding it in your hand
Ripples in the water
Turning hearts of stone to love

Lord, lead me from death to life, from falsehood to truth;
lead me from despair to hope, from fear to trust;
lead me from hate to love, from war to peace.
Let peace fill our heart, our world, our universe.  Amen.

25:22 - 26:50 - Reading: Micah 4: 1 – 5 read by Larry Ogbewe
4 In the last days the mountain of the LORD’s temple will be established as the highest of the mountains; it will be exalted above the hills, and peoples will stream to it.  2 Many nations will come and say,
‘Come, let us go up to the mountain of the LORD, to the temple of the God of Jacob.  He will teach us his ways, so that we may walk in his paths.’
  The law will go out from Zion, the word of the LORD from Jerusalem.  3 He will judge between many peoples and will settle disputes for strong nations far and wide.  They will beat their swords into ploughshares and their spears into pruning hooks.  Nation will not take up sword against nation, nor will they train for war any more.  4 Everyone will sit under their own vine and under their own fig-tree, and no one will make them afraid, for the LORD Almighty has spoken.
5 All the nations may walk in the name of their gods,
but we will walk in the name of the LORD our God for ever and ever.

27:57 - 29:12 - Reading: Revelation 22. 1 – 5 read by Norma Garden
Then the angel showed me the river of the water of life, as clear as crystal, flowing from the throne of God and of the Lamb 2 down the middle of the great street of the city. On each side of the river stood the tree of life, bearing twelve crops of fruit, yielding its fruit every month. And the leaves of the tree are for the healing of the nations. 3 No longer will there be any curse. The throne of God and of the Lamb will be in the city, and his servants will serve him. 4 They will see his face, and his name will be on their foreheads. 5 There will be no more night. They will not need the light of a lamp or the light of the sun, for the Lord God will give them light. And they will reign for ever and ever.

30:01 - Hymn R&amp;S 477 - Let there be love shared among us

32:07 - Prayer before the Act of Remembrance

36:56 - Act of remembrance at 11 am
They shall grow not old, as we that are left grow old; 
age shall not weary them, nor the years condemn. 
At the going down of the sun and in the morning, 
we will remember them. 
We will remember them.

The  two minutes of silence
Prayers

43:19 - 46:36 - Hymn -  R&amp;S 705  Our God, our help in ages past

46:42 - 01:00:36 - Short Address: ‘healing a broken world’

Minister: On this day when our nation remembers the sacrifices of the past and the conflicts and crises of the present, we offer our lives once more for God’s work of healing a broken world and bringing peace and justice to all:  
All:  God of hope, we commit ourselves 
to your way of truth and compassion.
As we work for peace – give us wisdom, 
as we strive for justice – give us courage, 
as we care for those in need – give us compassion. 
As we strive to protect the planet – give us hope
Through Jesus Christ our Lord. Amen.

01:00:52 - 01:04:20 - Hymn R&amp;S 629  Make me a channel of your peace

01:04:24 - Thanksgiving Prayer and Lord’s Prayer

01:07:19 - Distribution of bread and wine 

01:13:40 - Closing Prayer 

01:14:37 - 01:17:50 - Hymn R&amp;S 620   For the healing of the nations

01:17:52 - 01:18:30 - Blessing

01:18:58 - 01:22:14 - Music and notices after the service

#Remembrance #WeWillRemenberThem #NeverForget #Poppy #Poppies #Flanders #Church #Worship #Cenotaph</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="28"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:LeUKLHZrtxg</id>
  <yt:videoId>LeUKLHZrtxg</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Trinity URC Sunday 6th November 2022 led by Rebecca Hawes</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LeUKLHZrtxg"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-11-06T11:52:59+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-12-12T08:44:15+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Trinity URC Sunday 6th November 2022 led by Rebecca Hawes</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/LeUKLHZrtxg?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/LeUKLHZrtxg/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00:00 - Opening music, photos, and notices

13:51 - Welcome and lighting of peace candle (an elder)

15:47 - Call to worship

16:38 - 19:44 - Hymn:  Alleluia, Sing to Jesus  ( to tune MP315 ). 

19:51 - Opening Prayers and the Lord’s Prayer

22:34 - 27:50 - Talk for all ages
A wonderful catchphrase for the Christian faith
A quiz - who said this?
To infinity and beyond
Nice to see you , to see you nice
Here's one I made earlier
Simples
Ahana means family, family means no-one gets left behind
I have a cunning plan
Think happy thoughts
We know those catchphrases because they are used by people and we learn about those people by their use
If you had a catchphrase, would it tell us about you?
The phrase that Job uses - I know that my redeemer lives
He clings on to this through his trials and tribulations
Peter says we should always have hope
A challenge - how can we live our lives so that we point to the hope we have in Jesus  

28:10 - 30:44 - Hymn Come on and Celebrate  ( TP23 )
 
30:55 - Blessing as Junior Church go to their activities:

31:55 - Reading: Job 19:23-27a read by Samuel Evans

32:40 - Update on the work of Wycombe YFC
Sharing the &quot;Encounter&quot; project in secondary schools
A place young people can come to and put their gifts and talents to use
Launched just under 12 months ago
Real growth in young people offering to help
A new worship band
A safe space to encounter God
Helping at Lighthouse Cressex supporting the lamplighters
Mentoring and pastoral support in primary schools

44:16 - 46:15 - Reading: 2 Thessalonians 2:1-5 &amp; 13-end read by Kitty Bird

46:133 - 50:01 - Hymn: Lord for the Years (R&amp;S 603)

Sermon followed by time of quiet reflection 

Hymn: How sweet the name of Jesus sounds (R&amp;S 277)

Prayers for others and ourselves

Hymn: O Jesus I have Promised (R&amp;S 509) new tune                       

Closing blessing 

Organ voluntary and photos/notices

#WycombeYouthForChrist #WYFC #YFC #Job19 #thessalonians #church #god #worship #jesus #urc #unitedreformedchurch #AllAreWelcome</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="27"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:Wf6luERPLNM</id>
  <yt:videoId>Wf6luERPLNM</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Trinity URC Sunday 30th October 2022</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Wf6luERPLNM"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-10-30T13:15:48+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-12-04T09:26:53+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Trinity URC Sunday 30th October 2022</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/Wf6luERPLNM?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i4.ytimg.com/vi/Wf6luERPLNM/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00:00 - Opening Music on the Organ. 

07:39 - Welcome and lighting of peace candle (an elder)

09:38 - Call to worship
What does the Lord our God require of us? Is it not to act justly,
love mercy and walk humbly with our God.

10:34 - 15:30 - Hymn - Let us build a house
© Marty Haugen 1994 GIA Publications

15:32 - Opening Prayers with the response
May the love of Christ unite us
in wonder, love and praise.

Lord’s Prayer

19:02 - Introduction for all ages – out of the box!
If you filled a box, what might be in it?
Soap, flannels, a toy, toothbrush &amp; paste, a hat and scarf
Shoebox Collection: Daphne Stopforth updates us on the work of

22:07 - Link to Hope in Eastern Europe (including Ukraine) and collects
any Christmas shoeboxes you have brought to church today

28:32 - 31:09 - Song from Ukraine (recording)
Lord, oh the Great and Almighty, protect our beloved Ukraine,
Bless her with freedom and light of your holy rays.
With learning and knowledge enlighten us, your children small,
In love pure and everlasting, let us, oh Lord, grow.
We pray, oh Lord Almighty, protect our beloved Ukraine,
Grant our people and country all your kindness and grace.
Bless us with freedom, bless us with wisdom,
Guide into a kind world, Bless us, oh Lord, with good fortune
for ever and evermore.

31:39 - 33:15 - Reading: Isaiah 1.10 – 18 (NIVUK) read by Linda Curley

34:23 - 44:26 - Update on Commitment for Life given by Angus Massie. Our
focus is on Israel and the occupied Palestinian territories.

45:40 - 47:56 - Hymn MP 376 - Jesus taught how to be a family

48:23 - 49:41 - Reading: Luke 19.1 – 10 (NIVUK) read by Julia Sparks

50:23 - 52:02 - Hymn R&amp;S 92 - Amazing grace
(vs 1 and 2 only, sung seated as a prayer)

52:08 - 01:01:52 - Short Talk
Jesus is on his way to Jerusalem
A city so important to people before and after through the centuries.
He went to confront hypocrisy
He knows this is part of God's plan to save the world
He has important business to do - global salvation
The little town of Jericho has to be passed through 
A little man up a tree catches his eye and despite the huge task ahead, Jesus pauses and gives him his attention
No-one is beyond Jesus' attention

01:01:57 - Prayers for the church and the world with sung response
Hymn R&amp;S 401 - Through our lives

01:09:28 - 01:12:34 - Hymn - R&amp;S 567 Thy hand, O God, has guided

01:12:36 - 01:13:05 - Blessing

01:13:28 - 01:17:33 - Organ voluntary and photos/notices</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="19"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:AqI779nVQs8</id>
  <yt:videoId>AqI779nVQs8</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Trinity URC Compassion Sunday Guest speaker 23rd Oct</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AqI779nVQs8"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-10-23T10:53:14+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-11-14T08:38:40+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Trinity URC Compassion Sunday Guest speaker 23rd Oct</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/AqI779nVQs8?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/AqI779nVQs8/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00:00 - Music before the service

07:34 - Welcome and lighting of peace candle (elder)

09:35 - Call to worship: words from Psalm 24

10:34 - 13:11 Hymn: Jesus shall reign where’er the sun R&amp;amp;S 269

13:20 - Opening Prayers and the Lord’s Prayer

15:49 - 20:48 - Trinity's sponsored children

20:55 - 39:18 - My story – Miss Dilini Paul
Our impact:
More than 3,000 hours for children at the projects we support
More than 1,000 nutritious meals
More than 15 medical checkups
20 Letters sent, 9 letters received

39:54 - 42:58 - Worship song: Blessed assurance

Blessing as Junior Church go to their activities:
Adults: May the Lord be with you
Junior Church: And also with you
All: Amen

Introduction to Bible readings

43:52 - 45:23 - Reading: Exodus 2 vv 5-10 read by Jeany Bien

45:37 - 49:18 - Hymn: King of Kings MP100

49:40 - 01:04:21 - Talk - Mr Vinoraj Thavarasa followed by time of quiet reflection
Sponsored children, how we help
Guatemala
Pharoah's daughter stopping by the water's edge
God putting compassion into her heart
She was willing to put forward her love and resources to care for the child

01:06:07 - 01:10:07 - Hymn: Christ be our light MP1201

01:10:23 - Prayers for others and ourselves led by Rosemary

01:13:50 - 01:17:34 - Hymn: We’ve a story to tell to the nations MP744

01:17:35 - 01:17:53 - Closing blessing
The Grace

01:18:11 - 01:22:30 - Organ voluntary, photos, and notices

#God #exodus #Compassion #Jesus #sponsorachild  #mushroom #berries #berry #autumn #leaves</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="12"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:vqv0l2Y0lNI</id>
  <yt:videoId>vqv0l2Y0lNI</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Trinity URC morning worship 16th Oct led by church members</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vqv0l2Y0lNI"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-10-16T10:40:48+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-11-01T08:45:24+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Trinity URC morning worship 16th Oct led by church members</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/vqv0l2Y0lNI?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/vqv0l2Y0lNI/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00:00 - Music before the service

12:55 - Welcome and lighting of peace candle (elder)

13:50 - Kate to introduce David Reynold’s video
15:17 - 17:30 - David Reynold’s video

17:39 - Call to worship    
2 Corinthians 3:18
And we, who with unveiled faces all reflect the Lord’s glory, are being transformed into his likeness with ever-increasing glory, which from the Lord, who is the Spirit.

18:05 - Hymn – R&amp;S 489  Be thou my vision 

21:52 - Opening Prayers and Lord’s Prayer 

24:00 - 28:18 - Short introduction to Compassion by Marian Drake followed by a video preparing us for next Sunday’s service for Compassion Sunday

28:35 - Hymn – R&amp;S 522 From heaven you came (Servant King) 

33:01 - Introduction to Bible readings
We will now listen to our readings 

Readings 

33:16 - 36:50 - Psalm 139 read by John Hillson

36:58 - 38:27 - John 9:1-11 read by Lesley Bogart

38:46 - Hymn – R&amp;S 549 One more step along the way I go 

42:29 - Poem written and read by David Reynolds 

43:55 - Hymn – R&amp;S 518 Father I place into your hands

46:34 - 53:30 - Short Address – Made in God’s image 
Psalm 139 has inspired many
From v13 the psalmist reflects on how he has been made for a purpose and calling
We too are formed in the image of God - the image may be perfect but we are not.
Yet all are precious in His sight
The John 9 story is beautifully crafted looking at the  perceived &quot;fault&quot; of the blind man
Jesus could use the situation to manifest his glory
The sign points to Jesus as the light of the world
&quot;Not unto us o Lord, not unto us but to Your name be the glory&quot;

53:42 - Video – “Made in God’s Image”

59:47 - Offering prayer (no collection is taken up but prayer can acknowledge our gifts to God)

01:00:29 - Prayers for the world led by Kate Yates

01:05:34 - 01:10:30 - Hymn – R&amp;S 117  How Great Thou Art

01:10:31 - 01:10:40 - Closing Blessing  

01:11:08 - 01:14:32 - Organ voluntary, photos, notices

#God #godsimage #sightloss #torchtrust #psalm139 #john1v9 #john1 #2corinthians3</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="12"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:9bBLxqi1slg</id>
  <yt:videoId>9bBLxqi1slg</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Trinity URC morning worship 9th Oct led by Rev Bridget Powell</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9bBLxqi1slg"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-10-09T11:14:06+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-10-24T20:50:34+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Trinity URC morning worship 9th Oct led by Rev Bridget Powell</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/9bBLxqi1slg?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/9bBLxqi1slg/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00:00 - Music before the service

09:40 - Welcome and lighting of peace candle (an elder)

11:35 - Call to worship: Verses from Psalm 111

13:39 - Hymn: R&amp;S 60  God who spoke in the beginning  To tune Rhuddlan 344

16:08 - Opening Prayer and The Lord’s Prayer

19:50 - 30:05 - Introduction to the theme: Saying Thank You
I have in mind a story from the Gospel
Do you remember the story where Jesus met 10 lepers on the road
They didn't come near but said to him - &quot;Master, have pity on us&quot;
He told them to go to the priest and they would be cleansed
There are 200,000 people suffering with leprosy in 2020
It can be cured now but there is still a lot of it around
These 10 men did not have access to modern medicine, they would have gone to a colony, gradually lost the use of their extremities.
However, they did as told, went to the priest and were seen as cured.
Only one of them turned back to Jesus to thank him
Do we always remember to say thank you?
ACTS mnemonic for how to pray - Adoration, Confession, Thanksgiving, and Supplication 
What would you like to give thanks for today?


30:18 - Hymn - R&amp;S 302  O breath of life come sweeping through us

33:28 - Introduction to the readings

35:04 - 38:44 - Readings:   2 Kings 5:1-15 NIVUK 
Naaman healed of leprosy

39:25 - 40:41 - Luke 17: 11-19 NIVUK 
Jesus heals ten men with leprosy

41:10 - Hymn:  R&amp;S 492  Dear Lord and Father of mankind

46:02 - 01:06:14 - Sermon:  First impressions  followed by time of quite reflection
I wanted to start thinking about how we see things
First impressions and the need to revisit them
A mishmash of faces
An optical illusion of the word Jesus
The face of Jesus
Have you ever met someone who you are not sure whether you wish to be friends with?
You gradually spend more time with them and find out more before becoming friends
How would you describe yourself in one word?
Naaman and the slave girl
Not just a physical healing but a spiritual one as well
Our experiences form who we become
Help us to see people as Jesus sees them


01:06:50 - Hymn - R&amp;S 648  Jesu, Jesu, fill us with your love

01:09:28 - Prayers of Intercession
Response:  Gracious Lord, hear our prayers

01:15:22 - Hymn: R&amp;S 200  The Kingdom of God is justice and joy

01:18:16 - 01:18:36 - Blessing

01:19:23 - 01:25:18 - Music and photographs after the service

#Worship #Naaman #Leprosy #Healing #Jesus</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="16"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:yaOUyyqbjRk</id>
  <yt:videoId>yaOUyyqbjRk</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 2nd October  2022</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yaOUyyqbjRk"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-10-02T14:23:10+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-10-11T07:47:57+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship - Sunday, 2nd October  2022</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/yaOUyyqbjRk?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/yaOUyyqbjRk/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00:00 - Music before the service

15:49 - Welcome and lighting of the peace candle

17:32 - United Reformed Church 50th anniversary memorabilia 
19:49 - Call to worship
With the whole Christian Church, the United Reformed Church believes in one God, Father, Son and Holy Spirit.
Glory to God in highest heaven:  peace to all people on earth.

20:10 - Hymn -  R&amp;S 29  Father we love you

21:33 - The life of faith to which we are called is the Spirit’s gift continually received through the Word, the Sacraments and our Christian life together:
Glory to God in highest heaven; 
peace to all people on earth.

22:08 - Opening Prayers 

23:58 - 29:00 - Introduction for all ages – joined together
I would have loved to give each of you a piece of this 50th anniversary jigsaw but there is nothing more annoying than a missing piece
What kind of piece would you be? Corner, curly, straight?
I was sent a single piece this week, sent to URC ministers
Every time you reach 35 years in the URC ministry, you receive a symbolic piece to show how you are part of the one church family
Coming together as one family, united in peace, joining pieces together.
When we take the small piece of bread, it reminds us we are all a part of the one body of Christ, building to make one huge picture together
As reminders we have cards showing Faith, Hope, and Love with 4 questions for each day
How have I acted with love today?
How have I lived the life of Jesus today?
How have I lived my faith today?
How have I walked with hope today?

29:23 - 29:52 - Reading: Psalm 133 (Good News) 
133 How wonderful it is, how pleasant,
    for God's people to live together in harmony!
2 It is like the precious anointing oil
    running down from Aaron's head and beard,
    down to the collar of his robes.
3 It is like the dew on Mount Hermon,
    falling on the hills of Zion.
That is where the Lord has promised his blessing—
    life that never ends.

30:42 - 31:30 - Trinity Vision: Small Groups 

31:54 - 34:12 - Trinity Vision: Midweek Café

34:20 - Songs R&amp;S 565  Jesus stand among us
    TP 4  All heaven declares

40:33 - Introducing the readings
The highest authority for what we believe and do is God’s Word in the Bible alive for his people today through the help of the Spirit.
Glory to God in highest heaven; 
peace to all people on earth.

41:13 - 42:07 - Reading: 1 Corinthians 12. 1 – 5, 12 – 13, 31 (NIVUK) 
42:33 - Reaction to the reading

43:37 - Held together in the Body of Christ through the freedom of the Spirit, we rejoice in the diversity of the Spirit’s gifts and uphold the rights of personal conviction. For the sake of faith and fellowship it shall be for the church to decide where differences of conviction hurt our unity and peace.
Glory to God in highest heaven; 
peace to all people on earth.

42:10 - A Prayer of the unity and peace in the church family

45:35 - 47:30 - Reading: 1 Corinthians 13. 1 – 13 (NIVUK) 

48:28 - Hymn - R&amp;S 354 Come, Living God, when least expected

51:53 - 01:01:43 - Short Talk: ‘Faith, hope and love NOW’
Are you among the ardent youth or the mellow age?
Most of us rather mellow
Thinking of our anniversary, I tried to remember what it was like being 50
I remember being 40 more than 50
I was given an axe for my 50th birthday - in a pub!
What is it like being 50
In the history of the Church, 50 is nothing really, even less in the history of humanity, it's just a blink of an eye
Faith, Hope, Love since 1972 for the URC
Paul's 1st letter to the Corinthians Ch 13. A difficult letter he was writing
Replace the word &quot;love&quot; with &quot;Jesus&quot; to understand more
Paul longs for people to reflect that love in their lives
We believe in a loving God, not a condemning God
We have many convictions, expressed in different ways yet we hold that common faith in a loving God and Jesus
There are three things that last forever - faith, hope, and love and the greatest of these is love - hold on to that

01:01:49 - We affirm our intention to go on praying and working, with all our fellow Christians, for the visible unity of the Church in the way Christ chooses, so that people and nations may be led to love and serve God and praise him more and more, for ever.
Glory to God in highest heaven; 
peace to all people on earth.

01:02:47 - 01:04:50 - Prayers for the church and the world

01:04:55 - Hymn - R&amp;S 469  As we are gathered Jesus is here

01:07:33 - Communion: we invite you to share in the bread and wine at church (or at home) united in the name of Jesus Christ

01:07:33 - A Prayer of thanksgiving and Lord’s Prayer 

01:10:52 - 01:17:23 - Distribution of Communion and Closing Prayer

01:17:24 - Hymn - R&amp;S 603  Lord for the years

01:21:18 - 01:21:50 - Blessing 

01:22:18 - 1:26:31 - Music and notices after the service

#communion #urc #vision #corinthians #jigsaw #FaithHopeLove #corner</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="21"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:lCsGIi5eqSY</id>
  <yt:videoId>lCsGIi5eqSY</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship - 18th September Harvest 2022</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lCsGIi5eqSY"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-09-18T10:46:06+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-10-04T07:56:13+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship - 18th September Harvest 2022</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/lCsGIi5eqSY?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i1.ytimg.com/vi/lCsGIi5eqSY/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00:00 - Music before the service

15:07 - Welcome, introduction and call to worship

17:22 - Call to worship

17:52 - Hymn -  Praise and thanksgiving (R&amp;S 48)

20:16 - Opening Prayer of thanksgiving 

22:17 - 28:04 - Introduction: ‘harvest links’
The harvest display connects us with people across the country and across the world
Sunflower oil and sunflowers to creation and Ukraine
An ear of wheat - gleaning the leftovers after harvest from the field behind Cores End church - farmers everywhere
A coin - connecting to the Queen, thinking of the late Queen Elizabeth II and her family
An envelope - connecting us with the people in Africa experiencing a vicious drought, supported by Christian Aid
A can - connecting to One Can, our local foodbank supporting people in need 

28:05 - 40:18 - One Can Update 

40:25 - 42:21 - Reading: Psalm 65. 1, 5-13 (CEV) 

42:51 - Song - Our God is a great big God

44:57 - Short Christian Aid Film: the Crisis in East Africa

47:56 - Prayer for East Africa
Loving and compassionate God, 
When Famine stalks the land, nothing grows. 
Plants cannot, people cannot, ideas and dreams cannot  
everything withers and dies. 
It is a violent aberration of your will for the world 
and it is multiplied now by conflict, climate change and covid. 
God of the flourishing field, there is enough to feed us all. 
Call us to that sacred sharing, neighbour to global neighbour,  
your gifts of food, water, a chance to live the life 
so delicately crafted by your divine spirit. 
We will not turn away but turn towards each other 
with generosity and a justice-driven compassion 
that searches for solutions. 
Famine stalks the land, so may our outrage grow, 
may our determination steel itself, 
may our solidarity spur us into action. 
God of the flourishing field, help us feed each other.  Amen.

50:26 - Song - Come all you people, come and praise your maker (video)
Uyai mose, tinamate mwari. (x3)
Uyai mose zvino.

Activity for children at back of church

52:45 - 54:05 - Reading: Luke 12 8.1 – 9 
13 Someone in the crowd said to him, ‘Teacher, tell my brother to divide the inheritance with me.’
14 Jesus replied, ‘Man, who appointed me a judge or an arbiter between you?’ 15 Then he said to them, ‘Watch out! Be on your guard against all kinds of greed; life does not consist in an abundance of possessions.’
16 And he told them this parable: ‘The ground of a certain rich man yielded an abundant harvest. 17 He thought to himself, “What shall I do? I have no place to store my crops.”
18 ‘Then he said, “This is what I’ll do. I will tear down my barns and build bigger ones, and there I will store my surplus grain. 19 And I’ll say to myself, ‘You have plenty of grain laid up for many years. Take life easy; eat, drink and be merry.’”
20 ‘But God said to him, “You fool! This very night your life will be demanded from you. Then who will get what you have prepared for yourself?”
21 ‘This is how it will be with whoever stores up things for themselves but is not rich towards God.’

54:42 - Song - Give thanks with a grateful heart (MP 170)

57:42 - 01:06:30 - Short Talk
We live connected lives
Our display connects us with many people - rich and poor, black and white, friends and enemies
Many situations linked to us, we can not live in a vacuum
The rich man in the parable tries this, no concern for his workers, just what to do with all his wealth - go for growth, growth, growth
It could be a parable of the western world
Jesus said to be on guard for all kinds of greed
Life does not consist of an abundance of possessions
Reflecting on the life of our Queen, we could say she was one of the top 0.1% in terms of wealth but looking at her lifetime of service, what she has done is incredible.  &quot;Each day is a new beginning, I know that the only way to live my life is to try to do what is right&quot; 
Jesus said - whoever stores up things for themselves but is not rich towards God
Let's speak to God today, come clean, and be challenged to live our lives better putting our trust in Our loving Saviour

01:06:32 - Hymn - God whose farm is all creation (R&amp;S 612)

Offering of our gifts (symbolic gifts)

01:08:22 - Prayers of intercession for the world 
Lord of all the harvest
Hear our prayer.

01:14:11 - The Lord’s Prayer 

01:15:18 - Hymn - Fill your hearts with joy (MP 147)

01:18:39 - 01:19:04 - Blessing

01:19:29 - 01:22:35 - Music and notices after the service

#onecan #foodbank  #queenelizabeth #tribute #harvest #creation #paddington #ukraine</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="19"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
 <entry>
  <id>yt:video:ItoLy-7NlBE</id>
  <yt:videoId>ItoLy-7NlBE</yt:videoId>
  <yt:channelId>UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</yt:channelId>
  <title>Morning Worship - 11th September 2022</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ItoLy-7NlBE"/>
  <author>
   <name>Trinity High Wycombe and Cores End URCs</name>
   <uri>https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCOGU0Xl7GgEXwutvo2kRLPg</uri>
  </author>
  <published>2022-09-11T11:26:24+00:00</published>
  <updated>2022-12-11T16:50:55+00:00</updated>
  <media:group>
   <media:title>Morning Worship - 11th September 2022</media:title>
   <media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/ItoLy-7NlBE?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="390"/>
   <media:thumbnail url="https://i2.ytimg.com/vi/ItoLy-7NlBE/hqdefault.jpg" width="480" height="360"/>
   <media:description>00:00:00 - Music before the service

00:12:40 Welcome and lighting of peace candle (an elder)

16:48 - Call to worship:

18:18 - Hymn - Our God our help in ages past R&amp;S 705

21:51 - Opening Prayer

24:07 - The Lord’s Prayer

25:20 - 27:17 - Reading: Luke 15 vv 1-10  read by Norma
Now the tax collectors and sinners were all gathering round to hear Jesus. 2 But the Pharisees and the teachers of the law muttered, ‘This man welcomes sinners, and eats with them.’
3 Then Jesus told them this parable: 4 ‘Suppose one of you has a hundred sheep and loses one of them. Doesn’t he leave the ninety-nine in the open country and go after the lost sheep until he finds it? 5 And when he finds it, he joyfully puts it on his shoulders 6 and goes home. Then he calls his friends and neighbours together and says, “Rejoice with me; I have found my lost sheep.” 7 I tell you that in the same way there will be more rejoicing in heaven over one sinner who repents than over ninety-nine righteous people who do not need to repent.
The parable of the lost coin
8 ‘Or suppose a woman has ten silver coins[a] and loses one. Doesn’t she light a lamp, sweep the house and search carefully until she finds it? 9 And when she finds it, she calls her friends and neighbours together and says, “Rejoice with me; I have found my lost coin.” 10 In the same way, I tell you, there is rejoicing in the presence of the angels of God over one sinner who repents.’

27:30 - 30:52 - Talk for All ages
I remember the chaplain coming to my last place of work
Misunderstanding the chaplain referring to us as a flock of sheep
Driving home from Wales one night and a sheep ran out into the side of the road.
God loves all of us and doesn't want any one of us to be lost
Lots of things make us wander off from God
Everyday life, tragedies etc.
We can help by doing something that sheep do a lot - bleat, which for us translates to praying
Remember the God forgives when we return to him and ask for forgiveness

30:54 - Hymn: Brother sister let me serve you R&amp;S 474 

34:28 - 36:07 - Reading: 1 Timothy 1  vv 12-17 read  by Alan
2 I thank Christ Jesus our Lord, who has given me strength, that he considered me trustworthy, appointing me to his service. 13 Even though I was once a blasphemer and a persecutor and a violent man, I was shown mercy because I acted in ignorance and unbelief. 14 The grace of our Lord was poured out on me abundantly, along with the faith and love that are in Christ Jesus.
15 Here is a trustworthy saying that deserves full acceptance: Christ Jesus came into the world to save sinners – of whom I am the worst. 16 But for that very reason I was shown mercy so that in me, the worst of sinners, Christ Jesus might display his immense patience as an example for those who would believe in him and receive eternal life. 17 Now to the King eternal, immortal, invisible, the only God, be honour and glory for ever and ever. Amen.

36:17 - Hymn: The King of love my shepherd is  R&amp;S 552 

39:46 - 49:32 - Sermon followed by time of quite reflection
We heard two parables today, the lost sheep and the lost coin
Different but vividly illustrating the truth of John 3:16 - God so loved the world that he gave his only Son
Both follow the same pattern:
1. Something is lost
2. There is a search for the thing that is lost
3. There is great joy when the thing that is lost is found
How the things are lost are not important to the parables
The items are regarded as precious by their owner, just as we are regarded by God
Jesus is the shepherd not content to be happy with the 99, he will go out and look for the missing one
God so loved us that whilst we were still sinners, he gave His Son
We need a daily awareness of the gospel in our lives to keep us humble before our Saviour
Do we look down on the sinners around us or do we seek the sinners as the lost needing to be found?

51:18 - Hymn: Eternal Father of the ceaseless round R&amp;S 623

56:08 - Prayers of Intercession

01:00:35 - Hymn: God is love let heaven adore Him R&amp;S 95

01:04:37 - 01:05:06 - Blessing

01:05:28 - 01:10:12 - Music and notices after the service

#queenelizabeth #photostory #worship #parables</media:description>
   <media:community>
    <media:starRating count="0" average="0.00" min="1" max="5"/>
    <media:statistics views="51"/>
   </media:community>
  </media:group>
 </entry>
</feed>
